I've had patients go from stage four
我曾有病人从四期
cancer to stage zero. So, I have now
癌症逆转到零期。 所以，我现在
seen where the end of cancer is coming
明白了癌症的终结之道在哪里
from. I've seen how the war is going to
。 我已经预见到这场战争的
finish. And here's how. Dr. William Lee
结局了。 方法如下。 威廉·李博士
is a Harvard trained physician and
是一位在哈佛大学接受过培训的医生和
medical scientist whose work is
医学科学家，他的工作正在
revolutionizing the way we understand
彻底改变我们理解
and fight some of the most devastating
和对抗
diseases facing our world today. I'm
当今世界面临的一些最具破坏性的疾病的方式。 我
going to give you a brand new view of
将带你领略一种全新的
thinking about cancer. And this is
癌症观。
shocking to some people to hear, but
有些人听到这个消息可能会感到震惊，但事实上，
every 24 hours there are 10,000 mistakes
每 24 小时，
that are made in your body. Each of
你的身体就会发生 10,000 次错误。 每一种都是
those is a microscopic cancer. But the
肉眼看不见的癌症。 但
reason that we don't become more sick
我们之所以不会因为
from all kinds of diseases, including
各种疾病（包括
cancer, is because our body is hardwired
癌症）而病情加重，是因为我们的身体
with its own health defense systems. But
本身就具备强大的健康防御系统。 但
here's the problem. We are presently
问题就在这里。 我们目前正在
seeing the fallout of some of the not so
承受上
good moves that we made in the 1950s
世纪
and60s and 70s. For example, people
五六十年代和七十年代一些不太明智的举措所带来的后果。 例如，人们
worth of plastic every single week,
每周消耗的塑料可能相当于一张信用卡的量，
which is very worrying, and I won't tell
这非常令人担忧，我不会告诉
you why, but there's also the foods you
你为什么，但还有你所
eat, which contribute to taking your
吃的食物，这些食物也会降低你的
health defenses down. But the good news
健康防御能力。 但好消息
is that you can actually put shields up
是，你也可以设置护盾
as well. So, this is our experiment, and
。 所以，这是我们的实验，
we're trying to discover drugs that
我们试图发现
could be developed as cancer treatments.
可以开发成癌症治疗药物的东西。
So, we said, let's remove half of them,
所以，我们决定移除其中一半，
and let's swap them out with food. You
并用食物代替它们。 你
know, I I was a skeptic, but when I saw
知道，我以前是个怀疑论者，但当我看到
these results, it made my jaw drop
这些结果时，我简直惊呆了，
because the holy grail in the
因为
pharmaceutical industry is to find
制药行业的圣杯就是找到
something that can kill cancer stem
能够杀死癌症干
cells. And we don't have a drug that can
细胞的东西。 我们目前还没有能
do that. Turns out, mother nature beat
做到这一点的药物。 结果证明，大自然抢先一步
us to the punch. And there's more than
。
200 foods that I've studied that can
我研究过的200多种食物
actually starve cancers. And if you had
实际上可以“饿死”癌细胞。 如果让你
to pick five based on the science you've
根据你所看到的科学研究选出五项
seen, what would those top five be? The
最重要的成果，你会选择哪五项？
good news is that it's food that we can
好消息是，这是我们
eat every single day. So, number one,
每天都可以吃的食物。 首先，
this has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点难以置信
bit. 53% of you that listen to this show
。 经常收听本节目的听众中，有 53% 的人
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
尚未订阅本
show. So, could I ask you for a favor
节目。 那么，在我们开始之前，我能请你帮个忙吗
before we start? If you like the show
？ 如果你喜欢我们的节目，
and you like what we do here and you
喜欢我们在这里所做的一切，并且
want to support us, the free simple way
想要支持我们，最简单的免费方法
that you can do just that is by hitting
就是点击
the subscribe button. And my commitment
订阅按钮。 我向
to you is if you do that, then I'll do
你们承诺，如果你们这样做，
everything in my power, me and my team,
我和我的团队将竭尽全力，
to make sure that this show is better
确保这个节目
for you every single week. We'll listen
每周都能为你们带来更好的体验。 我们会认真听取
to your feedback. We'll find the guest
您的反馈意见。 我们会找到
that you want me to speak to and we'll
您想让我采访的嘉宾，然后
continue to do what we do. Thank you so
继续做我们该做的事情。 非常感谢
[Music]
[音乐]
much. Dr. William Lee, if someone has
。 威廉·李博士，如果有人
just clicked on this conversation and
刚刚点击进入这段对话，并且
they're asking themselves, they're
他们正在思考，在
next couple of hours, what would you say
接下来的几个小时里和我们一起度过，他们会得到什么，您会
directly to them that they will learn,
直接告诉他们什么，他们会学到什么，
gain, and how will their life improve?
获得什么，以及他们的生活将如何得到改善？
I would say that you're going to hear
我想说，你会
about food in a brand new way that you
以一种全新的方式了解食物，你以前可能
didn't realize that a decision that you
从未意识到，
can make after this listening to this or
听完或看完之后，你可以立即做出一个决定并付诸
action to your life immediately could
实践，而这个决定实际上可能会对
actually help you for the rest of your
你
life. It could stave off disease, help
余生有所帮助。 它可以预防疾病，
you feel stronger, even help you with
增强体质，甚至有助于
longevity. Uh so there's no single moves
延年益寿。 嗯，虽然没有一蹴而就的办法，
that you can make but it's the beginning
但这却是迈向
you to live the rest of a long enjoyable
幸福
life. And what are the the key diseases
长寿的第一步。 那么，
concerned about today based on their
根据与
correlation to the food that we eat?
我们所吃食物的相关性来看，人们目前最关注和应该关注的主要疾病有哪些？
Yeah, if you look at the biggest health
是的，如果你看看
crises in the world today in developed
当今发达国家面临的最大健康危机
countries, um you know, you're really
，嗯，你知道，你真正
talking about cardiovascular disease
谈论的是心血管疾病，它是
being the number one killer, diabetes,
头号杀手，还有糖尿病
and all the consequences, the
以及由此产生的所有后果，
devastating consequences that come out.
毁灭性的后果。
Listen, your blood sugar is not being
听着，你的血糖
very well regulated. That's the
控制得不太好。 这就是
definition over time of diabetes. But
糖尿病的长期定义。 但
the knock-on effect of having high
高
uncontrolled sugars is really underlying
血糖不受控制的连锁反应实际上是潜在的
metabolic chaos. There's a whole litany
代谢紊乱。 由此会引发一系列
of terrible conditions that happens
可怕的后果，
every downstream from that from eye
从
disease to wounds that don't heal etc
眼疾到难以愈合的伤口
etc. Cancer is another one. Dementia is
等等。癌症也是其中之一。 随着人口老龄化，痴呆症正成为
a big bigger and bigger problem as our
一个越来越严重的问题
population ages. And a lot of people
。 很多人
don't re recognize this, but you know
没有意识到这一点，但你知道
the the saying that inflammation is a
那句老话：炎症是
root cause of chronic disease.
慢性疾病的根源。   从
Scientifically correct, but there are
科学角度来说是正确的，但是还有
many many inflammatory diseases that are
很多炎症性疾病
out there that don't get enough airplay
没有得到足够的关注，这些疾病会
your life as you get older. And so I
随着年龄的增长严重影响你的生活质量。 所以我
think all of these things, it's not just
觉得所有这些事情，不仅仅
about mortality, it's about morbidity.
关乎死亡率，也关乎发病率。   重要的
It's not just about living long, it's
不仅仅是活得长久，而是
about living well and feeling good along
活得精彩，并且一路保持愉悦的心情
the way. And where do you think we are
。 那么，你认为我们
as a society you especially as
作为一个社会，特别是作为
westerners as it relates to our
西方人，在
relationship with health and food?
健康和食物的关系方面，处于什么状态？
Because when I look at some of the stats
因为当我查看一些关于预期寿命的统计数据时
expectancy, there's been a bit been a
，
bit of a stagnation in I think it was
我发现从
2020ish time. But then also when you
2020 年左右开始，预期寿命似乎出现了一些停滞。 但当你
look at a lot of these chronic diseases,
观察很多慢性疾病时，
whether it's diabetes, whether it's
无论是糖尿病还是
cancer, these things seem to be on the
癌症，这些疾病的发病率似乎都在
rise. So, as a nation, it feels like
上升。 所以，作为一个国家，我们感觉
we've got more information than ever
自己比以往任何时候都掌握了更多信息
before, but when you look at the
，但当你查看
objective numbers, for some reason,
客观数据时，由于某种原因，
we're not going in the right direction.
我们并没有朝着正确的方向前进。
What's your your 30,000 foot view on it?
你从宏观角度看待这个问题？   在
30,000 foot, there's more and more
三万英尺的高空，
people in the world. So, once you get
世界上的人口越来越多。 所以，一旦病例
huge numbers, uh, the diseases that
数量庞大，
affect most people are going to magnify.
影响大多数人的疾病就会加剧。
So, just as a a matter of math, we're
所以，从数学角度来看，我们
going to see more of these chronic
将会看到更多这类慢性
diseases. Um, but we're also going to be
疾病。 嗯，但我们也将
seeing two things that are happening
看到两件
that uh actually oppose each other. One
实际上相互对立的事情正在发生。 一方面，
over 20, 30, 50 years from the
过去 20、30、50 年间，
industrialization of food, from the
食品工业化、
industrialization of health care, from
医疗保健工业化、
degradation of the environment. Those
环境恶化等因素造成了生活方式和饮食习惯上的危害。 这些都
are all things that take time to
需要时间才能
manifest. And so to some extent we are
显现出来。 因此，在某种程度上，我们
presently seeing that the fallout of
目前正在看到我们
made in the 1950s and60s and 70s and so
在 20 世纪 50 年代、60 年代、70 年代等等时期所采取的一些不太好的举措的后果
on and so forth. So decades later we're
。 几十年过去了，我们
beginning to see the consequences
开始看到几十年前
devastation of things that happened
发生的事情所带来的毁灭性后果
decades ago. That's one side of
。 这是提高
prevalence of of health conditions bad
健康状况（包括不良
health conditions. There's another side
健康状况）发生率和患病率的一个方面。 另一方则持
that is counterveailing and the other
相反观点，而
side which is the side I that's the team
我所在的球队也持相反观点，这真的
I play on is it really exciting because
很令人兴奋，因为
one thing that's different is that we
不同之处在于，我们
have now have tremendous scientific
现在拥有强大的科学
power to get in there and probe diseases
力量去深入研究疾病，实际上
and also indeed pro probe health which
也可以研究健康问题，而
is something we're not doing often
我们在这方面做得还
enough and in so doing we're actually
不够。通过这样做，我们实际上
able to find solutions to the problems
能够找到解决问题的方案，从而
that that counter some of those harms.
抵消一些危害。
So, we're beginning to discover now how
所以，我们现在开始发现
do we actually prevent diabetes? How do
究竟该如何预防糖尿病？
we prevent cardiovascular disease? Can
我们如何预防心血管疾病？
we reverse heart disease? And even
心脏病可以逆转吗？ 即使是
conditions that seemed like no-win
看似毫无胜算的
situations. And I like to talk about
情况。 我喜欢谈论的
this is that in my career, I never
是，在我的职业生涯中，我从未
thought as a physician I would actually
想过作为一名医生，我竟然能够亲眼
see the cure to cancer, the end of
见证癌症的治愈，癌症的终结
cancer. But actually, I tell you, I have
。 但实际上，我告诉你，我
now seen where the end of cancer is
现在已经看到了癌症终结的希望所在
coming from. I've seen how the war is
。 我已经看到了这场战争
going to finish because I've had well
将如何结束，因为我已经有了
over a dozen patients and there are
十几位病人，而且还有
hundreds of people like this that are
数百名像我这样的人
starting to form that can go from stage
正在形成，他们可以从癌症晚期（也就是绝症）转变
four cancer that's game over cancer to
为癌症早期（
stage zero. We can do this. And it not
零期）。 我们能做到。 虽然它还不适合
for everybody yet, but we're beginning
所有人，但我们开始
to see where the light at the end of the
看到隧道尽头的曙光了
tunnel is. And it involves your immune
。 这和你的免疫
system. And some of the remarkable
系统有关。 一些非凡的
scientific breakthroughs are teaching us
科学突破告诉我们，
that our body heals itself against
我们的身体能够以
that the pharmaceutical industry can't
制药行业
by itself do, but it really relies on
自身无法做到的方式治愈像癌症这样严重的疾病，但这实际上依赖于
the body. So when you talk about food as
身体自身。 所以，当你谈论食物作为
medicine or medicine as medicine, none
药物或药物作为药物时，
of them are as powerful as what the body
它们都不如人体
is hardwired to do by itself. When I
自身固有的机制强大。 每当我
think about something like cancer, it's
想起癌症这类疾病，都会感到
slightly terrifying because it feels
有些恐惧，因为感觉
like a game of roulette. It feels like
就像在玩轮盘赌。 感觉
the the people that get cancer, it's
患癌症这件事
completely random and that our outcomes
完全是随机的，我们的命运就像玩
are also a game of roulette. And this is
轮盘赌一样。 而这个
someone that knows very little about
人对
cancer. I hear someone that I thought
癌症却知之甚少。 我听说一些我认为
was very very healthy get cancer and
非常非常健康的人得了癌症，
then their outcomes whether they they
然后他们的结果，无论是否
beat it or not also seem to be largely
战胜癌症，似乎很大程度上也
down to chance sometimes. That's how it
取决于运气。
seems. What do you think of that view?
看起来是这样。 你觉得这种观点怎么样？
Yeah, I'm going to give you a brand new
是的，我要给你们带来一个
view of thinking about cancer and that
关于癌症的全新观点，那就是
is that we are all forming cancer in our
我们
bodies all the time from the time we
从
were kids. you don't have clinical
孩提时代起，体内就一直在形成癌症。 你没有临床上的
cancer, you haven't gone to the doctor
癌症症状，也没有去医院
to get a diagnosis, still start forming
确诊，却仍然开始形成
cancers. And let me tell you why.
癌症。 让我来告诉你为什么。
Cancers are like pimples in our body.
癌症就像我们身体上的粉刺。
All right? And this is shocking to some
好的？ 有些
people to hear, but our the human body
人听到这个消息可能会感到震惊，但我们的人体
is made up of about 40 trillion cells.
是由大约 40 万亿个细胞组成的。
That's more cells in our body than stars
我们体内的细胞数量比
in a clear sky. All right? And these
晴朗夜空中的星星数量还要多。 好的？ 这些
cells have to divide uh to be able to
细胞必须分裂才能
reproduce themselves. uh copy and paste.
自我复制。 呃，复制粘贴。
Every cell has its own genetic material
每个细胞都有其自身的遗传物质，
called DNA. It's our instructions for
称为DNA。 这是我们
how our cells are work. So, you got to
细胞运作的指令。 所以，你得
copy and paste uh your DNA. All right?
复制粘贴你的DNA。 好的？
Now, copy and pasting is a tricky thing
现在，复制粘贴要做好是一门技巧
to do really well. So, if I gave you a
。 所以，斯蒂芬，如果我给你
sentence to write, Stephen, and I said,
一句话让你写，我说：
"Copy it 10 times on a word document,
“把它复制到 Word 文档里 10 遍，
you'll do it perfectly." If I get told
你就能写得完美无缺。” 如果让我
you to copy it a thousand times, you're
抄写一千遍，你肯定会
going to make a few mistakes. Good thing
犯一些错误。 幸好
that we have spellch check to fix it, to
我们有拼写检查功能来纠正错误，它可以
catch it and fix it. But if I ask you to
发现并纠正错误。 但是，如果我让你
copy a single sentence 40 trillion
复制一个句子 40 万亿
times, you're going to make so many
次，你会犯很多
mistakes that your spell check isn't
错误，以至于你的拼写检查也无法
even going to be a to catch all of it.
全部发现。
Okay? And that's what's happening in our
好的？ 这就是我们
body every single day as we are
体内每天都在发生的事情，因为我们每天都在进行
replicating ourselves. We're going to
自我复制。 我们会
make mistakes. And whenever there's a
犯错。 每当出现
mistake that's being made that isn't
错误而没有被
caught and fixed, that's a mutation. And
发现和纠正时，那就是变异。
so we have mutations that are forming in
因此，我们体内会形成一些突变，这只是我们
outcome of being alive and doing our
活着、做
thing and we're not sick from those
事情的结果，但我们并不会因为这些
mutations. But every mutation is the
突变而生病。 但每一次突变都是
beginning of a microscopic cancer. Take
微小癌症的开端。 猜猜看，在
copying and pasting your own body uh are
复制和粘贴自身身体DNA的过程中，
made every 24 hours. Take a guess. This
每24小时会发生多少次错误？ 猜猜看。 这
has been calculated randomly. Well, you
是随机计算得出的。 嗯，你看，
there's so many cells in my body.
我身体里有很多细胞。
It's going to be a big number. A
这将是一个很大的数字。 一
million. Okay. Every day, every 24
百万。 好的。 每天，每 24
hours, there are 10,000 mistakes that
小时，
are made in your body that your body
你的身体都会发生 10,000 个错误，而你的身体却
doesn't catch that keep on that
无法察觉这些错误，这些错误会不断地
propagate in the document of our body as
在我们的身体记录中传播开
it goes on. 10 10,000. Each of those is
来。  10 10,000。 每一种都是
a microscopic cancer. A microscopic
肉眼看不见的癌症。 微小的
cancer is just that. It's microscopic.
癌症就是微小的癌症。 它是微观的。
It's too small to be seen with the naked
它太小了，肉眼无法看到
eye, but it's abnormal. And that thing
，但这很不正常。 那东西
could turn turn into a big tumor that
可能会变成一个巨大的肿瘤，
could eventually kill you. So why don't
最终可能会要了你的命。 那么，为什么
we die from cancer all the time? Now
我们不总是死于癌症呢？
this is actually something that I see as
作为一名医生，这确实是我看到的问题
a physician. I have a patient diagnosed
。 我有一位病人被诊断出
with cancer. They always ask me, "Dr.
患有癌症。 他们总是问我：“
Lee, why me? Why did I get breast
李医生，为什么是我？为什么我会得
cancer, colon cancer, pancreatic cancer,
乳腺癌、结肠癌、胰腺癌、
brain tumor?" A very very uh natural
脑瘤？” 一个非常非常……很自然的
question. And I do my best to try to
问题。 我会尽力尝试用
provide an empathic answer to that
同理心来回答这个
question. But as a researcher, I have a
问题。 但作为一名研究人员，我有一个
more interesting question. Given the
更有趣的问题。 鉴于
number of mutations that occur in our
我们体内每天都会发生大量的基因突变
body every single day, why don't we get
，为什么我们患
cancer more often? Why don't we all get
癌症的几率并不高？ 为什么我们不都是在
cancer as kids? You know, cancer can
孩子小时候就得癌症？ 你知道，癌症也会
happen in children, but not as often as
发生在儿童身上，但远不如基因
we have mutations. And it turns out this
突变那么常见。 事实证明，这
was the great unlock for me in terms of
对我来说是健康方面的一个重要转折点
health. The reason that we don't become
。 我们之所以不会因
more sick from all kinds of diseases,
各种疾病（
including cancer, is because our body is
包括癌症）而病情加重，是因为我们的身体
hardwired with its own health defense
本身就具备强大的健康防御
systems. So that we've got these
系统。 所以我们现在拥有了这些威力
swashbuckling defenses that are firing
十足、​​火力
on all cylinders. All day long from the
全开的防御体系。 从
from the moment we're born until our
我们出生到
very last breath, these systems that are
生命的最后一刻，
inside our body defend our health,
我们体内的这些系统每时每刻都在保护我们的健康，
including the microscopic cancers, spots
包括微小的癌细胞，它们会发现癌细胞，并将
them, takes them out. kind of like a
它们清除掉。 就像一辆
police cruiser patrolling a quiet
警车在安静的
neighborhood sees a drug dealer on the
街区巡逻，发现街角有个毒贩
corner, pops them in the back of the
，就把他抓进
police vehicle and takes them away
警车后座，带走，
cleaning up the neighborhood. That's how
清理街区一样。 这就是
our body naturally cleans up these
我们身体自然清除这些
microscopic cancers. And so when you
微小癌细胞的方式。 所以，当你把
talk about cancer as a scary disease,
癌症说成是一种可怕的疾病时，
you're thinking about the person whose
你想到的是那些
body has failed to detect and eliminate
身体未能发现和消除
the microscopic cancers and it's become
微小癌细胞，导致癌细胞
large enough to actually become a
增大到足以构成
threat. Now here's a question for you.
威胁的人。 现在我问你一个问题。
So we tell women to actually do a self
所以我们建议女性在
breast exam when they're taking a
淋浴时进行乳房自检
shower. You know, look for lumps or
。 你知道，要留意身上是否有肿块或
bumps and you know if you find one, you
凸起，如果发现肿块，
know, certainly go to your doctor
一定要立即去看医生
immediately for an exam.
进行检查。
with a trained person can feel with
受过训练的人
their with their hands in the breast is
用手在乳房中能摸到的最小的癌症
one centimeter in diameter. A 1 cm
直径为一厘米。 一个1厘米的
breast cancer already has 1 billion
乳腺癌肿瘤中已经含有10亿个
cancer cells that have already
癌细胞，这些癌细胞已经
multiplied. That microscopic cancer
增殖。 那种微小的癌细胞
multiplied a billion times. That's the
增殖了十亿倍。 这是
smallest one you can feel. Now immune
你能感觉到的最小的磁共振。 现在免疫
systems not taking that amount. All
系统无法吸收那么多。
right? So, you need a better immune
好的？ 所以，
system if you I want a shot at this and
如果你想尝试这种方法，而
not just chemo or hormonal therapy. And
不仅仅是化疗或激素疗法，你需要更好的免疫系统。 而其中
that's where some of these incredible
一些令人难以置信的
advances are taking place. But there's
进步正是在那里发生的。 但还有
another one. In order to feed a billion
另一个。 要想养活十亿个
cancer cells, you need blood vessels to
癌细胞，就需要血管来为
feed them. So, the cancers as they get
它们提供养分。 所以，随着癌细胞体积
bigger, they hijack our own circulation
增大，它们会劫持我们自身的血液循环系统
to feed themselves. Okay? It's kind of
来获取营养。 好的？ 这就像
like terrorists kicking in the cockpit
恐怖分子踹开驾驶舱
door to take over the controls of the
门夺取飞机控制权一样
plane. They want to actually get your
。 他们真正想要的是让你的
blood vessels to feed themselves. Now
血管能够自我供血。
normally the body knows how to control
通常情况下，人体自身能够控制
those blood vessels. It's called
这些血管。 这叫做
angioenesis. Angio blood vessels genesis
血管生成。 血管生成：
how the body grows and controls them.
身体如何生长和控制血管。
That's my area of research. So naturally
那是我的研究领域。 所以，
our body knows how to prevent blood
我们的身体自然而然地知道如何阻止
vessels from feeding cancers and yet
血管为癌细胞提供养分，同时也
knows how to uh direct blood vessels to
知道如何引导血管为
feed healthy tissues. So guess what? A
健康组织提供养分。 你猜怎么着？ 一个直径
one centimeter tumor with 1 billion
一厘米、含有10亿个
cancer cells is fed by 100 million blood
癌细胞的肿瘤，由1亿条血管
vessels courarssing into the tumor to
流入肿瘤内部为其提供
feed them. And we've studied this in the
营养。 我们在实验室里研究过这个问题
laboratory. The moment that a single
。 一旦有一根
blood vessel touches a tumor, tiny
血管接触到肿瘤，哪怕是
microscopic tumor, it will grow 16,000
微小的肿瘤，它也会
times in size in just two weeks. Wow.
在短短两周内增大 16000 倍。 哇。
All right. So, I've told you some scary
好的。 所以，我刚才告诉了你们一些令人担忧的
statistics, but now let me kind of give
统计数据，现在让我来告诉
you the where the breakthroughs are
你们，突破性进展正在
coming through. Right. So with this kind
发生。 正确的。 那么，有了这些
of knowledge, what do we what can we do
知识，我们能
with cancers? Not just breast cancers,
对癌症做些什么呢？ 不仅是乳腺癌，
but in general. Number one, we know that
而是所有癌症。 首先，我们知道，
if you boost your immune system with
如果你通过
foods, with exercise, diet, lifestyle,
食物、运动、饮食和生活方式来增强免疫系统，
you're going to actually make your
你的
immune defense is a lot stronger to
免疫防御能力实际上会大大增强，从而
patrol your body to wipe out those
巡逻你的身体，消灭那些
microscopic cancers. That's why healthy
微小的癌细胞。 这就是为什么健康的
diet lifestyle lowers the risk of
饮食生活方式能够降低
cancer. That's why eating the right
患癌风险。 这就是为什么食用能够
foods that boost your immunity can
增强免疫力的正确食物也能
substantially lower your risk of cancer
大幅降低患癌风险的原因
as well. We also know that you can eat
。 我们也知道，可以通过食用某些
foods that support, prompt up, fortify
食物来支持、促进、增强
your body's natural ability to control
身体控制血管的自然能力
blood vessels. Keep those blood vessels
。 让血管保持在
where they're supposed to be and get rid
它们应该在的位置，并清除
of those blood vessels where you don't
那些你不
want them to be, which is kicking in the
希望它们出现在那里的血管，这些血管就像驾驶舱里的炮弹一样，
cockpit to take over your circulation to
会接管你的血液循环，为
feed cancers. So, if you eat foods like
癌细胞提供养分。 所以，如果你吃一些
that are anti-androgenic foods that like
抗雄激素的食物，比如
are unstable, you've got um coffee and
不稳定的食物，还有咖啡和
tea, both of those contain natural
茶，这两种食物都含有天然
substances that cut off the blood supply
物质，可以切断血液供应，使
and starve cancers. That's a good thing.
癌细胞挨饿。 这是件好事。
So, that's why we know our what we do
所以，这就是为什么我们知道，我们的
with our diet can actually help to lower
饮食习惯实际上可以帮助降低
the risk of cancer as well. I'm assuming
患癌风险。 我假设
the opposite also applies. I I could eat
反过来也成立。 我可以吃一些
foods, I can drink things that cause my
食物，喝一些饮料，这些都会导致我的
body to malfunction. I makes the blood
身体机能失调。 它会导致血管
vessels unregulated makes and starts to
不受控制地生长，并开始为
feed the cancer, right? Yeah,
癌细胞提供养分，对吗？ 是的，
absolutely. So, let's talk let's talk a
绝对的。 那么，我们就来谈谈
little bit about that. So, so I told you
这个吧。 所以，我之前就告诉过你们，
the body's hardwired with these
人体天生就具备这些
defenses. Shields up, right? That's what
防御机制。 护盾升起，对吧？ 这就是
we want to do because shields are
我们想要做的，因为护盾
already normally up. You want to raise
通常都是开启的。 你想把
them higher, but what about and this is
它们提高得更高，但是……这是
a brilliant question you're asking a
一个绝妙的问题，你问了一个
very probing question. What are the
非常有见地的问题。 什么
things that take your shields down,
事情会让你放下戒备
right? What are the things that turn off
？ 家里哪些东西会关闭
the smoke alarm in your house that
烟雾报警器并
unlock the doors? Can I take a guess?
解锁门锁？ 我可以猜一下吗？
Is it
是
this? Okay, now I know the answer that
这个吗？ 好了，现在我知道
you're setting this conversation up for,
你展开这场对话的真正目的是什么了，
which is a burger with meat. Uh, is that
那就是吃肉汉堡。 呃，那
actually uh disease-causing? And I would
真的会致病吗？ 我会
I would tell you that yes and no. A
告诉你，答案既是也不是。
burger is something that many people
汉堡是很多人
enjoy eating. And I would say eating
喜欢吃的食物。 我认为，
not going to harm you if your health
如果你的身体免疫力强，偶尔吃肉、吃汉堡，甚至吃一些超加工食品，都不会对你造成伤害
defenses are naturally strong. But if
。 但如果
you make it a habit, a regular habit of
你养成习惯，经常
eating this at the expense of eating
吃这种食物，而忽略了
healthier foods, more plant-based foods,
更健康的食物、更多的植物性食物和
less processed foods. Okay. Um, you are
更少的加工食品。 好的。 嗯，
actually going to tip the uh your odds
实际上你这样做会增加患病的几率，让
get you. What that what that means is
你更容易感染疾病。 这意味着
that over eating fast foods like burgers
过度食用汉堡等快餐食品
will actually contribute to taking your
实际上会削弱你的
uh health defenses down, shields down.
健康防御能力。
So what are those things then that bring
那么，究竟是什么因素会
the shield down? You were saying okay
打破这种保护机制呢？ 你刚才说的是
excess sodium, too much salt, which can
钠含量过高，盐分过多，
be present in a lot of restaurant foods.
很多餐馆食物中都含有这些物质。
People eat out a lot, go to restaurants
人们经常外出就餐，经常去餐馆
all the time. You ever you ever go to
。 你有没有去过
the back of a kitchen of a restaurant to
餐馆的后厨，
see how they're salting seasoning their
看看他们是怎么给食物加盐调味的
food? Patrons love salty food. It makes
？ 顾客喜欢咸味食物。 它能让
food taste really great. There's a, you
食物变得非常美味。 你
know, our brains uh respond very well to
知道，我们的大脑对咸味食物的反应非常好
salty food. That high sodium levels
。 高钠水平
actually speeds up, accelerates our
实际上会加速
cellular aging, so we actually age
细胞衰老，所以我们实际上会衰老得
faster. But it also um is a huge wear
更快。 但这也会对
and tear on our health defenses,
我们的健康防御系统造成巨大的损耗，
specifically our circulation, our our
特别是我们的血液循环、血管
blood vessels, our androgenesis system
，
is taken down by excess salt. Okay, I've
过量的盐会损害我们的雄激素生成系统。 好的，我
got a question here. Obviously there's a
有个问题。 显然，
a big movement at the moment around
目前人们对
hydration and electrolytes and these
补水和电解质非常关注，这些
electrolytes have magnesium, potassium,
电解质含有镁、钾和
they have sodium in them. Yeah. So a lot
钠。 是的。 所以
of people are now taking electrolytes to
现在很多人都在服用电解质补充剂来
hydrate themselves.
补充水分。
Is there a a risk here? So the great
这里存在风险吗？ 所以好
news is that the healthy body has got
消息是，健康的身体
its own titration system for
自身就拥有调节电解质的滴定系统
electrolytes. If you drink a electrolyte
。 如果你喝
fortified beverage, you're your body's
添加了电解质的饮料，你的身体会
going to take everything it needs and
吸收它需要的所有电解质，其余的则会通过尿液排出体外
it's going to pee out the rest. You're
。 你
going to eliminate through your urine.
会通过尿液排出体外。
All right. However, sodium
好的。 然而，钠
uh is one of those electrolytes is
是一种电解质，
present like you're not drinking
就像你不会
electrolyte fluid all day long, but
整天喝电解质饮料一样，但
sodium you're eating it in almost every
你几乎在所有食物中都摄入了钠，
food that you actually have except
除了
perhaps dessert, but maybe even then.
甜点，但即使是甜点，也可能含有钠。
And so this is one of the things that we
因此，我们
realize is sodium is a high risk for
意识到，钠是
hypertension, high blood pressure,
高血压、血液循环系统
inflammation of the lining of your
内膜炎症的高风险因素，这会对
to your health and it takes down your
你的健康造成很多不良后果，并削弱
circulation um health defenses that we
我们之前提到的血液循环系统健康防御能力
talked about. High blood sugar can also
。 高血糖也会
do the same thing. So if you're eating
导致同样的问题。 所以，如果你摄入
an excess of added sugar, we all have
过多的添加糖，我们
heard by now glucose spikes and glucose
现在都听说过血糖飙升和血糖
crashes. I don't actually use those
骤降的现象。 顺便说一句，我其实并不使用这些
words by the way. I don't like to
词。 我不喜欢用
terms of spikes and crashes. I think
峰值和谷值来描述我们身体的新陈代谢。 我认为
those are fear words. They get
这些词语带有恐惧的意味。 它们能吸引
attention. Uh they they do make you pay
关注。 嗯，它们确实会让你
attention to it, but in fact really our
注意到这一点，但实际上，我们
the healthy body sort of has, you know,
健康的身体会有
smooth ups and smooth downs. They're
平稳的起伏。 它们是
gentle slopes up and down of our blood
我们血糖水平的平缓上升和下降
sugar. And that's completely fine. All
。 完全没问题。
right? And and it should be like that.
好的？ 就应该是这样。
However, if you have an uphill climb of
但是，如果你
your blood glucose and it continues to
的血糖持续升高，并且一直
stay up, that can actually happen if
保持高位，这实际上是由于
you're eating too much added sugar.
摄入了过多的添加糖造成的。
Okay, added sugar, ultrarocessed foods.
好的，添加糖，超加工食品。
What happens is that your blood sugars,
结果是，你的血糖，也就是
your intake of the sugar, glucose rises
你摄入的糖分、葡萄糖水平会不断升高，
up up up and now your body has your
现在你的身体需要通过
metabolism to chase that blood sugar
新陈代谢来
down and it's got to work harder and
降低血糖，它必须更加努力地工作，并
make more insulin. And eventually you
产生更多的胰岛素。 最终，你的身体
just wear out that system and then you
系统就会衰竭，导致
have a high blood blood glucose and an
血糖升高、
insensitive metabolism and that's the
新陈代谢迟钝，这就像是
beginning of sort of the the dominoes
多米诺骨牌效应
starting to fall apart in your body. And
开始在你体内瓦解的开始。
so sugar, high blood sugar, added sugar
所以，糖、高血糖、添加糖
is a problem. You get it from fruit, not
都是个问题。 从水果中就能获得，没
a problem. Okay? No one's going to be
问题。 好的？ 没人会
eating a crazy amount of fruit. This is
大量吃水果。 这就是
why extremes aren't good. Diversity.
为什么走极端不好。 多样性。
Switch it out. Keep it interesting for
换掉它。 保持它对
yourself. This is what our human nature
你自己来说有趣就好。 这就是我们人性所
uh wants anyway. Uh it's how we're
渴望的。 呃，这是我们
hardwired. You you'll actually be fine.
与生俱来的本能。 你真的会没事的。
So salt, sugar, those are two offenders.
所以，盐和糖，这两种就是罪魁祸首。
Okay. Um alcohol is another one that
好的。 嗯，酒精也是另一种会
defenses over time. You know, people
随着时间推移削弱你健康防御能力的物质。 你知道，人们会
say, "Well, what about red wine? Isn't
问：“那红酒呢？
red wine healthy?" What I would say is
红酒不是有益健康吗？” 我想说的是，
that actually the fermented products the
实际上，红酒中含有的红葡萄发酵产物
or the bioactives that come out of red
或生物活性物质，例如
grapes from the skin of red grapes
红葡萄皮中的
properties of the resveratrol and other
白藜芦醇和其他多酚，可能具有一些健康功效，
in wine, but it's never the alcohol.
但真正有益健康的绝非酒精。
It's not the alcohol in the beer, the
问题不在于啤酒、葡萄酒或威士忌中的酒精
wine, the whiskey. Nope. None, none of
。 没有。 不，这些都不
that is the alcohol is is a universal
是酒精是一种普遍存在的
toxin. Toxic to your brain, toxic to
毒素。 对大脑有害，对
your liver, toxic to your heart. Can't
肝脏有害，对心脏有害。
get away from that. Your body will
摆脱不了这一点。 你的身体会
recover. Shields up little. It can take
恢复的。 稍微抬起盾牌。 它能承受轻微的
a ding. It's like a, you know, like a
磕碰。 这就像，你知道，就像
drink is sort of like a driving behind a
开车
truck and it flings a little pebble
跟在卡车后面，卡车溅起一颗小石子，
right into your windshield. You might
直接打到你的挡风玻璃上一样。 你的
get a little spider in the windshield.
挡风玻璃上可能会有只小蜘蛛。
Okay, don't worry. It'll repair itself.
好的，别担心。 它会自行修复。
You You'll fix yourself. You'll bounce
你会自己解决的。 你会重新振作起来的
back. It's not going to break your
。 它不会打破你的
windshield. But if you keep on drinking,
挡风玻璃。 但如果你继续喝下去，
you're actually gonna smash your
你真的会把
windshield. And that's why alcoholism is
挡风玻璃砸碎的。 这就是为什么酗酒
so devastating to the health. But you
对健康危害如此之大的原因。 但你
know, regular a small amount of alcohol.
知道，偶尔少量饮酒是正常的。
So alcohol itself is is a toxin. Do you
所以酒精本身就是一种毒素。 你
drink? Uh I I rarely drink and when I
喝酒吗？ 呃，我很少喝酒，即使
drink it's in moderation. Mhm. And I was
喝也是适量。 嗯。 我当时也在
thinking about stress as well. Does that
考虑压力问题。
bring down the So besides the foods you
那么，除了你吃的食物之外
eat, other things that can compromise
，还有哪些因素会损害
your health defenses? Uh, and by the
你的健康防御能力呢？ 呃，顺便一
way, there are five health defenses. We
提，生命防御有五种。 我们
talked about blood vessels. We talked
讨论了血管。 我们谈到了
about immunity, but there's three other
免疫力，但还有其他三个方面对于以最
the healthiest way possible. If you
健康的方式运作至关重要。 如果你
want, if you want longevity, you need
想要长寿，你需要
all five of your health defenses and
五种甚至更多的健康防御机制都
more to be working in your favor. But
为你发挥作用。 但是
stress, what does stress do? Lowers your
压力，压力究竟会带来什么影响？ 降低你的
immune system. Shields down. All right?
免疫力。 盾牌放下。 好的？
Those microscopic cancers. Whoa. That's
那些微小的癌症。 哇。 这就是
why stressful people are more vulnerable
为什么压力大的人更容易
to de developing diseases like cancer.
患上癌症等疾病的原因。
All right? Stress also causes your blood
好的？ 压力还会导致
pressure to go up and causes uh
血压升高，并导致
released from your brain and your
大脑、
kidneys, your adrenal glands that ought
肾脏和肾上腺释放神经递质和激素，这些都会
to wear down your circulation. Now your
损害血液循环。 现在你的
androgenesis system is also uh not
雄激素生成系统也无法正常
functioning uh as well to protect
运作，无法保护
yourself and keep good blood flow going
自身并保持血液正常流向
where it needs to go. Now your
需要的地方。 现在你的
circulation is actually down. Um so
血液循环实际上已经恶化了。 嗯，所以
again, stress also can actually damage
再说一遍，压力实际上也会损害
the DNA. We talked about naturally
DNA。 我们自然而然地谈到了
copying and pasting and having errors.
复制粘贴以及出错的问题。
add some stress to it. Now, it's kind of
增加一些压力。 现在，这就像……
like um you're trying to copy that
嗯，你试图
sentence I was telling you perfectly.
完美地复制我刚才跟你说的那句话。
Now, I'm going to come in and just smash
现在，我要
your fingers down every now and then,
时不时地按压你的手指，
and let's see if you actually make a
看看你是不是真的会
mistake. You will. All right? Stress
犯错。 你会。 好的？ 压力
will actually do that. It's devastating
确实会造成这种情况。
to have so much stress continuously.
长期承受如此大的压力令人难以承受。   顺便
Listen, by the way, I want to be really
说一句，我想
clear to anybody listening or watching
向所有正在收听或观看
this, a little stress is actually good
这段视频的人明确说明，一点压力实际上
for you. You know, like just being
对你有好处。 你知道，就像
coddled all day long and living in a
整天被娇惯着，生活在一个
happy bubble. That doesn't that's not
幸福的泡泡里一样。 这样做
that's not good for our health either.
对我们的健康也不好。
We kind of get laxidasical. We let our
我们有点变得懒散了。 我们放松了
guard down. Little stress. I mean,
警惕。 压力不大。 我的意思是，
anybody who's hardworking, you know,
任何一个努力工作、取得
successful knows that, you know, it's
成功的人都知道，
not the no pain, no gain. It's that the
不经历痛苦就没有收获。 正是这种伴随而来的
that the grit that goes along with it,
磨砺，带来的
which gives a little stress keeps us
些许压力，让我们保持
sharp, you know, uh which is a which is
敏锐，你知道，这是
a good thing. You want to be on you want
一件好事。 你想参与，你想
to be on. So, a little stress is good,
参与。 所以，适度的压力是有益的，
but when that stress is unabated, it
但如果压力持续不断，就会
literally sinks your health defenses. It
严重损害你的健康防御能力。 这
is just taking those shields down. Yeah,
只是解除那些护盾而已。 是的，
I've noticed that with myself. I've
我自己也注意到了这一点。
spent the last 10 years running
过去十年，我一直在经营
businesses, a little bit more than 10
企业，
years now, but probably the last 13
现在可能超过十年了，但或许过去十三年里我一直在经营
years running businesses. And the only
企业。 只有在连续两周
after two weeks of stress.
压力过大之后，我才会真正生病，卧床一周，而且感觉非常非常难受。
So when I say two weeks of stress, what
所以，当我说两周的压力时，
I mean there is when something happens
我的意思是，当
in my life business where that it's kind
我的生活和事业中发生一些事情，导致压力持续存在，甚至成为一种慢性
of chronic and it's enduring stress. I
压力时。 我
can deal with having a stressful day. I
可以应对压力大的一天。 连续
can deal with having two stressful days
两天压力大我可以应付
in a row. But when I've had like two
。 但是，如果我持续
weeks of an enduring issue, like an
两周左右都受到某种问题的困扰，比如
enduring angst or a
持续的焦虑或
problem, almost perfectly predictably, a
难题，几乎不出所料，
week later, I'm sick. And I'm extremely
一周后，我就病倒了。 我很少
rarely sick because I think I sleep
生病，因为我觉得我睡眠质量
really well. Like I think I eat really
很好。 我觉得自己吃得很
clean. And so it's taught me something
健康。 所以它教会了我一些东西，
about if I zoom out on that and see
如果我把视角拉远，看看
what's going on in my body, well
我的身体发生了什么，
eventually like my body's kind of my
最终就会发现，我的身体，我的
immune system is running out of energy
免疫系统，
almost more than your immune system. So
几乎比你的免疫系统更容易耗尽能量。 所以，
when you're super stressed, it also
当你压力过大时，也会
interferes with your ability to sleep
影响你的睡眠质量
well. Yeah. When you're sleeping well,
。 是的。 你知道，睡眠质量好的时候，
you know, sleeping is something that I
睡眠是我小时候就被
was taught when I was a kid. When you're
教导的事情。
sleeping, you're resting. And when
睡觉的时候，你就是在休息。
you're resting, you're not active,
休息的时候，你就不活动了，
right? Well, that's just our physical
对吧？ 嗯，那只是我们的肉体层面
self. It turns out when we're sleeping,
。 事实证明，当我们睡觉时，
even though our muscles may not be
即使我们的肌肉不像
moving like we are during the day, in
白天那样活动，但
fact, a lot of other systems including
实际上，包括
our health defenses are being repaired,
我们的健康防御系统在内的许多其他系统都在睡眠期间得到修复、
renewed, regenerated, rebooted while we
更新、再生和重启
are sleeping. So in those ideally eight
。 所以，在理想的
hours, 7 to n hours, eight's the sweet,
八小时、七小时到 n 小时之间（八小时是个非常
sweet number, you know, our brain is
理想的数字），我们的大脑会进行
cleansing itself, detoxifying itself,
自我清洁、排毒和
releasing. Do you know about the
释放。 你知道
lymphatic system in the brain? Not as
大脑中的淋巴系统吗？
well as you do. Okay. Well, there's a
不如你做得好。 好的。 嗯，
in our brains that's called the
我们的大脑中有一个叫做
glimpmphatic system and it's shut
脑脊液系统的下水道系统，它
tightly during the daytime when we're
在白天我们
using our brain doing our work uh
使用大脑工作
whatever we're doing and during the day
或做任何事情的时候都是紧闭的，而白天我们
inside our brain during the day. It's
的大脑中会积累很多毒素。 这
just a matter of functioning. All right?
只是正常运转的问题。 好的？
And what happens is that those toxins
结果就是，这些毒素会
accumulate which is that you know at the
不断积累，尤其是在你经历了
end of a really really tough hard day.
一天非常非常辛苦的工作之后。
You got if not a headache you've got
即使你没头痛，你也会
your you feel like your brain is it's
感觉大脑像被
full. It's the cup runth over. Right.
塞满了东西。 杯子都溢出来了。 正确的。
All right. So when you go to sleep guess
好的。 所以当你睡觉的时候，猜猜看
what this sewer system it's like the
这个下水道系统是什么样子？它就像
sewers of par underneath Paris. The
巴黎地下的下水道一样。
grates open up suddenly and it drains
通风口会突然打开，在
those toxins out while you're sleeping.
你睡觉的时候把那些毒素排出去。
And only when you get good sleep. So,
只有睡眠充足才能达到效果。 所以，
when you're stressed and you're not
当你压力过大且
getting good sleep, you start to
睡眠不足时，体内就会开始
accumulate these toxins that are never
积累这些毒素，这些毒素永远无法
quite cleaned up and your brain is not
完全清除，你的大脑也无法得到充分的
that cleaned up. When your brain's not
清洁。 当你的大脑没有得到
cleaned up, you're feeling foggy. So,
清理时，你会感到头脑昏沉。 所以，
think about the, you know, when you're
想想看，你知道，当你
in college, you pull an allnighter or
上大学的时候，如果你熬夜或者
you go to a party or whatever and you're
去参加派对什么的，
and you're staying up all night, you're
你整夜不睡，你就再也回不到从前了
never quite the same. It takes a while
。 大脑需要一段时间才能
for your brain to clean up itself. When
自我清理。 当
your brain is foggy, you tend to not
你大脑一片混乱时，往往难以
make as good decisions. I'm too tired to
做出明智的决定。 我太累了，没力气
work out. I'm too tired. I don't care
锻炼。 我太累了。 我不在乎
what I eat. I'm just hungry. I'm going
吃什么。 我只是饿了。 我
to eat anything. You start to make bad
什么都想吃。 你在饮食和生活方式方面开始做出错误的
decisions when it comes to diet and
选择
lifestyle. You see? So, it's a it it the
。 你看？ 所以，
stress can cascade on your health like
压力确实会像这样对你的健康产生连锁反应
that. Is there a certain stage of sleep
。 睡眠中是否存在某个特定阶段，
where the glimpmphatic system kicks in?
此时视觉系统会开始发挥作用？   是的
Yeah. It's during like the deep REM
。 这发生在深度快速眼动
sleep. Okay. That dreaming sleep. Okay.
睡眠阶段。 好的。 那梦乡般的睡眠。 好的。
And that usually comes later in the
而且这种情况通常也会在深夜发生
night as well. Correct. Correct. And in
。 正确的。 正确的。
more qual quantity later in the night.
之后，当晚还会有更多高质量的食物供应。
So, you need to really be getting a lot
所以，你真的需要保证充足的
of sleep. Now, the other thing about
睡眠。 此外，
deep sleep is while you're sleeping
深度睡眠的另一个好处是，当你睡得
really deeply, your metabolism is also
很沉的时候，你的新陈代谢也会
burning down fat. So, you think that
燃烧脂肪。 所以，你认为
you're not working out during the night,
你晚上没有锻炼，
you're right, you're not actually
没错，你确实没有
exercising, but in fact, your metabolism
锻炼，但实际上，你的新陈代谢
is burning fat because while you're
正在燃烧脂肪，因为当你
sleeping and your insulin levels don't
睡觉时，
need to be high because you're not
由于你没有
eating, insulin levels go down, your
进食，胰岛素水平不需要很高，胰岛素水平下降，你的
metabolism shifts gears. I I sort of
新陈代谢就改变了模式。 我经常用这个
give people the analogy. It's like your
比喻来解释。
your body is a race car, sports car,
你的身体就像一辆赛车、跑车，
like a Ferrari. During the day, you are
比如法拉利。 白天，你
in gear to drive, accumulate speed, and
挂挡开车，加速，
and you're you're revving your engines.
然后轰鸣引擎。
At night, you shift gears where you're
到了晚上，身体会转换到
actually burning down fat. You don't
燃烧脂肪的阶段。 你不需要
need to accumulate more fuel. Now,
储存更多燃料。 现在，
you're burning down the fuel. So, when
你正在消耗燃料。 所以，
you're sleeping, you're actually burning
睡觉的时候，你实际上是在燃烧
away fat. But when you don't sleep well
脂肪。 但是，如果你睡眠不好
or you don't sleep long enough, you're
或者睡眠时间不够长，你就
not burning down that fuel. That fuel
无法消耗掉那些能量。 这种能量会
accumulates, day or two of not good
逐渐积累，一两天
enough sleep, that's that's okay. Think
睡眠不足也没关系。 想想
about flying overseas, getting some jet
看，飞到国外，会不会有时差
lag. You got to catch up. Once you get
反应。 你得迎头赶上。 一旦把事情
catch up, you feel better. All right?
处理完，你就会感觉好多了。 好的？
But think about this like day in and day
但想想看，这种情况每天都会发生
out. Chronically stressed people are
。 长期处于压力之下的人
never getting good sleep. Add a little
总是无法获得良好的睡眠。 再加点
booze, alcohol to the to the equation.
酒，酒精进去。
You can kind of see the problems that
你大概能预见到一些问题
are going to build up. Your brain's
会逐渐累积起来。 你会感觉大脑一片
going to be foggy. your metabolism is
空白。 你的新陈代谢会
going to be out of whack. You're not
紊乱。 你并没有
burning as much fat from the calories
燃烧掉白天摄入的那么多卡路里所对应的脂肪
that you ate during the day. Now,
。 现在，
inflammation starts to uh rise in your
你的身体开始出现炎症，
body and that inflammation really takes
这种炎症会
down your health defenses and now you're
削弱你的健康防御能力，让你变得
much more vulnerable. So, in your own
更加脆弱。 所以，以你举的
example of where chronic stress leads to
慢性压力导致
poor sleep and then you get sick, no
睡眠质量差，然后生病的例子来说，这并不
surprise. If we go back up the thread
奇怪。 如果我们回到之前的讨论
there, we were talking about the sort of
，我们当时是在谈论
individual perspective on cancer. And I
个人对癌症的看法。 我
was looking at some stats here and it
查看了一些统计数据，数据
says that the number one Google search
显示，与癌症相关的谷歌搜索排名第一的
related to cancer is breast cancer. One
是乳腺癌。 每
in two people will develop some form of
两个人中就有一人会
cancer during their lifetime. That's
在一生中罹患某种癌症。 这是英国国家
according to the NHS. Cancer is the
医疗服务体系（NHS）的说法。 癌症是
worldwide. And by 2040, there will be 28
全球第二大死因。 到 2040 年，全球每年将新增 2800 万例
million new cases of cancer each year
癌症病例
worldwide. But one of the most shocking
。 但
things that I saw was that globally
我看到的最令人震惊的事情之一是，全球
early onset cancer incidents has risen
早发性癌症病例
by about 80% by
在 1990 年至 2019 年间增加了约 80%。
which I'd sent to my team a couple of
几周前，我曾把一篇文章发给我的团队
weeks ago. It's it's called the worrying
。 这就是所谓的
puzzle behind the rise of early onset
早发性癌症病例增加背后令人担忧的谜题
cancer. And it says that there are
。 报告指出，
other cancers in people in their 20s,
20多岁、
30s and 40s. And it posits the question,
30多岁和40多岁的人群中，乳腺癌和其他癌症的病例正在增加。 它提出了这样一个问题：到底发生了
what is going on? Over the last 10
什么？ 过去 10
years, rates of colorctyl cancer among
年里，
different countries, including the UK,
包括英国、
US, France, Australia, Canada, Norway,
美国、法国、澳大利亚、加拿大、挪威
and Argentina. I mean, what is going on?
和阿根廷在内的 24 个不同国家 25 至 49 岁人群的结直肠癌发病率有所上升。 我的意思是，到底发生了什么事？
Yeah, that's a big question.
是的，这是个大问题。
So, are we seeing the results of more
那么，我们是否正在目睹
harms in our environment that we're
环境中更多有害物质的出现，
being exposed to that are more toxic and
这些有害物质毒性更大，
leading to earlier incidents of clinical
导致临床癌症病例提前发生
cancer? They're talking about clinical
？ 他们说的是临床
diagnosed cancer, not the invisible
诊断的癌症，而不是那些看不见的、一直在
microscopic ones that are forming all
形成的微小癌症
the time. Um, it's yes, it's very
。 嗯，是的，这非常令人
worrying. Are we be exposing ourselves
担忧。 我们是否会让自己暴露在
encountered today than before? Number
如今比以往更常见的事物之中？
one. Number two, are our defenses being
第一名。 第二，我们的防御是否正被
appreciate are compromising us? Most
我们之前没有意识到正在危害我们的势力所瓦解？ 很
likely both. It's most likely uh I mean
可能两者兼有。 最有可能的原因是，
the human makeup hasn't changed and so
人体构造并没有改变，所以一定是多种因素
it's got to be the fact a combination
共同作用的结果：一方面，
that we're being exposed to more harmful
我们接触到更多有害
things and though some of those harmful
物质；另一方面，一些有害
things are actually that you know
物质确实会
provoking more cancers but and we're
引发更多癌症；此外，我们
also being exposed to things that take
还接触到一些会
down our health defenses. So the balance
削弱我们健康防御能力的物质。 所以天平
is being tipped against us and it's
正在向我们不利的方向倾斜，这是
true. I can tell you that when I went to
事实。 我可以告诉你，我上
medical school I mean colorectile cancer
医学院的时候，结直肠癌
people even in their 50s. it was for
即使在 50 多岁的人身上也很少见。 这是给年纪
much older uh people. Uh now to see uh I
大得多的人用的。 呃，现在看来，呃，我的
mean there's even teenagers that have
意思是，甚至有青少年患上了结
actually developed colurectal cancer
直肠癌，
which was
这简直
unfathomable. So I will tell you one
难以置信。 所以我要告诉你一
thing that's actually arisen in terms of
件事，那就是关于
like what are some of the clues of these
这些
things that could be happening right? So
可能正在发生的事情，有哪些线索？ 所以
we are talking about climate change and
我们现在讨论的是气候变化以及
all the things that are happening in our
我们环境中正在发生的一切
environment. That's a that's almost too
。 这几乎是一个
big a conversation to have to answer a
太大的话题，不足以回答
question like this. But we I think we
这样的问题。 但我认为我们
cannot afford to ignore the fact that
不能忽视这样一个事实：
the environment, the climate that we
我们所处的环境和气候已经发生了
live in has changed. But there are other
变化。 但还有一些
things that we're beginning to unearth
事情，
that we didn't realize until just within
直到
the last few years. And one of them is
最近几年我们才开始意识到。 其中一个问题是，
microlastics we are ingesting. When I
我们摄入了多少炎症性微弹性蛋白。 在我
was growing up, uh my mom very uh
小时候，呃，我妈妈出于好意，
well-intentioned would store foods in
会把剩菜剩饭储存在
plastic leftovers. Uh, and we'd buy
塑料袋里。 呃，我们会买
foods that came in plastic packages,
用塑料包装的食品，
right? We wouldn't think think second
对吧？ 我们不会
have a second thought about it. A
再三考虑这件事。
plastic cup, styrofoam cup, go to a
塑料杯、泡沫塑料杯，去
picnic, you're eating off of a plastic
野餐，用塑料
plate, right? I mean, these are all
盘子吃饭，对吧？ 我的意思是，这些都是
common uh experiences that we all have
我们
uh in the modern developed world. Well,
在现代发达世界中都会遇到的常见经历。
what if I told you that we now realize
如果我告诉你，我们现在已经意识到，
that the plastic touching food can shed
接触食物的塑料会
the plastic itself as microparticles
以微粒的形式脱落
into the food and then we eat the food
到食物中，然后我们吃掉这些食物，
and okay, we've known this for maybe
而我们可能已经知道这
more than a decade. Maybe there's little
一点十多年了，你会怎么想？ 可能会有一些细小的
plastic particles uh that come off, but
塑料颗粒脱落，但是
you know, hey, there's no harm, right?
你知道，嘿，这没什么害处，对吧？
We we haven't been able to discover it.
我们一直未能找到它。
I I used to say that. Now, just within
我以前也这么说过。 现在，就在
the last few years, we're beginning to
最近几年，我们开始逐渐
pinpoint that number one, it does
意识到，第一点是，
plastics can actually embed themselves
塑料实际上可以嵌入
in our body. We even know where we also
我们的身体中。 我们甚至知道，
know that these plastics uh are
这些塑料
associated with
与
inflammation. That is a big red flag.
炎症有关。 这是一个非常危险的信号。
The claxon alarm should start going off.
警报器应该开始响了。
And third is that the volume of plastics
第三，
that we're consuming is crazy. There was
我们消耗的塑料数量简直太惊人了。
a study that came out recently that
最近有一项研究
showed that in normal autopsies of
表明，在对非
people that didn't die of a brain
脑部疾病死亡的人进行正常尸检时，
problem that when they were doing the
当进行
autopsies and looking for plastic that
尸检并寻找塑料时，
we could find them. And the amount of
我们发现了塑料。
plastic that was found in the average
在普通人脑中发现的塑料含量，大约相当于
a typical plastic picnic spoon just
一个普通塑料野餐勺中的塑料含量，这些塑料均匀
distributed throughout the brain. This
分布在整个大脑中。 这就像
is like a normal this is a person who's
正常情况一样，这个人
died of something else. Wow. Does that
死于其他原因。 哇。 那是不是
mean that you know like you and I are
意味着你知道，就像你我一样，
of plastic in our brain. There's been
我们的大脑里其实只有一勺塑料那么大的塑料？
some people that calculated and this has
有些人计算过，虽然
been the actual calcul math has been
实际的计算结果受到了
challenged but there was an estimate
质疑，但据估计，
if they're not careful about it. And let
如果不注意，有些人每周可能会在食物中摄入相当于一张信用卡大小的塑料。 让
me just tell you where we're finding
我来告诉你我们在哪里发现了
microplastics. And you know I want to
微塑料。 你知道，我想最终
get to the point where we're talking
讨论的是那些
actually turn the ship around. How do we
真正能扭转乾坤的健康食品。 我们如何才能
turn the battleship of of unhealth back
让这艘充满疾病的战舰重回
to health? So, we're back on the course
健康状态？ 所以，我们又回到了
that everybody wants to go to. We want
大家都想去的道路上。 我们
to go to that north. How do we find our
想去北方。 我们如何找到
northstar for health? So, I do want to
健康的指路明灯？ 所以，我确实想
get to that, but let me just say
谈到这一点，但我想先说说
microplastics. We've now found
微塑料的问题。 我们现在已经
microplastics in the brain. As I
在大脑中发现了微塑料。 正如我之前
mentioned to you, we found it in a
跟你提到的，我们是在
bloodstream. A group in Italy actually
血液中发现的。 意大利的一个研究小组正在
looking at men who had narrowing of the
研究患有冠状动脉狭窄的男性患者
corateed artery. That's the blood vessel
。 那是为
feeding the brain from comes from the
大脑供血的血管，它从
heart right to the brain the corateed
心脏直接通向大脑，就是
artery. Oh through the neck through the
冠状动脉。 哦，穿过脖子，穿过
neck. They found that the narrowing that
脖子。 他们发现，
can occur in some men can accumulate
某些男性体内可能出现的血管狭窄会导致
plastic. They can actually find plastic
塑料积聚。 它们确实能找到塑料
particles. There's photographs of the
微粒。 里面有
chunks of plastic the particles
塑料块、塑料颗粒和
fragments of plastic in there. And they
塑料碎片的照片。 他们
followed them over a period of time.
跟踪观察了一段时间。
Those men who had plastic embedded in
那些血管内壁植入塑料的男性，
years later. 400%. Four four-fold. Yeah.
多年后发生致命性心脏病或中风的几率增加了四倍。  400%。 四倍。 是的。
Okay. Now, that's that's not kidding,
好的。 这可不是开玩笑，
right? So, now you're now we're
对吧？ 所以，现在我们
beginning to take notice of this, but
开始注意到这个问题了，但
we're also finding microplastics in
我们也发现母乳中含有微塑料
breast milk. We're finding microplastics
。 我们在睾丸中发现了微塑料
in testicles. We're finding
。 我们
microplastics in human semen.
在人类精液中发现了微塑料。
How does it get there? And urologists
它是怎么到达那里的？ 泌尿科医生
who are doing surgery on the penis are
在进行阴茎手术时，在
they look under the microscope, we never
显微镜下观察人体组织时发现了这种现象，而我们
used to look for this. Now we're looking
以前从未在显微镜下观察过它。 现在我们正在寻找证据
for it, that there's even microplastics
，发现甚至在
in the flesh of the penis. Okay. So if
阴茎的肉体中也存在微塑料。 好的。 所以，如果
notice about microplastics now, it's
现在还有人没有注意到微塑料问题，那么是
time to start thinking about this. So
时候开始思考这个问题了。 所以其中
one of the questions is and I'm not
一个问题是，我并不是
saying that the rise in rate of cancers
说我们现在看到的癌症发病率上升
that we're seeing is due to
是由于
microplastics. What I what I am saying
微塑料造成的。 我的意思
is that we're beginning to wake up to
是，我们开始逐渐意识到这个
the fact. So let's close off on
事实。 那么，我们就结束关于
microplastics. What are the the easy
微塑料的讨论吧。 生活中哪些事情是容易
wins in our lives? Do you think when you
实现的？ 你想到
think about microplastics? Is it just
微塑料时会想到什么？ 是不是只要把
removing anything plastic that I eat
所有塑料餐具都去掉就行了？
from or are there some sort of easy
还是说还有其他简单又
cheap wins? Is it my shampoo? Is it my
便宜的办法？ 是我的洗发水的问题吗？ 是我的
frying pan? Is it a container? Yeah. So,
煎锅吗？ 它是容器吗？ 是的。 所以
I always tell people that the easiest
我总是告诉人们，
way to lower your exposure to
减少接触
microplastics is to throw out your
微塑料的最简单方法就是扔掉
plastic cups, your plastic plates, and
塑料杯、塑料盘子和
your plastic silverware. Mhm. Okay. And
塑料餐具。 嗯。 好的。 可以
get ceramic or glass. Uh that's the best
选择陶瓷或玻璃材质。 嗯，这
way to actually avoid those. And also,
确实是避免这些问题的最佳方法。 另外，
when you're buying food, try to avoid
买食物时，尽量避免购买
food that comes clearly packaged in
明显用塑料包装的食品
plastic. All right. Now, I do want to
。 好的。 现在，我想
point out one thing because right here
指出一点，因为就在
on this table, we are looking at a tray
这张桌子上，我们看到一个
full of beverages and I can already
装满饮料的托盘，我已经
identify the matcha and this looks like
认出了抹茶，这看起来像是
a cup of coffee and we've got English
一杯咖啡，还有英式
breakfast tea. I've done a lot of
早餐茶。 我对茶做了很多
research on tea. All right, but I'm
研究。 好吧，但我
noticing something that green tea, which
注意到绿茶（一种
is universally healthy, the polyphenols
普遍被认为有益健康的饮品）
in green tea lower the risk of
中的多酚可以降低炎症的风险
inflammation. They actually improve your
。 它们实际上可以改善
metabolism, lower your risk of cancer.
新陈代谢，降低患癌风险。
They're heart healthy. Before you take
它们有益心脏健康。 不过在你喝
that sip though, let me tell you, I see
那一口之前，让我告诉你，我看到
a tea bag in
里面有个茶包
there. Okay? And there's different ways
。 好的？ 泡茶的方法有很多种
of brewing your tea. It turns out
。
research from the University of Montreal
蒙特利尔大学的研究
have now shown that um tea bags can shed
表明，茶包会释放
microplastics. So you can have a billion
微塑料。 所以，一个茶包就能
particles of microplastic shed from a
释放出十亿个微塑料颗粒
single teabag. Okay. All right. So I
。 好的。 好的。 所以，我
just changed your mind, right? So look,
改变你的想法了，对吧？ 所以你看，
this is the power of awareness and
这就是意识和理解的力量
understanding. I probably should have
。 我当时或许应该
stopped you. What was you were like, why
阻止你的。 你当时是什么样的人？为什么
didn't you save my life? You let me
不救我的命？ 你让我
drink it first, but I've I
先喝，但我看到
sp as you were doing it. I was like, uh
你喝的时候已经喝完了。 我当时就想，呃呃
uh. All right. But look, there's another
。 好的。 但是你看，那里还有另一款，
there's another one there that's got uh
里面是
lemon ginger tea. This is like an herbal
柠檬姜茶。 这就像一杯花草
tea. That's fine. Listen, um I I would
茶。 没关系。 听着，嗯，我还想
also tell you with flavored
告诉你，喝调味
teas, just be cautious. Like always
茶的时候要小心。 像往常一样，要
check anything that's been machined to
检查任何经过机械加工、
be a little bit more than nature. Tea
比自然状态略好一些的东西。
bags are supposed to be paper, right?
茶包应该是纸质的，对吧？
Well, in order to prevent the paper from
为了防止茶包纸
ripping, the the manufacturers of the
撕裂，
tea bag spray it with a small amount of
茶包生产商会在上面喷洒少量
plastic to have it hang together better.
塑料，使其更好地保持形状。
And that's the plastic that comes off.
这就是要取下来的塑料。
But what about the lemon and ginger in
但是这款柠檬姜茶里的柠檬和生姜呢
this lemon ginger tea? That that sounds
？ 听起来是不是
so appealing and calming, right? And and
很吸引人，让人感到平静？ 而且，
something that most people would find
大多数人都会觉得它是一种
nice as an herbal tea. Well, listen,
不错的草药茶。 听着，
you're you're relying on a factory to
你得指望工厂能
actually put that lemon flavor, ginger
真正做出那种柠檬味、
ginger flavor. Is it real lemon or is it
姜味。 这是真柠檬还是
real ginger? always look at the
真姜？ 一定要查看
ingredient label to know what's in there
配料表，了解里面有什么，
or just buy your own tea and squeeze
或者干脆自己买茶叶，
your own lemon and and add your own
自己挤柠檬汁，自己加
piece of ginger. These are ways to
一块姜。 这些方法
actually kind of avoid the uh potential
实际上可以避免
exposures to toxins that come from
接触到
ultrarocessed food. So all this
超加工食品中可能产生的毒素。 所以，所有
conversation about, you know, avoid
关于避免食用
ultra ultrarocessed foods and watch out
超加工食品，以及注意
for all those harmful things, you know,
各种有害物质的讨论，
it's actually quite easy to dodge them
其实很容易就能避开它们，
if you just have in your mindset that
只要你抱着自己
you're just going to make it yourself.
动手做的心态就行了。
And it's uh absolutely easy. Now, I will
而且这真的很容易。 现在，我将为
tell you in something interesting about
大家讲一些关于
English breakfast tea. We did research
英式早餐茶的有趣故事。 我们
at the Androgenesis Foundation, the
在我考察过的非营利组织——雄激素基金会——进行了研究，
nonprofit I I looked at, to look at um
研究了
different types of teas, different types
不同类型的茶，不同类型的
of green tea, Japanese tea, Chinese
绿茶、日本茶、中国
jasmine tea, uh English tea. And we were
茉莉花茶、英国茶。 我们
always assuming, again, this is the
一直认为，这就是
power of food as medicine research. We
食物作为药物研究的力量。 我们
were always assuming that the green tea
一直都认为绿茶
is going to be the best. I'd always
是最好的。 我一直
heard that Japanese green tea is going
听说日本绿茶是最好的
to be like the ultra best. And what we
。 我们
found was that English tea, specifically
发现，英国茶，特别是
Earl Grey tea, actually was the most
伯爵茶，
potent when it actually supported your
在支持
blood vessels, your body's defense
血管生成、维持身体血液
circulation healthy. Wow, what a
循环健康方面，实际上效果最强。 哇，真是个
surprise that is. And this spoke to me
惊喜！ 这让我意识到
about the fact that we can't make
我们不能妄下断言
assumptions. We need to look at facts.
。 我们需要看事实。
We need to look at data. And so I'm a
我们需要查看数据。 所以我是
big fan of Earl Gray. Now, now what
伯爵茶的忠实粉丝。 那么，究竟是什么原因
could what what might make Earl Gray
导致
give Earl Grey a superpower? Well, this
伯爵茶拥有了超能力呢？ 嗯，
is where knowing a little bit about what
了解一些
you're eating is actually useful because
你吃的东西其实很有用，因为
Earl Grey is a fermented is a is a black
伯爵茶是一种发酵的
tea. It's got bergamut in it and
红茶。 里面含有佛手柑，
bergamut is a kind of a citrus. So,
佛手柑是一种柑橘类水果。 所以，
maybe it's combining those uh
或许正是这些
ingredients that actually provides the
成分的组合才真正赋予了它
superpower. But I do see matcha on this
超能力。 但我确实在这个托盘上看到了抹茶
uh uh tray. I want to tell you about
。 我想跟你们说说
matcha because it is a matcha is truly a
抹茶，因为抹茶是一种真正富含
superenriched polyphenol enriched tea. A
多酚的超级茶。
lot of people don't realize it. There's
很多人都没意识到这一点。
no tea bag in it. So don't worry. So a
里面没有茶包。 所以别担心。 所以
lot of people think about matcha uh as
很多人认为抹茶只是
just another green tea, but it's not
另一种绿茶，但它并不是
another green tea. It is made with green
另一种绿茶。 它是用绿茶叶制成的
tea leaves, the same kind of green tea
，
leaves, but uh as you would find in any
就是那种你在普通绿茶里能找到的
green tea. However, it's what's the
绿茶叶。 然而，
composition of matcha? Matcha is green
抹茶的成分是什么呢？ 抹茶是
tea that is before it's ready for
绿茶在成熟
harvest is grown under a shade that
采摘前，在遮荫下生长，这会
chemical structure a little bit. So,
稍微改变其天然化学结构。 所以，
it's got a lot of potency to it. And
它效力很强。
what happens with matcha is they take
抹茶的制作方法是，将
leaf, they take out the stem of the
茶叶取出，去除
green of the of the green tea leaf and
绿茶的茎部，然后将
they ground up the actual leaf into a
剩下的茶叶磨成
powder. Now, what's in that green tea
粉末。 那么，这片绿
leaf? You've got not just some of the
茶叶里到底有什么成分呢？
cup, whether you're using a tea bag or
无论你用的是茶包还是
or loose leaf tea, you are getting all
散装茶叶，你得到的不仅仅是浸泡在茶杯中的部分多酚，而是所有
the polyphenols suspended in that. So
悬浮在其中的多酚。 所以
now you get 100% polyphenol, okay, in
现在抹茶中含有100%的多酚，好的
matcha. So go ahead. You're go ahead do
。 那你继续吧。 你去做吧。
it. That one's good. All right. Okay.
那个不错。 好的。 好的。
For matcha and because you're getting
抹茶因为是用
the tea leaf ground to it, you're also
茶叶磨成的粉末冲泡的，所以还能
getting your dietary fiber. The dietary
摄入膳食纤维。 膳食
fiber is good for your gut health, your
纤维对肠道健康、
microbiome, good for uh your metabolism,
微生物群有益，对新陈代谢有益，
good for lowering inflammation. And the
对降低炎症有益。
polyphenols found in green tea have also
绿茶中含有的多酚类物质，抹茶中的多酚类物质，
found in the lab to kill breast cancer
在实验室中也被发现能够杀死乳腺癌
stem cells. What's a breast cancer stem
干细胞。 什么是乳腺癌干
cell? What's a stem cell? Cancer stem
细胞？ 什么是干细胞？ 癌症干
cell. Well, look, stem cells are these
细胞。 你看，干细胞就是这些
renewable cells. All right? And um
可再生细胞。 好的？
cancers contain stem cells that help the
癌症中含有干细胞，这些干细胞会帮助
cancers come back, right? If you got
癌症复发，对吧？ 如果得了
cancer, you get it treated. One the one
癌症，就要接受治疗。
thing you don't want it to do is to come
你最不希望它发生的一件事就是
back. So um and by the way, other foods
回来。 顺便一提，其他食物
can also do kill cancer stem cells.
也能杀死癌干细胞。
Purple potatoes uh that you might have
你可能
seen in the market. They're um kind of
在市场上见过的那种紫色土豆。 它们
purpley looking on the outside. Slice it
外表看起来有点紫紫色。 切开后
open, dark purple on the inside. All
，里面是深紫色。
right. Turns out that those purple
好的。 原来，那些紫色
potatoes have something called
土豆含有一种叫做
anthocyanins.
花青素的物质。
lab, okay, at Penn State University and
宾夕法尼亚州立大学的实验室已经对紫薯进行了研究，结果
been shown to kill colon cancer stem
表明紫薯可以杀死
cells which contribute to the colon
导致
cancer coming back. So, full disclaimer,
结肠癌复发的结肠癌干细胞。 所以，先声明一下，
matcher company a couple of years ago.
几年前我向一家配对公司投入了巨额资金——七位数。
And if you look at the search trend data
如果你查看一下
on the subject of ma matcher, I don't
关于“ma matcher”这个主题的搜索趋势数据，我不
know if you've seen this, but that's
知道你是否已经看过，但
I'll throw it up on the screen for
我会把它显示在屏幕上，给
anyone that's watching on video, but you
所有观看视频的人看，你
can see how it's just come out of
可以看到它是如何突然出现的
nowhere. It seems it's exploded. And
。 好像爆炸了。
when you say that matcha cells have an
当你说抹茶细胞
impact on breast cancer cells, what does
对乳腺癌细胞有影响时，
that mean in reality? Does it? Because
这在现实中意味着什么？ 是吗？ 因为
obviously the the the conclusion one
很显然，人们
might jump to is that if you drink
可能会得出这样的结论：喝
matcha, you're lowering your risk of
抹茶可以降低患
breast cancer, but that's not
乳腺癌的风险，但这
necessarily what you're saying. What
不一定是你想表达的意思。
what I what I am saying is that drinking
我的意思是，饮用
green tea in its most healthful form,
最健康的绿茶可以
okay, um raises your body's health
提高身体的健康
defense systems. And by having better
防御系统。 拥有更好的
health defense systems, better immunity,
健康防御系统、更好的免疫力、
better control of your blood vessels,
更好的血管控制、
better control over your DNA and those
更好的DNA和
mutations, and if you can actually kill
突变控制，如果你还能杀死
some of those stem cells, cancer stem
一些干细胞，也就是癌症干
cells, that's going to be in your favor
细胞，那对你
as well, that is overall going to
也是有利的，总体而言，这将
actually lower your risk of cancer. And
降低你患癌症的风险。
so I think that, and by the way, the
所以我觉得，顺便说一句，
other thing that green tea and matcha
绿茶和抹茶的另一个作用
can actually do is improve your
是改善
metabolism. It's it's really pretty much
新陈代谢。 其实一切都挺
all good. I my great uncle by the way
好的。 顺便一提，我的叔祖父
lived to 104 years old, vital, intact,
活到了 104 岁，身体健康，精神矍铄，而且
uh independent. He told me that he
独立生活。 他告诉我，他之所以
attributed his longevity and his
长寿且
vitality to the fact that he lived at
精力充沛，是因为他住在山
the base of a mountain that grew tea.
脚下，而山上长满了茶叶。
That every morning he got up and he
每天早上他都会起床，然后
walked up. He walked up stone steps, a
走上去。 他走上石阶，沿着
stone path to a tea garden and he had
石径来到茶园，那里有
freshly picked tea. It's all organically
新鲜采摘的茶叶。 全部都是有机
grown and everything. And he and he
种植的。 他和他一整天都在
drank tea all day long. He probably had
喝茶。 他可能
10 cups of green tea a day. And this has
一天要喝10杯绿茶。 这就是
been his whole life. He sat with his uh
他的一生。 他和他的几个关系很
uh close friends who are also very
亲密的朋友坐在一起，这些朋友也都非常
vibrant and and elderly. Um social
有活力，而且年纪都比较大了。 嗯，社交
connection. All right. Watch the
联系。 好的。 观看
sunrise. It's very calming. Do you drink
日出。 它让人感到非常平静。 你喝吗
it? Absolutely. Um I've got to just
？ 绝对地。 嗯，我得再往上翻翻
going up the the thread again a little
帖子
bit. You mentioned the word colurectal.
。 你提到了结肠直肠这个词。
Where is the colarctyl? All right. So,
柱状体在哪里？ 好的。 所以，
we have a little um model here cuz I'm
我们这里有一个小模型，因为我
asking this because I'm wondering why
问这个问题是因为我想知道为什么
that type of cancer is increasing. So,
这种类型的癌症病例在增加。 那么，这其中有什么
is there is there a particular reason
特殊原因吗
why? Well, okay. So, let's do a quick uh
？ 好吧。 那么，让我们为播客主播们快速上一堂
medical school uh course crash course
医学院速成课程吧
podcasters.
。
Um the the gut, we talk about gut
嗯，说到肠道，我们来谈谈肠道
health. Most people think of the gut as
健康。 大多数人认为肠道是
sort of lower down in your belly or
指腹部下方，或者
maybe even just your stomach. But the
甚至只是胃部。 但
gut actually starts in your mouth and it
实际上，肠道是从你的口腔开始，向下延伸
runs down down down about 40 feet worth
约 40 英尺，包括
of stuff organs u your esophagus, your
你的食道、
stomach, your small intestines, your
胃、小肠和
large intestines. By the way, these
大肠等器官。 顺便说一下，这些
squigglies are your small intestines.
弯曲的东西是你的小肠。
All right. This blue is your large
好的。 这部分蓝色是你的
intestines. This is like a it's shaped
大肠。 它的形状
like a horseshoe. It's big thick tube
像个马蹄铁。 它是一根粗大的管子，起到
that that's kind of framing your small
支撑
intestines. And then it goes down the
小肠的作用。 然后它就顺着
poop shoot, the rectal, and the anus.
排便道、直肠和肛门流下去了。
That's the end of your gut. All right?
你的肠子就到此为止了。 好的？
So, the colon is really the large uh
所以，结肠实际上是
framing thick part of the gut. It's near
肠道中较大较厚的支撑部分。 已经接近
the very end. All right? So, all this
尾声了。 好的？ 所以，所有这些
squiggly small intestines winds up here
蜿蜒曲折的小肠最终都汇聚到这里，也就是
uh at the beginning of the colon. The
结肠的起始端。
colon goes up. It's called the ascending
结肠向上移动。 它被称为升
colon. And then it makes a sharp angled
结肠。 然后它突然
turn right across your belly. Kind of
急转弯，正好横穿你的腹部。 就像
like a belt right across your belly.
一条腰带横跨在你的肚子上。
This is colon here and then it goes to
这是结肠，然后它通向
the descending colon. Take the elevator
降结肠。 乘电梯往下走
down down down down down. You see the
。 你会看到
blue down going down and then it kind of
蓝色的管子向下移动，然后
takes a little jog at the very end and
在最后稍微拐了个弯，
goes down into your rectum and your
进入你的直肠和
anus. Okay. Right. So the blue thing is
肛门。 好的。 正确的。 所以，蓝色的那部分是
my colon. So this is where cancer
我的结肠。 所以，这就是
incidence is rising in young people. So
年轻人癌症发病率上升的原因。 所以
you're talking about the rising
你是在谈论
incidence of colctal cancer. That could
结肠癌发病率上升的问题。 那可能
be a cancer that's typically uh either
是癌症，通常
on the right side of the colon either
位于结肠右侧，或者向上延伸，就像
elevator. Yeah. Or down the elevator. On
电梯一样。 是的。 或者乘电梯下去。 在
the right side of the left side. Okay.
左侧的右侧。 好的。
Okay. It turns out that we've known for
好的。 事实证明，我们早就知道
a long time that unhealthy diets are
不健康的饮食习惯与
linked to a higher risk of colorectal
更高的结直肠癌风险有关，
cancer specifically processed meats. So
尤其是加工肉类。 所以
the World Health Organization contains
世界卫生组织
considers processed meats, salami,
认为加工肉类、萨拉米香肠、
bologna, ultrarocessed, you know, kind
博洛尼亚香肠、超加工肉类，你知道，就是那种
of deli meats, delicates, meat you find
熟食肉类、精致食品，你
in delicates. All right. Um th those
在精致食品里能找到的肉类。 好的。 嗯，这些物质
would be uh considered uh
会被认为是
carcinogens and and they're they're they
致癌物，而且它们与
risk of bowel cancers. Now, why would
肠癌风险增加密切相关。 为什么会这样呢
that be? Well, it turns out that think
？ 仔细想想，事实的确如此
about it. If you're eating a ton of
。 如果你吃很多
meat, all right, you're actually
肉，好吧，你实际上是在让你的
exposing the gut to a lot of those
肠道接触到很多
processed meat carcinogens that when it
加工肉类中的致癌物，这些致癌物会
sits around in your colon, not one, not
在你的结肠里停留一段时间。偶尔吃一次，比如
not once in a while, go to the ball
去
game, have a hot dog, enjoy yourself,
看球赛，吃个热狗，好好享受一下，
but if you eat it day in and day out,
但如果你日复一日地吃，
you're giving a lot of exposure uh to
你的肠道就会大量接触到这些致癌物
your gut. This term
。
angiogenesis, you talked about the link
你刚才谈到了血管生成这个术语，以及它与
that that has to cancer. Angioenesis
癌症的联系。
from my um novice understanding is how
根据我这个外行的理解，血管生成是指
the blood cells provide blood to
血细胞如何为
different parts of our body. Right? And
我们身体的不同部位提供血液。 正确的？ 而
in the case of cancer there's
癌症的情况是
this the angioenesis system is making a
血管生成系统出现了
mistake. Is that a simplified version of
错误。 这是简化版吗
it? Yeah. So angioenesis which is the
？ 是的。 所以，
field I studied study you break it down
我研究的领域是血管生成，你可以把它分解成
angio blood blood vessel genesis how the
血管生成的基本组成部分，也就是
body grows and maintains them so
身体如何生长和维持血管。血管生成
androgenesis is how our body grows and
是指我们身体如何生长和
maintains our circulation a lot of
维持循环系统。很多
people don't know this but our
人不知道这一点，但
circulation is one of our body's health
循环系统是我们身体的健康
defense systems and it's so extensive
防御系统之一，它非常庞大，
that in a typical adult there are 60,000
一个典型的成年人体内有
miles worth of blood vessels packed
长达 60,000 英里的血管
inside our body. These are the highways
。 这些是为人体
and byways that deliver blood to every
各个
organ and tissue. But that means that
器官和组织输送血液的通道。 但这也就意味着，
they also deliver the air we breathe,
它们也输送着我们呼吸的空气、
the oxygen we're breathing in, and the
我们吸入的氧气以及
nutrients that we're eating. So we eat
我们摄入的营养物质。 所以我们吃好
good things, they're going into our
东西，它们就会进入我们的
bloodstream, and our blood vessels, our
血液和血管，我们的
androgenesis systems develing to every
雄激素生成系统就会发育到
cell in the body. Now you eat something
身体的每一个细胞。 同样地，如果你吃了不
bad similarly or you breathe something
干净的东西，或者吸入了不
in bad, similarly those blood vessels
干净的东西，血管
are delivering something negative. Now
也会输送有害物质。
inside the blood vessels um is a lining.
血管内部有一层内膜。
It's called a the lining is like a clear
它被称为内皮层，内皮层就像
like a plastic wrap inside the blood
血管内壁上一层透明的塑料薄膜
vessel called the endothelial layer.
。
That's like a layer of ice like on an
这就像
ice skating rig to ensure that
冰上滑冰架上的一层冰，确保
everything in the blood vessels are
血管内的血液
flowing smoothly without getting caught
流动顺畅，不会卡
on the walls. So when you have
在血管壁上。 所以，当你患有
cardiovascular disease, too much uh uh
心血管疾病时，摄入过多的
too much salt to hypertension. When you
盐会导致高血压。 当你
have diabetes where you're actually
患有糖尿病时，
wearing down the lining of the blood
血管内壁会逐渐磨损
vessels, endothelial layers being
，内皮层也会受到
damaged. It's like um damaging the
损伤。 这就好比……破坏
lining of your angioenesis defense
血管生成防御系统的内膜会
system has really deadly consequences
造成非常致命的后果，
because it's like scraping up the ice on
因为这就像刮掉
an ice skating rink. You know, uh if you
溜冰场上的冰层一样。 你知道，如果
rink, after a while it's unskatable,
溜冰场上有很多滑冰者，过一段时间后就没法滑冰了，
right? You can't get on it. And what
对吧？ 你上不去。 然后，
elements in your blood get caught along
血液中的某些成分就会滞留在血管
the walls and they build up and that's
壁上，不断积聚，这就是
actually how blood vessels narrow up. So
血管变窄的真正原因。 所以，
that's one of the areas of of of so
雄
androgenesis actually is intended to
激素生成实际上是为了向
tissues that need it for to maintain
需要氧气和营养物质的组织输送氧气和营养，以维持
your health. But because it's so
你的健康。 但正因为它
critical, it's also very very carefully
至关重要，所以也受到非常非常严格的
controlled so you don't have blood
控制，以防止
vessels growing where they should not be
血管在不应该生长的地方生长
growing. like in your joints, in your
。 例如关节、
eyes, or of course to cancers. You don't
眼睛，当然还有癌症。 你
definitely don't want to be feeding
绝对不想通过向
cancers by delivering oxygen or
癌细胞输送氧气或
nutrients to them. I've got this graph
营养物质来滋养它们。 我有一张图表，
which shows different things that cause
显示了导致血管生成
more or less
增多或减少的不同因素
angiogenesis. If you've seen this graph,
。 如果你已经看过这张图了，
but okay. So, you are showing a graph
那好吧。 所以，你展示的这张图表是
that I I generated my my organization
我和我的组织
generated. And this is actually you're
生成的。 实际上，你现在
looking at the experiment that got me
看到的这个实验让我开始
into food as medicine. Let me explain to
关注食物作为药物这一概念。 让我来给
you the experiment. Um I'll just put
你解释一下这个实验。 嗯，我就把它
I'll put it over here. So um so we were
放在这里吧。 所以，我们曾经
studying at one
研究过
point drugs and we're trying to discover
药物，并且试图发现
drugs that could be developed as cancer
可以开发成癌症
treatments. So what we're looking for
治疗药物的药物。 所以我们正在寻找
are drugs that could cut off the blood
能够切断
supply to tumors. So we were screening
肿瘤血液供应的药物。 所以，我们当时正在筛选
uh lots of chemicals that biotech
生物技术
companies were developing and inventing
公司和教授们正在研发和发明的许多化学物质，然后
and professors were inventing and said
问他们：“
hey can you take a look to see if this
嘿，你们能不能看看这是否有可能
could be a worthwhile drug that could
成为一种有价值的药物，可以
cut off the blood supply to a tumor as a
切断肿瘤的血液供应，从而
cancer treatment. All right and at the
治疗癌症？” 好吧，
time there were no such treatments. So
当时还没有这种治疗方法。 所以
it was all discovery like this was you
这一切都是发现，你
know like the like the golden age of
知道，这就像是雄
discovery when it came to androgenesis.
激素生成领域的发现黄金时代。
We were testing oh my gosh this thing
我们当时在测试，天哪，这东西
could really stop blood vessels. Could
真的能堵塞血管。
we develop this into our cancer
我们能否将其应用于癌症
treatment? Ultimately, yes. The answer
治疗？ 最终，答案是肯定的。 答案
was yes. But we were looking for them.
是肯定的。 但我们一直在寻找他们。
And we would f and so we developed a
于是我们开发了一种
system where we could add a substance
系统，可以将某种物质添加
into a laboratory test system to see if
到实验室测试系统中，看看
blood vessels would grow or shrink. And
血管是会生长还是收缩。
so here on this graph, you can see at
所以在这张图表上，你可以看到最
the very top a very long bar of blood
顶端有一条很长的血管
vessels growing. That's normal, healthy
条在生长。 这是正常的、健康的
blood vessels growing out as long as
血管向外生长的过程
they can. And then what we would do is
。 然后我们会
we would throw drugs into it and we
往里面加入药物，
would see if we could actually shrink
看看能不能真的把
them up. And so some of the uh shorter
它们缩小。 所以有些较短的
bars uh uh are uh cancer drugs. Uh you
条形码是抗癌药物。 呃，你
can see them uh in this color in blue.
可以看到它们，呃，是蓝色的。
Not surprisingly, some of the cancer
不出所料，一些抗癌
drugs were making the blood vessels
药物会使血管
smaller. Hey, this could be a good
收缩。 嘿，这可能是一种不错的
candidate drug. And we were also testing
候选药物。 我们当时也在测试
other uh drugs that were available, not
其他一些可用的药物，这些药物虽然不是
used for cancer to see if they would
用于治疗癌症的，但看看它们是否
work. Sure, we discovered some of those,
有效。 当然，我们也发现了一些
too. But I did something a little bit
。 但我做了一些有点
subversive and as you know, you know, if
颠覆性的事情，你知道，如果
you want to be disruptive, you got to
你想搞破坏，有时候你必须先
sometimes um disrupt yourself in order
搞破坏自己
to be able to do this. So this is our
才能做到这一点。 这就是
experiment that we were doing at the
我们在
Androenesis Foundation. We decided to
雄激素基金会进行的实验。 我们决定
disrupt ourselves. So we said, we have a
自我颠覆。 所以我们说，我们有
whole system of drugs to test. Let's
一整套药物系统需要测试。 让我们
remove half of them and let's swap them
去掉其中一半，并
out with powders that came from
用食品粉末代替它们
food. All right? Just to see what would
。 好的？ 只是想看看会
happen. And when we actually tested
发生什么。 当我们
foods in the same system used to develop
用开发药物的同一系统来测试食物时
drugs, food as medicine, tested in the
，也就是用同样的系统来测试食物作为药物时
developed, we found what you see on this
，我们发现了你在这张
bar chart in red, we actually found that
红色柱状图中看到的情况，我们发现
dietary factors, stuff that's found in
饮食因素，也就是食物中的某些物质
food, could actually cut down the blood
，实际上可以减少为癌细胞提供养分的血液
supply that would be growing to feed a
供应
cancer. In other words, there's
。 换句话说，有些
anti-angioenic foods. You can see the
食物具有抗血管生成作用。 你可以看到
green tea. You could see the onions and
绿茶。 你可以看到洋葱、
garlics and red grapes and strawberries.
大蒜、红葡萄和草莓。
Um, it was really an eye openener to me
嗯，
for when I saw these results. It made my
看到这些结果，我真的大开眼界。 我惊得
jaw drop and I said, "My god, foods have
目瞪口呆，说道：“我的天哪，食物竟然和
potency just like drugs." I was I was a
药物一样有药效。” 我以前是个
skeptic. All right. And I and it just
怀疑论者。 好的。 这让
made me realize like this is something
我意识到，这是
that I had to pursue. This was an area
我必须追求的事情。 这是我必须深入研究的一个领域
into. A drug takes a decade and a
。 一种药物从零开始研发到最终应用于患者，可能需要十年时间和数
billion or more dollars to be able to
十亿美元甚至更多，
a patient and then not everyone who
而且并非所有
needs a treatment can actually get the
需要治疗的人都能真正获得这种
drug. But a food has immediiacy. If you
药物。 但食物具有即时性。 如果你
discover something amazing about a food,
发现某种食物具有神奇的功效，
whether it's matcha, whether it's purple
无论是抹茶、紫
potatoes, whether it's a strawberry,
薯还是草莓，
that could that that that immediacy
那么这种功效就可以在
could be used beneficially without
不产生毒性的情况下得到有益的利用
toxicity. All right? Uh and affordably.
。 好的？ 而且价格实惠。
And so I just saw this as this was this
所以，我当时就把这件事
experiment is what brought me into the
看作是把我带入“
realm of food is medicine. So I'm going
食物即药物”领域的契机。 所以我要
to ask some stupid questions here. So on
问一些愚蠢的问题。 所以在
here I can see that for example soy
这里我可以看到，例如大豆
extract causes less angiogenesis which
提取物会导致血管生成减少，
what I understand is the the growth of
我理解的血管生成是指
these blood vessels. But does that mean
这些血管的生长。 但这是否意味着，
that if I have lots of soy extract or
如果我摄入大量大豆提取物、朝鲜蓟、
arichoke or parsley or berries that it's
欧芹或浆果，就会
going to cause other parts of my body
导致我身体其他部位
not to grow blood cells? So this is the
无法生成血细胞？ 这是一个
great question that let let me kind of
很好的问题，让我换个方式
reframe the question as you're asking
重新表述一下你提出的问题
it. If uh experiments are able to show
。 如果实验能够证明
that certain foods can uh prevent blood
某些食物可以阻止
vessels from growing, will that actually
血管生长，这是否真的会
cause a problem with your body's health
损害人体的健康
defenses to keep blood vessels from
防御机制，使其无法阻止血管
growing in healthy tissues? Yeah. All
在健康组织中生长？ 是的。
right. Answer is no. And here's why. as
好的。 答案是否定的。 原因如下。 作为
a health defense system. Our
健康防御系统。 我们的
androgenesis system is completely
雄激素生成系统经过精心
designed to yoke in the right number of
设计，能够连接适量的
blood vessels to give just amount just
血管，从而提供适量的
the right amount of blood flow. Not too
血液流动。 不多
much, not too little. I call it the
不少，恰到好处。 我称之为“
Goldilocks zone. You know, Goldilocks a
黄金地带”。 你知道，《金发姑娘和三只熊》是个
fairy tale. Um, you know, the bears were
童话故事。 嗯，你知道，那些熊是
home invaders. They broke into the house
闯入民宅的。 他们闯入房子，
and they were looking for chairs and
寻找椅子、
porridge and beds. Not too hot, not too
粥和床。 不冷不
cold, but just right. All of our health
热，刚刚好。 我们所有的健康
defenses, including the androgenesis
防御机制，包括雄激素生成
health defense, is hardwired to keep the
健康防御机制，都是为了让身体保持最佳状态而设定的
body just right. So, what that means is
。 这意味着，
that eating foods like artichokes or
食用朝鲜蓟、
strawberries or soy can actually help
草莓或大豆等食物实际上可以帮助
your body prevent extra blood vessels
你的身体防止额外的血管
from growing towards cancer, for
向癌症
example, and and other diseased tissues,
和其他病变组织生长，
but it will not override the body's
但它不会取代身体将
natural ability to get the right amount
适量
of blood vessels to the right tissue. So
血管输送到正确组织的自然能力。 所以
you don't have to worry about starving
你不用担心
your healthy tissues. You're just uh
健康组织会缺乏营养。 你只是把
tissue. I can I call it like a
组织中病变的血管切断而已。 我可以把它比作
landscaper on a golf course that that
高尔夫球场上的园艺师，他会
breaks out the lawn mower to mow that uh
拿出割草机来修剪
the golf course so it's got a perfect
球场，使草坪保持完美的
level um of the lawn. You're not going
平整度。 你不可能真的
in on in a country club. You're going to
在乡村俱乐部里剃出一块秃顶吧。 你会
get just the right amount. Similarly,
得到恰到好处的数量。 同样地，
and um we're not talking about this
嗯，我们说的不是这张
graph. There's another graph that can
图。 还有一张图表可以
actually show foods that you can eat
显示哪些食物
that can grow blood vessels, healthy
可以促进血管生长，在
blood vessels where you want them. And
你想要的地方促进健康血管的生长。 事实
it turns out things like fruit peel uh
证明，像水果皮之类的东西
uh can actually do that. And barley can
确实能做到这一点。 而且大麦还能促进
grow new blood vessels. And dark
新血管的生长。 黑
chocolate can actually help to support
巧克力实际上也有助于保护
blood vessels as well. And some of these
血管。 有些
things can also work on both sides of
因素也可以同时适用于等式的两边
the equation. They can prune away the
。 它们可以修剪掉多余的
bad extra blood vessels and it can grow
坏血管，并在
them whenever you need them. So your
需要时重新长出新的血管。 所以你的
body is sort of like the gardener
身体就像一位技艺
extraordinaire. and knows exactly how to
超群的园丁。 而且他非常清楚如何进行
actually tend. You give them the right
实际的照料。 你给他们合适的
ingredients, they know exactly where to
原料，他们就知道在哪里
put the grass seed, and they know
播种草籽，也知道在
exactly where to mow the lawn. Have you
哪里修剪草坪。 你
ever had cancer in your family? Yes. Um,
家有癌症病史吗？ 是的。 嗯，
cancer's touched my family like it has
癌症对我的家庭的影响，就像
for most people. Um, I had two uncles
对大多数人的影响一样。 嗯，我有两个叔叔，
uh years ago that passed away. One
几年前去世了。 其中一人
passed away from colon cancer, one
死于结肠癌，一人
passed away from liver cancer. And, you
死于肝癌。 你
know, I was a doctor at the time. And so
知道，我当时是一名医生。 所以
I felt so uh
我感到非常
helpless uh because as a doctor I could
无助，因为作为一名医生，我可以
I could diagnose I could lay hands on I
诊断，我可以触摸，我
could feel the hard liver I could feel
可以感觉到坚硬的肝脏，我可以感觉到
the masses and I felt at the time
肿块，但当时我感到很
helpless even though I was doing the
无助，即使我一直在做
research cancer research and finding
癌症研究，寻找
future paths I felt like this was we
未来的治疗方向，我感觉我们还
we're we're not there yet and we can't I
没有达到目标，我们做不到，我
couldn't help him. I felt I felt
帮不了他。 我感到自己
powerless. Fast
无能为力。
forward, we're now at a point where
时至今日，我们
we're beginning to see the light at the
终于看到了
end of the tunnel. And my mother, when
隧道尽头的曙光。 我的母亲，也就是
my mother had cancer, so my uncle's
我叔叔的妹妹，得了癌症，她最终被
sister, my mother, wound up having
诊断出患有
endometrial cancer, she was 80 years
子宫内膜癌，当时她 80
old. one day um had some bleeding, went
岁。 有一天，她突然出血，去
to the hospital, found a mass, she had a
了医院，发现子宫里​​有个肿块，于是做了
hyerectomy to remove her uterus and
子宫切除术，切除了子宫和
ovaries, and they found in there an
卵巢，结果发现里面有
endometrial cancer. That's a cancer, the
子宫内膜癌。 那是癌症，是
lining of the uterus. The surgery and a
子宫内膜癌。 手术加上
little bit of radiation was supposed to
少量放射治疗本应能
take care of it.
解决这个问题。
Unfortunately, in her case, those little
不幸的是，在她身上，那些微小的
cancer stem cells and it was microscopic
癌干细胞和肉眼看不见的
cancers that were present took off,
癌细胞
raced off in her 80-year-old body, which
在她80岁的身体里迅速扩散，
you know, weaker immune system when
你知道，80岁的时候免疫系统比较弱。
you're 80. Uh, and within a few months
嗯，
after successfully recovering from the
手术后几个月，她虽然成功康复，但
everywhere. All right? And her
全身都出现了四期癌症。 好的？ 她的
oncologist told me, uh, Dr. Lee, you
肿瘤科医生告诉我：“李医生，你
know, you're a doctor as well. You know,
知道，你也是一名医生。” 你知道，
this is serious and this is pretty much
情况很严重，基本上已经结束了
the time of game over. And
。
now times have changed. Science had
如今时代变了。 科学取得了
advanced. Progress has advanced. At that
进步。 进展顺利。 当时
time when my mother was diagnosed with
我母亲被诊断出患有
stage 4 cancer,
四期癌症，而
immunotherapy, the latest and greatest,
免疫疗法，
I think advancement in cancer treatment
我认为是癌症治疗领域最新、最好的疗法，
had just broken through and become
刚刚取得突破并被
approved. Imunotherapy is not
批准。 免疫疗法不是
chemotherapy. It doesn't actually poison
化疗。 它实际上并不会杀死
the cancer. Imunotherapy is a medicine
癌细胞。 免疫疗法是一种给
that you give a cancer patient that
癌症患者服用的药物，可以
wakes up your own immune system. Whether
唤醒患者自身的免疫系统。 无论
you're a young person or an old person,
你是年轻人还是老年人，
it can wake up your immune system. All
它都能唤醒你的免疫系统。
right? And my mother had imunotherapy.
好的？ 我母亲接受了免疫疗法。
She was one of the early patients that
她是最早
got imunotherapy. And her own
接受免疫疗法的患者之一。 她自己
80-year-old immune system woke up like a
80岁高龄的免疫系统就像
super like an army of super soldiers and
超级战士一样苏醒过来，像一支超级士兵大军一样向
went after that cancer. Now, we
癌症发起攻击。 现在，我们
completely adjusted her diet to so that
完全调整了她的饮食，以便
her body between treatments would be as
她在治疗间隙身体
strong as possible. Shields raised as
尽可能保持强壮。 正如
we've been talking about. And we gave
我们刚才所说的那样，举起了盾牌。 我们还给
her a little bit of radiation to to to
她做了少量放射治疗，以
help the uh the her immune system spot
帮助她的免疫系统发现
the cancer. Guess what
癌细胞。 你猜
happened? Three treatments of
发生了什么？ 免疫疗法共进行三次
imunotherapy, three three weeks apart.
，每次间隔三周。
So, time zero is the first treatment.
因此，时间零点是第一次治疗。
Three weeks later, the next treatment.
三周后，进行下一次治疗。
Three weeks after that, the next
三周后进行下一次
treatment. All right. So, we're talking
治疗。 好的。 所以，我们说的是
about like total nine weeks of three
总共九周，三次
treatments. All right. Of these three
疗程。 好的。 在这三种
treatments, we scanned her stage four,
治疗方案中，我们扫描显示她的病情为第四期，然后又降到
zero, and she never had chemotherapy.
零期，而且她从未接受过化疗。
Now, chemotherapy can be helpful too
现在，化疗也可以
with imunotherapy, but this was where I
与免疫疗法结合使用，但正是
saw firsthand close up in my own family,
在我自己的家庭中，我亲眼目睹了
the ability to harness your body's own
利用人体自身
health defenses in a way that I couldn't
健康防御机制的能力，而这是我在 15 年前无法
do for my
为我的
uncle 15 years ago before. And we lost
叔叔做到的。 我们失去了
them. And we were to save my mom. And I
他们。 我们的任务是救我妈妈。 我
can tell you, I literally had dinner
可以告诉你，就在
with my mom two days ago, and she's 90,
两天前，我还和我妈妈一起吃了顿饭。她已经90岁、
91, 10, 11 years later, completely
91岁了，10年、11年过去了，她依然非常
healthy, completely cancer-free. And by
健康，完全没有癌症。
the way, this
顺便说一句，这种
amunotherapy, if we could only get this
免疫疗法，如果我们能让它对
to work as well for everyone. This is
每个人都有效就好了。 这就是
where we are in the history of medicine.
医学发展至今的现状。
We can see an end. We know how we can
我们可以看到结局。 我们知道如何才能
get to an end. We've actually seen
达到目的。 我们确实已经取得了一些
successes. We just can't get it to work
成功。 我们目前还无法让它
for everyone yet. And there are
对所有人都有效。
different ways to actually wake up your
唤醒
immune system. Another way that I'm
免疫系统的方法有很多种。 我现在正在研究的另一种方法，也是
mine in Germany is working on is also
我的一位德国同事正在研究的方法，同样令人叹为观止
absolutely jaw-droppingly amazing.
。
Imagine this. Somebody has cancer and
想象一下。 有人得了癌症，
biopsy no matter what. They're going to
无论如何他们都要接受活检。 他们将
take some tissue out to look at it under
取一些组织样本，在显微镜下观察
the microscope. What kind of cancer is
。 这是哪种癌症
it? A brain? Is it breast? Is it a
？ 大脑？ 是乳房吗？ 这是
colon? Is it pancreas? Where is it
结肠吗？ 是胰腺吗？ 它
coming from? You're gonna get a
来自哪里？ 你将会得到
diagnosis. Right now, up until recently,
诊断结果。 直到最近，
that's all we did with the tissue, the
我们对组织样本的处理方式仅限于
biopsy. You just got a result, and it's
活检。 你刚刚拿到了结果，这有点像
kind of like a death sentence, depending
死刑判决，具体取决于
on what type of cancer, and you're
癌症的类型，然后你
supposed to then go to the guidelines
应该去查阅指南，
and open up the the the the treatment
打开治疗
book to say, well, what's the pathway we
手册，看看我们
should what's the recipe we should
应该采取什么治疗方案
follow for treatment. Too often, those
。 这些
recipes don't work very well for very
方法往往无法
long. Now, what if I told you that where
长期奏效。 现在，如果我告诉你，
we are headed with cancer therapy is a
癌症治疗的未来发展方向是进入一个
new frontier where you take the tumor
全新的领域，你会怎么想？通过活检取出肿瘤样本
with the biopsy, sure, look it under the
，当然，在显微镜下观察
microscope, call it out, uh uh define
，指出
what it is, and then you send it to a
它是什么，然后把它送到
lab where you do complete full-on
实验室进行全面的
genetics. You sequence the entire cancer
基因分析。 对整个癌细胞
genome. All right? Right now, we do
基因组进行测序。 好的？ 目前，我们按
sequence. We take a dozen, two dozen,
顺序进行。 我们拿一打、两打、
three dozen. I'm talking about doing 20,
三打。 我指的是检测 2 万到
30,000 genes, right? Right now, most
3 万个基因，对吧？ 现在大多数
people say it's not worth it. We don't
人都认为不值得。 我们不
know what we do with all that
知道该如何处理这些
information. What if I told you if you
信息。 如果我告诉你，如果你
took a tumor and sequenced all the
取一个肿瘤并对所有基因进行测序
genes, you find every mutation, every
，你会发现我们之前讨论过的每一个突变、每一个
typographical error that we talked about
拼写错误都存在于
earlier that's in that cancer. Those are
那个癌症中，你会作何感想？ 这些就是
the smoking guns of the cancer. Now,
癌症的确凿证据。 那么，
what if I took a piece of a little
如果我取一小块
normal blood, normal cells, and sequence
正常血液、正常细胞，也进行测序呢
that too? All right. Now people are be
？ 好的。 现在，一些
hearing me talk who are oncologists or
肿瘤学家或科学家听到我这么说，
scientists would say I don't know what
可能会说：“我不知道
you're talking about that's double the
你在说什么，这简直是
waste of effort because now you're going
浪费双倍的精力，因为你现在要对同一个
single patient what are you going to do
病人的基因组进行两次测序，你打算如何处理
with all that information ah this is
所有这些信息呢？” 啊，这就是
intelligence machine learning let's now
人工智能和机器学习技术发挥作用的地方。现在，让我们让
have a computer compare normal cells
计算机来回比较正常细胞
with tumor cells back and forth and back
和肿瘤细胞，来回比较，再来回比较，
out all the mutations that are found in
减去正常细胞中发现的所有突变，
leaving only the smoking gun mutations
只留下
in the cancer. Couple hundred are going
癌症中那些决定性的突变。 还会
to be left. Those are the smoking guns.
剩下几百人。 这就是确凿的证据。   正是这些
Those are the doers that led to this
人导致了这场
cancer. Now imagine, and I'm going to
癌症的发生。 现在想象一下，我
give you an analogy here. Do you
给你举个例子。 你还
remember that Tom Cruz movie uh Minority
记得汤姆·克鲁斯主演的那部电影《少数派报告》吗
Report? Yeah. So you remember like he
？ 是的。 所以你记得他当时
was wearing these gloves and you have a
戴着手套，面前是一块
glass pane and you can actually move the
玻璃，你可以
uh things around on the glass with your
用指尖在玻璃上移动东西
fingertips, right? So now imagine you
，对吧？ 现在想象一下，你
can take these human uh the the the
可以把这些人类的
cancer mutations on the bottom of this
癌症突变放在这个
glass screen and you can just randomly
玻璃屏幕的底部，然后你可以
with your fingers pick out 20 random
用手指随机挑选出 20 个随机
mutations and move them up on the
突变，并将它们移动到
screen. All right, now you've just
屏幕上方。 好了，现在你已经
picked out the mutations and now you can
选出了突变，现在可以把
connect the mutations together. I call
这些突变连接起来了。 我称它为
it a pearl necklace. Imagine every
珍珠项链。 想象一下，每一次
mutation is a pearl and you connect them
突变都是一颗珍珠，你用
together with the string that connects a
连接
pearl necklace. Now now you get what I'm
珍珠项链的绳子将它们连接起来。 现在你明白我的意思了吧
saying? Like now we've taken the tumor,
？ 就像现在我们已经找到了肿瘤，
find out the doers, the the the the uh
找出了作案者，找到了
the smoking guns. Now we've strung them
确凿的证据。 现在我们已经把它们串联起来了
together. Okay, this is the most wanted
。 好了，这是
sign that you would actually place out
你真正会张贴
for the criminal. And now imagine you
给罪犯的最明显的通缉令。 现在想象一下，你
hit
遇到了
print technology. And now you have a
印刷技术。 现在你有了一台
protein printer that prints out those
蛋白质打印机，它可以把那些确凿的
smoking guns as a protein, as a protein
证据打印出来，打印成一种蛋白质，一种
full of your own individual cancer of
充满
that particular person. Now you take
特定患者自身癌症的蛋白质。 现在你把
that protein and you inject it under the
这种蛋白质注射到
skin and you're challenging your own
皮下，就是在挑战你自身的
immune system. You're vaccinating
免疫系统。 你这是在
yourself with the with your own cancer
用自己的癌症给自己接种疫苗，
and you're c causing your own immune
你这是在让你的免疫
system to say, "Aha, this is a bad guy.
系统发出信号：“啊哈，这是个坏家伙。
We're going to develop antibodies to go
我们要产生抗体来
find our immune system. We're going to
攻击我们自身的免疫系统。我们要
get ratcheted up to go find that
全力以赴去找到那个
cancer." Well, this is happening right
癌症。”
now in clinical trials. I have a a
目前，临床试验中就正在发生这种情况。 我有一位
colleague named Saskia Biscup that is
名叫萨斯基亚·比斯库普的同事，她正在
actually developing peptide vaccine
研发用于治疗癌症的肽疫苗
treatments against cancer. And if you
疗法。 如果你
want to see some amazing results, um
想看看一些惊人的结果，嗯，
there was a paper we published in Nature
我们大约一年前在《自然通讯》上发表了一篇论文，该论文
showed in more than a 100 people with
显示，在 100 多名患有
glyobblasto that is a game over brain
胶质母细胞瘤的患者中，这种疗法战胜了
cancer. Nobody lives more than a couple
脑癌。 没有人能带着这种病活过两
of years with this. All right. That with
三年。 好的。 通过
this treatment, we've been able to
这种治疗方法，我们已经能够
actually show that some patients with
证明，一些患者
their own immune system woken up can
自身的免疫系统被唤醒后，
actually keep them alive and
实际上可以让他们活下来，并且
cancer-free brain cancer. Like that is
摆脱脑癌的困扰。 这根本
no win-win situation. Impossible to
不是双赢的局面。 不可能变为
possible. And actually somebody who I've
可能。 事实上，我
just recruited as an ambassador to my
刚刚招募了一位人士担任我的
nonprofit organization, the Andrew
非营利组织“安德鲁·
Genesis Foundation, I strongly encourage
吉尼斯基金会”的形象大使，我强烈鼓励
people who want to have a modicum of
那些想要抱有一丝
hope, who wants to see what I'm talking
希望，想要
about in real life on social media.
在社交媒体上亲眼看看我所说的内容的人们关注他。
There's a woman named Rebecca Divine.
有个女人名叫丽贝卡·迪瓦恩。
She's okay with me giving her name. Her
她不介意我告诉她她的名字。 她的
handle is that brainy blonde. It's a
网名是“聪明金发女郎”。 这
it's a triple antandra. She's blonde.
是一个三重安坦德拉。 她是金发女郎。
She's very smart, but she had a
她非常聪明，但
glyobblastoma 7 years ago and she is
7年前她患上了胶质母细胞瘤，现在
thriving alive with his imunotherapy. So
通过他的免疫疗法，她活得好好的。 所以，就
between my mother, Rebecca Divine, I'm
我母亲丽贝卡·迪瓦恩而言，我只想
just telling you like I've had well I've
告诉你，就像我
known well over a dozen people who
认识的十几个人一样，
there's no way they'd be here today if
如果
it wasn't for the scientific advances
不是科学进步加强了
that all shore up the body's health
人体的健康
defense systems, specifically the immune
防御系统，特别是免疫系统，他们今天不可能站在这里
system. But that's the drugs alone
。 但仅仅依靠药物
aren't enough. you really can take
是不够的。 你完全可以
advantage at home of your own diet and
在家中利用自己的饮食和
lifestyle to be able to tip those odds
生活方式来扭转局势，使之对
in your favor. I've heard you say that
你有利。 我听你说过，
successful if you have certain bacteria
如果肠道内有某些特定的细菌，免疫疗法更容易成功
in your gut.
。
Yeah, that is okay. So
嗯，没关系。 因此，
in
在
2017, I helped to convene a cancer
2017 年，我协助在巴黎召开了一次癌症
research conference in Paris.
研究会议。
uh and we called it rethinking cancer
我们称之为“重新思考癌症”，
and we brought the world's best minds
我们把全世界最优秀的头脑都聚集到了
out there and one of the um researchers
一起，其中一位研究人员
uh uh named Dr. Laurance Zogle she's at
名叫劳伦斯·佐格尔博士，她在
the in Paris works in Paris at the
巴黎的
institute Gustaf Rousi she is an
古斯塔夫·鲁西研究所工作，是一位
imuninooncologist so she studies
免疫肿瘤学家，研究
imunotherapy for cancer and at the time
癌症的免疫疗法。当时，我们
we had uh we we asked her to
请她
present uh some uh groundbreaking
展示一些当时
results that were embargoed at the time.
被禁止公开的突破性研究成果。
So our research, our conference was the
所以，我们的研究，我们的会议，是
first time it was ever presented and she
第一次展示这项研究成果。她
said
说，在
in a 100 people who were receiving
接受
imunotherapy for uh different types of
免疫疗法治疗不同类型
cancer that if you looked at the
癌症的 100 名患者中，如果你观察那些有
difference between people who responded
反应、
lived did well versus people who didn't
存活良好和没有
respond didn't do well died. All right?
反应、存活不良甚至死亡的患者之间的差异。 好的？
And that's the frustration with the
这就是我对
types of treatments my mom had. um you
妈妈接受的治疗方式感到失望的原因。 嗯，你
know, some people do well, some people
知道，有些人做得很好，有些人
don't do well. We pull our hair out
做得不好。 我们绞尽脑汁也
trying to figure out like what's going
想不明白到底发生了什么
on? How do we make people do better?
？ 我们如何才能让人们做得更好？
Well, it turns out that when you compare
结果发现，当你比较
everything, gender, age, coorbidities,
所有因素时，性别、年龄、合并症，
uh uh all the other genetic factors. The
呃呃，所有其他遗传因素。 所
research that was presented showed that
展示的研究表明，
imunotherapy, except for one thing.
除了一个例外，免疫疗法疗效好的人和疗效不好的人这两组患者之间没有任何区别。
That one thing was one
那是一个
bacteria. The responders had one
细菌。 这些反应者体内有一种
bacteria called acromancia mucinophila.
名为嗜粘蛋白杆菌的细菌。
So most bacteria have a genus and
所以大多数细菌都有属和
species. First name, last name, first
种。 名字，姓氏，
name is acrimancia, last name is
名字是 acrimancia，姓氏是
mucinophila. Okay, it likes to grow in
mucinophila。 好的，它喜欢在黏液中生长
mucus. Mucinophilia. Where is there a
。 嗜黏蛋白症。 哪里有
lot of mucus? In the colon. Where's the
很多黏液？ 在结肠内。
colon? That's the on this model the blue
结肠在哪里？ 图中蓝色区域就是这个模型上的
area. So acromancy grows right here in
区域。 所以，腺毛就生长在这里，也
the seeum which is the pouch uh in the
就是
colon right at the beginning before you
结肠的囊状结构，在你
take the up elevator to the top of of
乘坐“上行电梯”到达
the colon. That's where it grows. If you
结肠顶部之前。 它就生长在那里。 如果这些
if the people had that
人患有这种
acromancia they would respond to
占卜症，他们就会对
imunotherapy. So what what the
免疫疗法产生反应。 所以，这位
researcher did they she took out the
研究人员做了什么呢？她
the responders from humans and and gave
从人类身上提取了有反应的acromancia，并把它带到她的实验室，然后给那些对
imotherapy. Boom. she'd recom she'd
免疫疗法没有反应的小鼠服用。 繁荣。 她建议
resurrect the immune response to kill
重新激活免疫反应来杀死
the cancer. So this is one of the first
癌细胞。 所以这是最早发现的
bacteria and there there may be many
细菌之一，可能还有很多很多
many that we haven't yet discovered. All
我们尚未发现的细菌。
right. So like my whole career has all
好的。 所以，我的整个职业生涯都与
been about discovery. There may be more
发现有关。 可能还有更多
bacteria but we discovered at least one
细菌，但我们至少发现了一种细菌，
the presence of which seems to be
这种细菌的存在对于
receiving imunotherapy
接受免疫疗法（例如
checkpoint inhibitors. uh if you want to
检查点抑制剂）的患者来说似乎至关重要。 呃，如果你想
uh uh tip the odds in your own favor of
呃呃，增加自己
being a responder. Now, how do you get
成为响应者的几率。 那么，如何才能获得
acromancia? Well, at the time uh there
占卜能力呢？ 当时还
was no acromancia probiotics. Now, you
没有益生菌产品。 现在，你
can actually find acromancia probiotics,
其实可以找到益生菌，
but but at the time this was coming out,
但是当初它刚问世的时候，
you you had to grow your own acromancia,
你必须自己种植益生菌，也就是
DIY acromancia. All right. So, how do
DIY 益生菌。 好的。 那么，
you grow it? Well, it turns out that
该如何种植它呢？ 原来，
there are certain foods you can eat that
有些食物可以让人
grow acromancia. What are those foods?
产生占卜能力。 这些食物是什么？
Pomegranate. Pomegranate juice.
石榴。 石榴汁。
Pomegranate seeds will grow acromancia.
石榴种子会生长出紫菀。
Cranberries,
蔓越莓、
uh, cranberry juice, dried cranberries
蔓越莓汁、蔓越莓干
will grow acromancia. Conquered grape
都会长出蔓生植物。 被征服的
juice or conquered grapes will grow
葡萄汁或葡萄会滋生
acromancia. Chili peppers will actually
魔力。 辣椒实际上会
grow acromancia. Chinese black vinegar.
生长出花蕊。 中国黑醋。
You ever go to dim sum and have soup
你吃过点心，吃过小笼
dumplings? Oh yeah. The black vinegar
包吗？ 哦，是的。 他们用黑醋汁来蘸
condiment to the soup dumplings. Chinese
汤包吃。 中国
black vinegar. That will prompt your
黑醋。 那也会促使你的
body to grow acromancy as well. So, what
身体也产生角质形成能力。 那么，
is your diet of preference then? There's
你偏爱哪种饮食呢？
people speak about when they talk about
人们在谈论
cancer and other chronic diseases. Um,
癌症和其他慢性疾病时，经常会提到各种各样的饮食疗法。 嗯，
as I think I said to you beforehand, I'm
我想我之前跟你说过，我
on an extremely low carb diet, which is
正在进行极低碳水化合物饮食，这就像
like VG is on keto, but I kind of bounce
VG 的生酮饮食一样，但我会在
in and out of ketosis. What What do you
酮症状态和正常状态之间来回波动。 你觉得怎么样？我们先从生
ketogenic diet. Do you have a view on on
酮饮食开始吧。 你对
that kind of diet? Yeah. So, let me just
这种饮食方式有什么看法？ 是的。 那么，让我来谈谈我对
diets. Lots of different diets out
饮食的看法。 市面上有很多不同的饮食方法
there. They're all designed uh with kind
。 它们的设计都带有某种
of a specific perspective and a
特定的视角和
particular goal in mind. Often times
目标。 很多时候
diet, whether you're talking about South
，无论是南
Beach or keto or carnivore or vegan, you
滩饮食法、生酮饮食法、食肉饮食法还是素食饮食法，你
know, um they're all designed to achieve
知道，它们都是为了达到
a certain kind of goal, uh most of them
某种特定目标而设计的，但大多数饮食法都
are very very difficult to maintain for
很难
a long period of time. Now people are
长期坚持。 现在人们有
vegans uh and vegetarians and they're
纯素食主义者和素食者，
that's something that because of the
由于
diversity of the food that you can you
食物种类繁多，他们
can actually maintain that but you know
能够坚持这种饮食方式，但你知道，
if you're only doing pure keto that's
如果你只进行纯粹的生酮饮食，那就
very difficult to do. So
很难做到。 所以
most popular trending diets are
大多数流行的减肥方法都是
short-lived
短暂的
short-term solutions and they'll kind of
短期解决方案，它们会
force your body to do something all
强迫你的身体做一些事情，
right but you can't keep it up. And so a
但你无法长期坚持下去。 因此，如果
diet that you can't keep up isn't to me
你无法坚持某种饮食计划，那么在我看来，这并不是一种
a very practical diet because you're
非常实用的饮食计划，因为你会
just can't do your whole life. I find
进行一些你不可能终生坚持的高强度运动。 我发现，从
that it's much more healthy in the long
长远来看，
run if you can find a sustainable way of
如果你能找到一种适合
eating that works for you personally
自己、
that you can maintain and that you're
可以长期坚持的可持续饮食方式，并且还能
going to enjoy your life as well. Most
享受这种生活方式，那对你的身心健康会更有益。 大多数
people who are on really strict diets,
严格节食的人，
know, like people who only eat meat,
比如只吃肉、
only eat carnivore diet or only eat raw
只吃食肉食物或只吃生
food. Listen, you can't don't con me.
食的人，他们并不享受自己的饮食。 听着，你骗不了我。
You can't you can't be enjoying eating
你不能，你不能一辈子都享受
raw food, you know, your entire life,
生食，
you know, navigating through society and
你知道，然后融入社会，
seeing other people, you know, eat a big
看到其他人吃一大盘
steaming plate of pasta or something,
热气腾腾的意大利面之类的东西，
you know, or going to a Chinese
或者去中
restaurant. So, what I'm saying is that
餐馆。 所以，我的意思是，
trending diets are well-intentioned. and
流行的减肥方法都是出于好意。
they often are designed to do one thing,
它们通常被设计成只做一件事，
but you can't keep it up. So, it doesn't
但你无法一直坚持下去。 所以，
really at the end of the day contribute
归根结底，它对
to the ultimate uh goal. What I prefer
最终目标并没有真正的贡献。 我个人更倾向于从
cuisines in the world. And I would say
世界上一些最健康的饮食文化中汲取经验，而我认为科学将引领我们走向终身健康的下一个前沿领域。 而且我认为
Mediterranean is the hot bed, the
地中海地区是
crucible of a lot of healthy diets, not
许多健康饮食的温床和熔炉，而不仅仅是
just the blue zones. might think but but
蓝色地带。 你可能会想，但是，但是，
there but there are blue zones in the
但是，地中海也有蓝色地带，
Mediterranean also Asia uh there's a
亚洲也有蓝色
blue zone in Asia as well but you know
地带，嗯，亚洲也有蓝色地带，你知道，你
look there's also a blue zone in Latin
看，拉丁美洲也有蓝色地带。
America if you take a look at the common
如果你看看
Mediterranean and Asia is a very healthy
地中海和亚洲的共同点，那就是非常健康的、以植物为主的、
plantforward fresh seasonal uh healthy
新鲜的、应季的、健康的
cooking oils healthy preparation style
食用油、健康的烹饪方式，
absolutely delicious way of eating. I
绝对美味的饮食方式。 我的
mean, come on. Take if I were to take
意思是，拜托。 假设我带你去
you to a Mediterranean restaurant or to
一家地中海餐厅或
a Asian restaurant, I would find it hard
一家亚洲餐厅，我很难
to believe that you wouldn't, you and I
相信你会不喜欢，你和我一起
opening a menu couldn't find something
打开菜单，却找不到
that we would enjoy eating. Right? So,
我们想吃的东西。 正确的？ 所以，
Mediterranean is what how I tell people
我跟别人说
I actually eat. That's my quote diet.
我实际吃的就是地中海饮食。 这就是我的引言秘诀。
Why do the Japanese seem to do so well
为什么在
on when we think about the world's
评选世界上最
healthiest countries? Looking at some
健康的国家时，日本人似乎总是名列前茅？ 我正在查看
data here, some a variety of different
这里的一些数据，以及
graphs that I have in front of me. And
我面前的各种不同的图表。 就
out on top as it relates to health span.
健康寿命而言，日本似乎一直名列前茅。   是的
Yeah. Okay. Well, um there's no one
。 好的。 嗯，
single factor I think that was
我认为没有哪个单一因素
responsible for it, but it is true. Um
导致了这种情况，但这确实是事实。 嗯，
the the Japanese uh demographics uh show
日本的人口统计数据显示，日本人
uh consistently some of the uh oldest
往往是世界上寿命最长的
longest living people, you know, they
人之一，你知道，他们
tend first and foremost. Okay, before we
首先也是最重要的因素。 好的，在我们
talk about what they eat, let me tell
谈论它们吃什么之前，让我先告诉
you what they don't do. They don't
你它们不做什么。 他们不会
overeat. And I'm giving a purposeful
暴饮暴食。 我特意
pause there because
停顿了一下，因为
overeating, caloric loading, okay, uh is
暴饮暴食、摄入过多热量，嗯，会对
very damaging to our metabolism. It
我们的新陈代谢造成很大的损害。 它
actually counters uh our ability for
实际上会削弱我们
long to to live long. It actually speeds
长寿的能力。 它实际上会
up our cellular aging. It's it it sets
加速细胞衰老。 正是它引发了
up inflammation. So, by cutting down on
炎症。 所以，通过减少
your caloric intake every day, that's
每天的卡路里摄入量，这是
one of the things is that the Japanese
日本文化中的一个重要方面
culture, the the the culinary and
，
gastronomic approach to food in Japan
日本的饮食文化和烹饪方式
tends to uh favor modesty. Uh uh uh
倾向于保持节制。 呃呃呃，是
undereating rather than overeating. I've
吃得太少而不是吃得太多了。 我
got a question here. How do how do I
有个问题。 我如何
know if I'm overeating?
知道自己是否吃得过多？
Okay. So, so there's a Confucian saying
好的。 所以，有一句儒家谚语，
uh that's been translated into the
被翻译成
Japanese that they that's a mantra which
日语，它是一种箴言，叫做“
is harachi which means stop eating when
八九”，意思是吃到八分饱就停止进食
you're 80% full. I asked this question
。 我问这个问题是
because I have a friend who was I think
因为我有个朋友好像
it was on this podcast so um don't think
在这个播客节目里提到过，所以，嗯，别以为
I'm revealing anything. He actually sat
我泄露了什么秘密。
next to me um when Peter was talking to
彼得和他说话的时候，他其实就坐在我旁边
him. He's Jack who um runs production
。 他是杰克，负责
for us. He had his DEXA scan done which
我们公司的生产运营。 他做了 DEXA 扫描，这项检查可以
looks at your visceral fat, subcutaneous
检测内脏脂肪、皮下
fat, muscle mass, bone density, those
脂肪、肌肉量、骨密度
kinds of things. Yeah. And he's a slim
等等。 是的。 他身材偏瘦
guy. He's much slimmer than I am.
。 他比我瘦得多。
the doctor basically said, "You're
医生给出的诊断结果基本上是：“你营养
overnourished." And when I look at him,
过剩了。” 我看着他，觉得
he doesn't look like someone that's
他不像个
overnourished. And the the doctor
营养过剩的人。 医生
essentially said to him that you need to
基本上是告诉他，你需要
reduce your calories. Now, I'm looking
减少卡路里的摄入量。 现在，我看着
at this guy thinking, "This is a slim
这个人心想：“他身材很瘦，
than I am, yet the doctor's telling him
比我瘦得多，可医生却说
that he's overeating.
他吃得太多。” 是
Yeah. So, I wrote a whole book on this
啊。所以我写了一整本书，
called Eat to Beat Your Diet, which is
叫《吃出健康，战胜节食》，这本书
not a diet book. It's an anti-diet book
不是节食书，而是反节食书，它
that really um uh uh unccloaks the new
真正揭示了
science of your metabolism. And what I
新陈代谢的最新科学原理。我
try to say in terms of sharing that
想分享的
science is that first of all, body fat,
科学原理是，首先，体脂，
which society is regarded as a bad
社会普遍认为它是不好的
thing. We don't nobody wants fat, right?
东西。我们谁都不想胖，对吧？但
Um is actually a good thing. Body fat's
实际上，体脂是
an organ in the body. Did you know that?
身体的一个器官。你知道吗？
Like it's it's one of our body organs.
它是我们身体的器官之一。
Um our body fat, it is distributed
体脂分布
throughout our body. And what does it do
在我们全身。它
as an organ? Well, it's got some
作为器官有什么作用呢？它有一定的
cushioning effect. So, you know, like if
缓冲作用。比如说，如果
you didn't have any body fat, by the
你没有体脂，
way, you tripped on the stairs and you
顺便说一句，如果你在楼梯上绊倒摔在
hit the ground, you might rupture your
地上，你可能会…… 会损伤你的
organs. All right, that's so that has a
内脏。好吧，脂肪确实起到了一定的
little bit of a cushion effect,
缓冲作用，就像
marshmallowy cushion effect. But our fat
棉花糖一样。但我们的脂肪
also is a fuel tank to store fuel. So,
也是一个储存能量的燃料箱。所以，
when we're eating calories, our calories
当我们摄入卡路里时，卡路里
are our energy. We're eating food, we're
就是我们的能量。我们吃食物，就是
eating calories. That's our energy.
摄入卡路里。这就是我们的能量。
That's that's a fuel our body runs off
这就是我们身体运转的燃料
of. I always tell people if you have a
。我总是跟人们说，如果你有一辆
car and you're filling it up with
车，你
gasoline at the petrol station or the
在
gas station, um you don't even think
加油站加油，你甚至不会想到
about your gas until your fuel gauge
油表指针快要
starts to run low. And the same thing
掉光了。我们的
for our our our bodies is that we don't
身体也是如此，我们只有在感到
think about our fuel until we're hungry.
饥饿时才会想到燃料。
And our our hunger in our brain and our
我们大脑和肠道中的饥饿感，
gut is really as our fuel tank that
实际上就像我们的燃料箱，它发出
signals, you know, we're getting towards
信号，告诉我们快到
that red line. Better go fill fill up.
红线了。最好赶紧加油。
Now, unlike a gas station or petrol
但是，与加油站不同的是
station, there's no clicker on our body.
，我们的身体上没有加油按钮。
We can keep stuffing food into our
我们可以不断地往身体里塞食物
system. We can very easily overload our
。我们很容易就会让
fuel tank. Okay, that is you've got you
燃料箱超负荷运转。好吧，就是这样。 你
got to cut back on your calories. That's
必须减少卡路里摄入。
what you your your friend heard when the
你和你的朋友听到
doctor was saying you got to cut back on
医生说要减少
your calories because you're overloading
卡路里摄入，因为你摄入的
on fuel. So, where does so where does
能量过剩了。那么，
the fat build up? It's there's different
脂肪都堆积在哪里呢？
areas that fat in your body builds up.
脂肪会在你身体的不同部位堆积。
Now, the fat can there's white fat and
脂肪分为白色脂肪和
there's uh uh uh brown fat. White fat
棕色脂肪。白色脂肪
can be under your chin, could be under
可能堆积在你的下巴、腋下、大腿
your arms, could be in your thighs and
和臀部，也可能堆积在你的腰部，也就是所谓的“游泳圈”。
But that's not where the most dangerous
但最危险的
fat builds up. The most dangerous fat,
脂肪并非堆积在这些地方。最危险的脂肪，也
inflammatory fat, is a fat that builds
就是炎症性脂肪，
up in the inside the tube of your body.
堆积在你身体的管状结构内部。你可以把
So if you think of your body like a
你的身体想象成一个
poster tube, okay, inside that tube and
海报筒，在这个管状结构内部，也就是你的腹部，也就是体腔。
cavity, if you were to slice this body
如果你把这个身体切
in half and look at a cross-section, all
成两半，观察它的横截面，你会发现
right, it's a tube. You can fill all you
它就像一个管子。你可以把所有东西都填满它。
any of these uh interstitial areas
任何
between organs, you can pack with fat.
器官之间的组织间隙都可以堆积脂肪。
So think about you're going to FedEx
想象一下，你要用联邦
something to somebody overnight mail uh
快递隔夜寄送东西，比如
a vase or or a glass or bottle of wine
花瓶、玻璃杯、酒瓶之
or whatever. you're going to pack it
类的。你会用
full of peanuts and you're going to put
花生米把它塞满，然后装进
it into a package. Well, look, you can
包裹里。你可以
get a big box and put a lot more peanuts
用一个大盒子装更多的花生米，
on or you can take a skinny box that
也可以用一个刚好能装
would just fit it and you'll put it in.
下东西的小盒子。
So, it doesn't really matter the size of
所以，
your tube. You could be a skinny person
你的“管道”（指内脏）大小其实并不重要。即使是很瘦的人，也
and you could pack it with a lot of
能塞很多
peanuts. In this case, visceral fat. And
花生米进去。这里说的“花生米”指的是内脏脂肪。
skinny person with too much visceral
瘦人体内过多的内脏
fat, too many peanuts packed in there.
脂肪，就像塞了太多花生米一样，就是这种情况。
And that is a result of overconumption
这是摄入过多
of calories. that fat, that energy, the
卡路里的结果。脂肪，也就是能量，就像
fuel tanks building up within a skinny
燃料库一样，堆积在瘦人的
body. Yeah. And that's what we call
身体里。这就是我们所说的“
skinny fat. I am still like mildly in
瘦胖”。我对此仍然感到有点
shock about it because because I saw his
震惊，因为 因为看到了他的检查
results, I I panicked. So the next day I
结果，我慌了。所以第二天我
also went to the same clinic as him. I
也去了和他一样的诊所。我
had my Dexus stan scan done and it came
做了Dexus Stan扫描，结果
back and said that I had quote zero
显示我的
visceral fat. So my results from Dr.
内脏脂肪为零。
Peter said I had zero visceral fat which
彼得医生也说我的内脏脂肪为零，
he said was rare but I had subcutaneous
他说这种情况很少见，但我的皮下
fat which is the fat on the outside more
脂肪（也就是体表脂肪）
than Jack did. So Jack had visceral fat,
比杰克多。杰克有内脏脂肪，也
which is the fat inside us, and he had
就是我们体内的脂肪，他的
he has like almost no subcutaneous fat,
皮下脂肪几乎没有，
and I'm kind of the inverse of that. And
而我的情况正好相反。
I don't what like I was trying to figure
我不明白，
out why is my body when I eat something
为什么我吃东西后，身体会把
putting the fat subcutaneously on the
皮下脂肪堆积到
outside, whereas Jack's body is putting
体表，而杰克的身体却把
the fat on the inside, which is the the
脂肪堆积到体内，也就是那种
dangerous fat. Here is um an interesting
危险的脂肪。这里有个很有意思的
thing. Let's look at the opposite of
地方。我们来看看
building up subcutaneous fat, which is
皮下脂肪堆积的反面，也就是
the external fat, not the not the
体表脂肪，不是
danger, the external fat. Yeah. So,
危险的那种体表脂肪。好的。
okay. So, there's two kinds of body fat.
所以，体脂有两种。
White fat and brown fat. White they're
白色脂肪。 脂肪分为皮下脂肪和棕色脂肪。白色脂肪
all good. They're all beneficial. Um,
都是有益的，对身体都有好处。
white fat can be subcutaneous.
白色脂肪可以是皮下脂肪，也就是位于皮肤
Subcutaneous means under the skin, under
下方，比如下巴下方
your jaw, under the skin of your jaw,
、
under your arms, on your thighs. That's
腋下、大腿等部位。
subcutaneous. White fat can also be
白色脂肪也可以是
visceral fat. That's deep inside the
内脏脂肪，也就是位于
tube of your body. And then brown fat is
体内深处的脂肪。
white fat. Brown fat is wafer thin and
棕色脂肪不像白色脂肪那样柔软有弹性，
it's plastered around our neck. It's
它像薄片一样，分布在颈部、
behind our breast bone, a little bit
胸骨后方
behind between our shoulder blades, a
、肩胛骨之间以及
little bit in our belly. And brown fat
腹部。棕色脂肪的代谢非常
actually is metabolically as a active
活跃，
and it fires up a process called
它会启动一种叫做
thermogenesis to burn down harmful
生热作用的过程，燃烧有害的
visceral extra body fat. So you can use
内脏脂肪。所以，你可以利用
good fat to burn down bad fat, which is
好脂肪来燃烧坏脂肪，这真是
the amazing thing. Again, fat is not
太神奇了。再次强调，脂肪并非
universally bad. It's actually quite
都是坏的，它其实有很多
good. And uh so one of the things that I
好处。我
think is really important to know is
认为非常重要的一点是，
that when you've got too much visceral
当你…… 内脏
fat, you got too much inflammation, but
脂肪过多会导致炎症，但
you can actually use your brown fat to
实际上你可以利用棕色脂肪来
try to um control that to try to burn it
控制炎症，并尝试燃烧
down. Brown fat, by the way, is
掉它。顺便说一下，棕色脂肪会
activated by foods and activated by cold
被食物和低温激活
temperatures. So when you talk about
。所以，当你提到
plunge, brown fat can actually light up.
冷水浴时，棕色脂肪实际上会被激活。
So, you you've just handed me a card.
你刚才递给我一张卡片。
I'll describe this in which there's two
我会描述一下，上面有两张
pictures of a figure. And one of the uh
人体的图片。
pictured on the left is room
左边那张图是
temperature. And it's not cold. It's
室温下的。它并不冷，就是
regular room temperature. And this is
普通的室温。顺便说一下，这是
the same individual, by the way. And you
同一个人。你
can't see anything lighting up because
看不到任何激活的迹象，因为
the brown fat is just adjusted to normal
棕色脂肪只是适应了正常的
room temperature. Now, on the right hand
室温。右边那张图
side is when you actually um lower the
是当你真正降低
temperature in an ice bath or something.
温度，比如在冰浴中。
No, no. This is actually just lowering
不，不，这实际上只是降低了
the room temperature. Really, really
室温。非常非常
cold. Like a like a like a laboratory
冷。就像在实验室
condition lowering the room temperature.
条件下降低室温一样。
And boom, you see all this brown fat
然后，砰的一声，你会看到所有的棕色脂肪都
lighting up. Remember I told you it's
激活了。记住我说过，
it's plastered around the neck, behind
它分布在脖子周围。
the breast bone, uh a little bit in your
胸骨后面，嗯，还有一点点在你的
belly. And this is mother nature's
腹部。这是大自然
adaptation in evolution to help animals
在进化过程中为了帮助动物在
survive cold temperatures. So before we
寒冷环境中生存而进化出的适应机制。所以，在
had thermostats and room heaters, um uh
恒温器和暖气出现之前，嗯，
uh think about a by the way, brown fat
想想看，棕色脂肪是
was discovered in hibernating animals.
在冬眠动物身上发现的。
Um there was a zoologologist uh who was
嗯，有一位动物学家，他
muskrat looking animal from hibernation
从冬眠状态中取出了一只类似麝鼠的动物，
and dissected it and found that there
并对其进行解剖，发现
was this brown lump that was between its
它的肩胛骨之间有一个棕色的肿块，当时
shoulder blades and nobody knew what it
没人
hibernating a mass we don't know what it
知道那是什么。随着越来越多的研究人员、生物学家和动物学家观察冬眠动物，他们发现这种肿块非常普遍。事实上，他们最初将这种棕色肿块称为冬眠瘤，一种我们不知道它作用的肿块
does. Okay. um a
。嗯，一种
hybrer who in the beginning we didn't
冬眠瘤，一开始我们
have microscopes and then we had
没有显微镜，后来我们有了
microscopes and we had really great
显微镜，而且是非常好的
microscopes and all of a sudden in 1930s
显微镜，突然之间，在20世纪30年代……
the researcher uh at UCLA said you know
加州大学洛杉矶分校的一位研究人员说，你知道，
that hibonoma is actually made of fat
冬眠细胞实际上是由脂肪
cells and those fat cells are brown and
细胞构成的，这些脂肪细胞呈棕色，
the reason they're brown is because they
它们之所以是棕色，是因为它们
have a lot of mitochondria in it.
含有大量的线粒体。
Mitochondria being the fuel cells of our
线粒体是我们身体的“燃料细胞”
body, like they're the batteries of our
，就像我们身体的“电池”一样
body. They're packing the they're the
。它们是
energy generators in our cell. And
我们细胞的能量发生器。
mitochondria are very rich in iron. And
线粒体富含铁。
when iron is oxidized, it turns brown
当铁被氧化时，它会变成棕色，就像
like a pile of nails that you've put
你放在门外的一堆钉子一样
outside your door and the outdoors.
。
Silver nails will turn
银色的钉子会变成
brown. Brown fat packed with
棕色。富含
mitochondria, energy generating, packed
线粒体、产生能量、富含
with iron, oxidizes, turns brown. That's
铁的棕色脂肪，氧化后会变成棕色。这就是
why brown fat is brown. And and so what
棕色脂肪呈棕色的原因。因此，在
happens is that in cold temperatures
寒冷的环境中，
like in hibernation in winter, the brown
比如冬季冬眠时，棕色
fat fires up and that's what keep keeps
脂肪会被激活，这使得
these hibernating animals warm
冬眠动物在
throughout the winter so they don't
整个冬天保持温暖，不至于
freeze to death. Now humans, we can
冻死。现在，我们人类
actually use that to our advantage. We
实际上可以利用这一点。我们
can actually activate our brown fat.
可以激活棕色脂肪。
Cold bath will do it. U sleeping in cold
冷水浴可以…… 试试吧。睡在
cooler warms will actually start to
凉爽或温暖的房间里也能
activate it as well. When that, by the
激活它。
way, that when those mitochondria fire
顺便说一下，当线粒体被
up, they are burning energy. You know
激活时，它们会燃烧能量。你知道
where they draw the energy from? From
它们从哪里获取能量吗？
first. So you want brown fat, good fat
首先是你的白色脂肪，也就是内脏脂肪。所以你需要棕色脂肪，也就是好脂肪，
to burn down bad fat, visceral fat,
来燃烧坏脂肪，也就是内脏脂肪和
white fat. You want to sleep in a cool
白色脂肪。你可以睡在凉爽的
room or you want to go into a cold bath.
房间里，或者洗个冷水澡。
And there are lots of foods that will
还有很多食物也
also you can eat foods to activate your
能激活你的
brown fat to burn down harmful fat. Um,
棕色脂肪，从而燃烧有害脂肪。嗯，
and then the last thing is cortisol. the
最后一点是皮质醇。
job that we have. I know this doesn't
我知道
sound like a hard job to be a podcaster,
做播客听起来不是什么辛苦的工作，
but the in Jack's role, he's basically
但杰克的情况是，他基本上
working seven days a week sometimes. You
每周工作七天，有时甚至一周七天。你
know, he's working early hours of the
知道，他经常凌晨就开始工作
morning. He's traveling around the world
。他和我一起环游世界
with me to come to these studios. It is
来到这些工作室。
I observe it. It's a stressful job. So,
我观察到，这是一份压力很大的工作。所以，
I was wondering if these if all of these
我想知道所有这些
factors play a role in in how our body
因素是否都会起作用。 在我们的身体如何
chooses where to store things. And
选择储存物质的位置方面，
really like the role of cortisol in
皮质醇的作用真的让
interesting to me. like the role of
我很感兴趣。还有
stress in determining where our fat is
压力在决定脂肪
stored.
储存位置方面的作用。是的
Yeah. Well, I mean cortisol is a stress
。我的意思是，皮质醇是一种压力
hormone. It actually snaps us into uh
激素。它实际上会让我们
action. It actually is also healing.
行动起来。它实际上也有修复作用。
Cortisol is a got multiple job
皮质醇有很多
descriptions. It's kind of like a Swiss
功能。它就像
Army knife of hormones. Uh and uh in a
激素界的瑞士军刀。而且，在
in small bursts, cortisol incredible
短时间内，皮质醇的作用非常强大，
like and it makes you feel good as well.
它还能让你感觉良好。
I mean it's a kind basically it's a it's
我的意思是，它基本上是
a type of body steroid. So cortisol is a
一种类固醇。所以，皮质醇是一种
very very useful hormone for all kinds
非常有用的激素，
of reasons. But long-term stress uh will
原因有很多。但是，长期压力会
lead to excessive prolonged unabated
导致
cortisol secretion. And when your
皮质醇分泌过量且持续不断。当你的
cortisol levels are up up and and
皮质醇水平持续升高时，它
relentlessly that then actually changes
实际上会改变
your metabolism. It definitely alters
你的新陈代谢。它肯定会改变
your the ability for your fat to
你的脂肪
actually conduct its metabolism. I mean,
进行代谢的能力。我的意思是，
fat releases itself about 15 different
脂肪会释放大约15种不同的
hormones. So, when you mess up the
激素。所以，当你搞砸了…… 如果
structure of your own body fat with
体内脂肪的激素结构或内分泌结构受到
something like excessive cortisol,
过量皮质醇等因素的影响，
you'll actually begin to derail your own
实际上会扰乱自身的
metabolism. So, it's not the short-term
新陈代谢。所以，真正有害的不是短期
cortisol, it's a long-term cortisol
皮质醇，而是长期皮质醇
that's actually the most damaging. Why
。为什么
is visceral fat dangerous? Because
内脏脂肪危险？因为
people refer to it as being linked a lot
人们常说它与许多
of chronic disease and cancers and stuff
慢性疾病和癌症
like that, but what evidence do we have
等有关，但我们有什么证据证明
that it's dangerous? And what why is it
它危险呢？它为什么
dangerous? Yeah, because the tube of
危险？是的，因为
your body with all the organs packed
你身体的管道里塞满了各种器官
into it, just like we're seeing here.
，就像我们在这里看到的。
Look at all these organs packed in. You
看看这些塞得满满的器官。你
got your liver, you got your stomach,
的肝脏、胃、
you got your your colon and your small
结肠和
intestines that's packed into the tube.
小肠都挤在这个管道里。
All right, it is it's it's kind of like
这就像……
uh packing for vacation. You know, some
打包行李去度假一样。你知道，有些
people are really really skilled at
人
packing. They can actually uh fold their
打包行李的技巧非常高超。他们甚至可以把
socks and underwear and their pants and
袜子、内衣裤和裤子叠得整整齐齐，让人惊叹不已。
it's like, oh my, you're a genius.
天才。
You're you're packing genius right now.
你现在正在打包天才。
visceral fat grows between those folded
内脏脂肪会在折叠的
shirts and pants and it and it fills all
衬衫和裤子之间堆积，填满所有
that space in there. When you have too
空间。当内脏脂肪
much of it, not only does it fill up
过多时，它不仅会填满
of your body, but it starts to push on
你身体的“行李箱”，还会开始挤压
organs, which is not healthy because
器官，这很不健康，因为
it's all packing inside the between the
它把所有
spaces, the potential spaces in there.
空间都塞了进去，填满了那些潜在的空隙。
And then when they grow, when it grows
然后，当内脏脂肪过度生长，
beyond its own blood supply, the
超过了自身的血液供应能力时，它就
visceral fat um starts to starve. It
开始缺氧。它
becomes hypoxic, meaning it's not
会变得缺氧，这意味着它
getting enough oxygen. bigger than the
得不到足够的氧气。它比体内不断
amount of blood vessels that are growing
增长的血管数量还要多
in there. And now you've got the center
。现在，
of the fat star of oxygen. Uh the
脂肪的中心氧气不足。
inflammatory cells start moving in. And
炎症细胞开始聚集。
now you've got this fat that's outgrown
现在，这些脂肪已经超过了
its own blood supply that's now becoming
自身的血液供应能力，并且变得
very inflammatory. And because it's
非常容易发炎。由于它
packed all throughout your the tube of
遍布你身体的各个部位，就像
your body into the suitcase of your
你
body, it's leaking out that inflammation
身体的行李箱一样，炎症会
everywhere. So, think about it like if
四处扩散。所以，想象一下，如果……
you have a neatly packed suitcase and
你有一个打包好的行李箱，然后
you're like, I'm, you know, I'm going to
你想，嗯，
put um I'm going to put some uh uh
我要放一些
lotion and cream, canisters of lotion
乳液和面霜，几罐一罐的乳液
and cream. I'm going to pack it
和面霜。我要把它们
everywhere in in between the spaces.
塞满所有空隙。
Okay, look uh Stephen, pack a few, but
好吧，听着，斯蒂芬，放几个，但是，
but let's stop right there. And you're
但是，我们先停一下。然后你又说，
no, I'm going to pack like 20 or 30 of
不，我要放二三十
them. And you keep on stuffing it. Even
罐。你继续往里塞。
though the suitcase it's a hard suitcase
即使行李箱是硬壳的，
and you can you can put a lot in there.
你可以装很多东西。
Now, you're starting to press on the the
现在，你开始挤压
clothing. you're going to scrunch up
衣服，把裤子卷起来。你甚至把
your pants. And here in the body, you're
身体里的
scrunching up your organs. Now, why
器官也挤压起来。现在，
don't we make those one of those tubes
我们来弄一管
uh uh of of cream. Let's break one of
乳液吧。我们掰开一管
them open. Now, it's leaking. All right?
。现在，它漏出来了。好吗？
And that's what's happening when your
这就是你的脂肪堆积时发生的情况。
fat is so inflame so inflamed, it starts
炎症非常严重，以至于开始
to leak, inflammation. Now, imagine that
渗漏。现在，想象一下，
that cream uh starts to leak out into
那层乳霜开始渗漏到
the interstites of your suitcase. Now,
你行李箱的缝隙里。
you've got a suitcase. Looks skinny on
你有一个行李箱，从外面看很窄，看起来
like a suitcase. It's a could be a
就像一个普通的行李箱，可以当
carry-on. But now all the organs, all
随身行李。但是现在，
the clothes you packed so neatly are
你精心打包的所有衣物和内脏都被
squeezed and scrunched off and now the
挤压变形，
lotion is leaking everywhere. That is
乳液也到处渗漏。这就
the analogy of excess body fat in a
好比在一个
small container spreading out
小容器里，过多的脂肪扩散开来，
compressing the organs and leaking out
挤压内脏，然后渗漏出来，
and that's why it's dangerous. Oh gosh.
这就是为什么它很危险。天哪！
And that there's a link there to cancer.
而且它还与癌症有关。
Yeah. So studies have actually shown
是的。研究确实表明了这一点，
that and this was a study uh done uh by
这项研究是由纽约康奈尔大学进行的，研究对象是
Swedish women who were normal body size
身材正常
or skinny. So you've heard of skinny
或偏瘦的瑞典女性。你可能听说过“瘦
fat. This is what they were studying.
胖”这个词，这就是他们研究的内容。
And they looked at these women uh to see
他们对这些女性
they did DEEXA scans as you described um
进行了双能X射线吸收仪（DEEXA）扫描，就像你描述的那样，看看她们的
to see how much body fat they had. And
体脂率是多少。 她们身上有脂肪。
then they followed them over 13 years
然后研究人员对她们进行了长达13年的追踪调查，
and they actually found that women who
结果发现，
did not have extra body fat had you know
没有额外体脂的女性患
normal risk of breast cancer but women
乳腺癌的风险与正常女性相同，但那些
who had skinny fat remember all the
体脂率较高的女性（注意，这里指的是
women in the study and so 3,000 women
研究中所有女性，共3000名，她们的
actually were normal body size not I
体型都很正常，不是
mean they weren't super models but they
说她们是超级模特，而是体型
were they were just normalsized women
正常的女性，
some of them were slimmer than others
有些比其他人更苗条，
but none of them were obese none of them
但没有一个肥胖，也没有一个
were overweight u just normal size Um
超重，就是正常体型）患
developing breast cancer and it's linked
乳腺癌的风险更高。研究人员在基线时通过双能X射线吸收法（DEXA）扫描了解了情况，结果发现，在13年的时间里，体脂率较高的女性患乳腺癌的风险增加了三倍，这与她们血液
to higher met inflammatory markers in
中较高的炎症标志物有关，
their bloodstream which makes total
这完全
sense. The leaking body cream, the
说得通。就像身体乳溢出，
leaking inflammation, you know, in a
炎症也随之释放，就像一个
skinny tube, all right, or normalized
细长的管子，或者说一个正常的
tube, normal suitcase. Look, the
管子，一个正常的行李箱。你看，
suitcase can't expand bigger. It's it's
行李箱的容量是有限的，它不可能无限增大，
got a finite size um but it's leaking
但它却在不断
out and and this is because cancer
溢出。 这是因为癌症
thrives in an inflammatory environment.
在炎症环境中更容易滋生。
If you have inflammation without even a
即使没有像
microscopic cancer like we talked about
我们之前讨论的那样发现微小的癌细胞，
but a small tumor putting inflammation
但只要体内存在炎症，哪怕只是一个小肿瘤，
in the environment of a cancer is like
在癌细胞的环境中引发炎症，就如同
pouring gasoline on the embers of a
在火堆余烬上浇汽油
fire. You ever go camping, you have a
。你有没有露营的经历？篝火快要熄灭的时候，
end. Now if you pour some gasoline it
如果你再浇上一些汽油，砰的一声，嗖的一声，
boom whoosh you're going to have to
你就得重新
create a bonfire all over again. That's
生火。
how dangerous inflammation is. So that's
炎症的危险性就是这么大。所以，
why excess visceral fat, inflammatory
过多的内脏脂肪，也就是炎症性
fat, is so dangerous and linked to
脂肪，是如此危险，并且与
cancer. And by the way, not just breast
癌症密切相关。顺便说一句，不仅仅是
cancer. Turns out that excess visceral
乳腺癌。事实证明，过多的内脏
fat has been linked to 14 other cancers.
脂肪还与另外14种癌症有关，会
Increased risk of 14 other cancers.
增加患这14种癌症的风险。
Everything from colon, ovarian, lung,
从结肠癌、卵巢癌、肺癌、
breast, prostate. Uh it it's the it's a
乳腺癌到前列腺癌，等等。而且，越来越
it's a growing list of cancers that seem
多的癌症似乎都与内脏脂肪过多有关，
if you had high levels of visceral fat.
如果你体内内脏脂肪含量高，患这些癌症的风险就会更高。
And it makes total sense given the
考虑到炎症，这完全说得通
inflammation. Don't you hate it when you
。你不觉得吗？ 当你灵光一闪，想到
have a good idea and then you forget?
一个好点子却又忘记了，这种感觉是不是很熟悉？
For the last two years, I've been
过去两年，我一直在
writing my brand new book. And my book
创作我的新书。我的
writing process is a little bit atypical
写作过程有点特别，因为
in the sense that I have all of these
我经常
great conversations on the diio. And I
在播客上和嘉宾进行精彩的对话。有时，我会在和嘉宾
of a conversation. Or I could be walking
聊天的时候突然冒出一个绝妙的想法。有时，我可能正在
the dog. I could be out and about with
遛狗，可能正在和
my friends. I could be anywhere when I
朋友们外出，总之，我可能在任何地方都可能想到
have an idea for my upcoming book. This
关于新书的灵感。正因
is why notion, who are a show sponsor of
如此，Notion（现在是我的节目赞助商）
platform for me. I've designed my notion
对我来说是一个非常棒的平台。我把Notion设置成
so that I can pull out my phone super
可以快速拿出手机，把
quickly and store the idea in the
想法保存到
section about my new book and I can
关于新书的版块里，然后
any type of media on the go, which means
随时随地收集图片、语音笔记以及各种媒体素材。这意味着
I'm able to capture that point of
我可以
inspiration in a flexible way and I'm no
灵活地捕捉灵感，再也不会
longer losing good ideas. I imagine many
错过任何好点子了。我想，很多
listening to my podcast already use
收听我播客的创意人士和创业者可能已经在使用
Notion. But if you want to try out
Notion了。如果你想尝试一下
Notion and you've never used it
Notion，但之前从未用过
yourself, head over to
，那就去看看吧。 转到
notion.com/doac. That's
notion.com/doac。就是
notion.com/doac. There was a a shocking
notion.com/doac。
study that I read about this a while ago
我之前
in JAMAMA and it examined the impact of
在《美国医学会杂志》(JAMA) 上读到一篇令人震惊的研究，它探讨了
illness anxiety disorder which they call
疾病焦虑症（他们称之为 IAD，
I a formerly known as hypochondriitis
以前称为疑病症）
and the impact that being avoidant of
以及回避
health and illness has on your mortality
健康和疾病对
rates. And they the researcher analyzed
死亡率的影响。研究人员分析了
data from approximately 45,000
大约 45,000 名
individuals over a 24-year period
个体在 24 年期间的数据，
comparing 4,000 patients who had this
比较了 4,000 名患有这种健康
anxiety around their health and were
焦虑症且
avoidant. And the findings showed that
回避健康问题的患者。研究结果表明，
those with IAD that were anxious about
患有 IAD 且对
health and getting checkups and those
健康、体检等感到焦虑的人
of death during the study period, dying
在研究期间的死亡风险高出 84%，
on average 5 years earlier than those
平均比没有这种疾病的人早逝 5 年
without the disorder. And again,
。当然，
causation is hard to establish there
很难确定因果关系，
because it could mean that being an
因为
anxious person means your cortisol's up
焦虑本身就可能导致皮质醇水平升高，或者导致
you make worse dietary choices. But I
饮食选择更差。但
I've always remembered that and thought
我一直记得这一点，并且一直在思考，
um how it's I find it much more much
嗯，我发现这样
better, especially as I age and I'm
更好。 尤其是我年纪大了，
going to be now confronted with more
面临的
risks, especially things in men like
风险也越来越多，特别是男性常见的
prostate cancer. Being on the front foot
前列腺癌之类的疾病。主动出击
um is probably a better approach. Well,
或许是更好的方法。嗯，
uh and if you take some proactive
如果你采取一些积极主动的
approaches using food as medicine where
方式，把食物当作良药，比如每天都要
you got to eat three, you know, you got
吃三顿饭，你知道，
to eat every day. Most most of most
每天都要吃。
people eat three times a day. Most
大多数人一天吃三顿，或者
day. Breakfast, lunch, dinner, and a
一天大约五次，包括早餐、午餐、晚餐和
couple of snacks. If you realize every
一些零食。如果你意识到每次
time you're encountering food is an
吃饭都是一次
opportunity, an opportunity to choose a
机会，一次选择能够
supports raises your shields, supports
增强自身免疫力、提升
your health defense systems. and know
健康防御系统的食物或成分的机会，并且要
that and trust your body, trust your
相信你的身体，相信你的
health defense systems that if you raise
健康防御系统，相信增强自身
your shields, you're less likely to
免疫力就能降低患病的可能性，虽然
won't eliminate them. Okay? There's no
不能完全消除疾病。明白吗？
guarantees in life, but it'll lower the
人生没有绝对的保证，但这确实能降低
risk. Here's an example. Um Stephen, you
风险。举个例子，斯蒂芬，你
know, research studies have shown that
知道，研究表明
tomatoes are good for overall um health.
西红柿对整体健康有益。
You mentioned prostate cancer. So
你提到了前列腺癌。
studies have shown that uh men who eat
研究表明……
tomatoes regularly, cooked tomatoes,
经常吃西红柿（煮熟的西红柿）的男性，患
developing prostate cancer. It's pretty
前列腺癌的风险实际上降低了29%。这相当
good. Uh what's the dose of the tomatoes
不错。那么，
that you need to cook tomatoes you need
煮熟的西红柿需要
to eat? Two to three servings per week.
吃多少呢？两个 每周最多三份。
All right, I can probably I can probably
好吧，我大概能
accomplish that. How much each time do I
做到。 我每次要吃多少才能
got to eat a wheelbarrow of tomatoes
吃掉一车西红柿
each time? No. the the typical serving
？ 不，
that this study supports is just half a
这项研究支持的典型食用量是每份
cup of tomato cooked tomatoes is per
半杯煮熟的番茄
serving. How do they know this stuff?
。 他们怎么会知道这些？
Because obviously how do they isolate
因为很明显，他们如何
that in a test? So these are from
在测试中分离出这种成分呢？ 这些数据来自
largecale population studies. In this
大规模人口研究。 在这种
case it's a it's a uh epidemiological
情况下，这是一项流行病学
study called a uh health professionals
研究，称为卫生专业人员
follow-up study where they looked at
随访研究，他们
they developed hypotheses and they
提出了假设，并
looked at outcomes over the course of 25
观察了 25 年期间的结果，
years and they looked for statistical
并寻找统计
correlations. So they found that um
相关性。 他们发现，
cancer based on people reporting their
根据人们报告的
tomato eating. Then they actually went
食用番茄的情况，番茄可以降低患前列腺癌的风险。 然后他们又
back and look at the report within the
回去查看了
data collected. How much how much do
收集到的数据报告中的内容。
they eat on average every week? So that
他们平均每周吃多少东西？ 这样
then you can actually back calculate the
你就可以反向计算
dose. All right. Now I I told you
剂量了。 好的。 我之前已经跟你说过
earlier about the way that I do research
我研究
foods and medicine research. Let's take
食品和药物的方法了。 让我们
it further. Let's figure out what's in a
更进一步。 我们来探究一下番茄里都有些什么
tomato. Well, tomatoes have lots of it's
。 番茄含有大量的
got it's got sugar. It's got uh some
糖分。 它有点咸
salt. It's got uh carotenoids which are
。 它含有类胡萝卜素，这是一种
bioactives. One of which is lycopine.
生物活性物质。 其中之一是番茄碱。
Well, okay. What does lycopine do? Guess
好吧。 番茄红素有什么作用？ 猜猜
what lycopine does? Lycopine in the lab
番茄碱有什么作用？ 实验室中的番茄红素
will cut off the blood supply to tumors.
会切断肿瘤的血液供应。
Anti-androenesis shores up your health
抗雄激素可以增强你的健康
defense systems. Prevents cancer from
防御系统。 阻止癌细胞
getting a blood supply. And in fact in
获得血液供应。 事实上，在
correlative studies um uh they've
相关性研究中，他们
actually taken the prostate cancer
确实对未能避免患上前列腺癌的男性进行了前列腺癌
biopsies of men who did not avoid
活检
prostate uh cancer. So they were tomato
。 所以，他们虽然
eaters who went on to develop prostate
爱吃番茄，但最终还是患上了前列腺
cancer anyway. There's no nothing takes
癌。 没有“什么都不带
you versus zero. And they looked at them
你”和“零”之间的区别。 他们观察了这些
and what they found is that those men
男性，发现
who ate more tomatoes had fewer blood
吃西红柿较多的男性
vessels in their prostate cancer and the
前列腺癌中的血管较少，而且
prostate cancers were also less
前列腺癌的侵袭性也较低
aggressive. So people who ate four times
。 因此，每天进食四
and five times and six times had fewer
、五、六次的人，
growing into their prostate cancer. So
其前列腺癌中生长的血管数量较少，且侵袭性也较低。 所以，举个
that's an example where you know if I
例子，如果我
told you
告诉你，可以
um consider having some cooked tomatoes
考虑
a few times a week and you don't need a
每周吃几次煮熟的西红柿，而且不需要
lot. Even half a cup is enough. Oh, why
很多。 即使半杯也足够了。 哦，为什么是
cooked tomatoes? Well, because it turns
熟番茄？ 原来，
out lycopine is uh a natural chemical
番茄碱是一种天然化学物质，就像
apple, it's absorbed in your body, but
苹果一样，从藤上摘下一个番茄吃掉时，它会被人体吸收，但吸收量
not avidly, not as much as
并不大，不会达到最大吸收量
possible. Um, what is that? That is
。 嗯，那是什么？ 那是
coffee. Okay. And we've been talking a
咖啡。 好的。 我们刚才稍微谈到了
little bit about brown fat. Yeah. Is
棕色脂肪。 是的。
there a link between fat and coffee?
脂肪和咖啡之间有联系吗？
Because I heard someone the other day
因为前几天我听到有人
saying that if you want to lose weight,
说，如果你想减肥，就
drink coffee. And I wasn't sure if that
喝咖啡。 我不确定那样是否
was well. So coffee is a beverage made
合适。 咖啡是
with coffee beans. Coffee beans are
用咖啡豆制成的饮料。 咖啡豆是
plant-based foods. Coffee beans contain
植物性食品。 咖啡豆含有
many polyphenols including chlorogenic
多种多酚，包括绿原
acid. Chlorogenic acid is
酸。 绿原酸具有
anti-inflammatory. Chlorogenic acid also
抗炎作用。 绿原酸还能
turns on your brown fat. So it activates
激活棕色脂肪。 因此，它会
it triggers your brown fat and it causes
激活你的棕色脂肪，使
your brown fat the mitochondria to fire
棕色脂肪中的线粒体开始
up undergo thermogenesis to burn down
运转，进行产热作用，从而燃烧
harmful white fat or visceral fat. So
有害的白色脂肪或内脏脂肪。 所以，
cup of coffee a day or actually the dose
每天一杯咖啡，或者实际上
coffee a day will definitely cause your
每天三到四杯咖啡，肯定会使你的
brown fat, good fat to burn down your
棕色脂肪（好脂肪）燃烧掉你的
bad fat, your harmful fat, your visceral
坏脂肪（有害脂肪）和内脏
fat. What about fasting?
脂肪。 禁食呢？
People people often talk about fasting
人们经常把禁食当作一种
as a as an intervention as a form of
干预手段，一种
medicine for the body. And I wondered if
治疗身体疾病的方法。 我想知道
you had a take on that. Yeah, f listen
你对此有何看法。 是的，听着，
fasting is beneficial. Fasting is good
禁食是有益的。 斋戒是好事，
and fasting is very old. It's not just a
而且斋戒历史悠久。 这并非
recent trend. uh if you go back
近期才出现的趋势。 呃，如果你追溯到
thousands of years, I mean if you look
几千年前，我的意思是，如果你看看
religions of the world, fasting was part
世界上一些最古老的宗教，斋戒是
of their ritual that would happen, you
他们全年都会进行的仪式的一部分
know, throughout the year. Now, people
。 现在，人们会问：
go, "Well, what about intermittent
“那么，间歇性
fasting? How long should I fast?" I try
禁食呢？我应该禁食多久？” 我尽量
to tell people there is no
告诉人们，
magic formula for success for fasting
禁食没有成功的灵丹妙药，
because we're all different and our
因为我们每个人都不同，我们的
bodies are different. Our lifestyles are
身体也不同。 我们的生活方式
different. There's no universal fasting
不同。 没有一种通用的禁食
protocol that's going to be
方案可以
one-sizefits-all. However, I will tell
适用于所有人。 不过，我会告诉
you an easy way to fast because fasting
你一种简单的禁食方法，因为禁食
is very natural to us is just paying
对我们来说非常自然，那就是
attention to what you do every day and
注意你每天所做的事情，并
be mindful. So, when you're sleeping,
保持觉知。 所以，睡觉的时候，
you're not eating. When you're not
你就不吃东西了。 不
eating, you're fasting. So, I try to be
进食的时候，你就是在禁食。 所以，我尽量让她
reassuring. So, guess what? You're
安心。 你猜怎么着？
fasting every day anyway. When you fall
反正你每天都在禁食。 当你
asleep, you're fasting. All right? And
入睡时，你就处于禁食状态。 好的？
the longer you're not eating and
你不吃不
sleeping, the more time your metabolism,
睡的时间越长，你的新陈代谢（
the Ferrari of your of your metabolism
你身体新陈代谢的“法拉利”）就越有机会
of your body can switch gears to burn
加速运转，燃烧
down any extra fat that's accumulated.
掉体内积累的多余脂肪。
Now, if you've been eating whatever you
如果你
want over time, you probably built up a
长期以来一直随心所欲地吃东西，那么你很可能已经积累了
lot of extra fat. Now, from your scans,
很多额外的脂肪。 现在，从你的扫描结果来看，
apparently not. You don't have too much.
显然并非如此。 你拥有的并不多。
All right? But you if you you're fasting
好的？ 但如果你
regularly, you're burning down all that
经常禁食，就能消耗掉所有
extra stuff. Okay? And so then how do
多余的热量。 好的？ 那么，如何在
you optimize that without having to
不
calendarize your fast and figure out,
安排禁食时间、不费心
you know, how to uh schedule your meals?
安排用餐时间的情况下优化禁食呢？
I try to make things
我尽量让事情
um as scientific but as practical as
既科学又实用
possible. And so I tell people you want
。 所以我告诉人们，如果你想
to really get involved in intermittent
真正参与间歇性
fasting. Easiest way is take advantage
禁食，那就去做吧。 最简单的方法就是充分利用
of what you're doing already. And that
你现在正在做的事情。
is if you're sleeping, try to sleep
如果你要睡觉，那就尽量
eight hours a day. So, how do you sleep
每天睡八个小时。 那么，你如何保证
eight hours a day? I don't know. I said
每天睡足八小时呢？ 我不知道。 我说，
if you go to bed at 11 o'clock, get up
如果你晚上11点睡觉，早上
at 7 o'clock, you get to eight hours of
7点起床，就能睡够8个小时
sleep. All right, we know that that's
。 好的，我们知道这种
the med the sweet spot for your brain,
药物对你的大脑、
for your metabolism, for you know, for
你的新陈代谢以及
burning out harmful body fat. How do you
燃烧有害的体内脂肪来说都是最佳选择。 如何才能从中
get more out of that? How do you turn
获得更多收益？ 如何将这
that eight hours of fasting into more?
八小时的禁食时间延长？
Well, what I say is that the night
我的意思是，
before when you're eating dinner, let's
前一天晚上你吃晚饭的时候，
say you eat from 7 to 8 o'clock in the
比如说你晚上7点到8点吃晚饭
evening, what I say is that when you
，我的意思是，当你
finish dinner and you put your dishes
吃完晚饭，把碗碟
away in the sink or in the dishwasher,
放到水槽里或者洗碗机里，就完事了
that's it. No more eating. Stop eating.
。 不再进食。 停止进食。
Nothing until the next day. Um, if
直到第二天才会有消息。 嗯，如果
you're going to have dessert or
你打算吃甜点
whatever, squeeze it in there. Don't
什么的，就挤出时间来吃吧。 不要
take a snack with you and sit by the
带着零食坐在
television or, you know, absent minily
电视机旁，或者你知道的，在外面
gobble food and don't before you be you
狼吞虎咽地吃东西，也不要
go to bed eat a big chunk of whatever.
上床睡觉前吃一大块东西。
Okay, now you got 3 hours before you go
好了，现在你还有3个小时，晚上
to bed at 11. Again, this is all a
11点就要睡觉了。再次声明，这只是一个
theoretical model. 3 hours of not
理论模型。  3个小时没吃
eating. Your blood sugar goes down. Your
东西。 你的血糖下降了。
your insulin goes down because your
因为你不再进食，所以你的胰岛素水平会下降
blood you're not eating anymore. All
。
right. Now, your metabolism shifts gears
好的。 现在，你的新陈代谢提前了
three hours earlier. Okay. Now you've
三个小时开始。 好的。 现在你
got those eight hours plus three hours,
有了那八个小时加上三个小时，一共
you got 11 hours. Now when you get up in
11个小时。 现在，当你早上起床的时候
the morning, okay, let's say you get up
，比如说你
at seven in the morning, don't do what
早上七点起床，不要按照
our moms told us to do, right? So when
我们妈妈告诉我们的去做，对吧？ 所以，
if you were like me growing up, my mom
如果你像我一样从小就习惯了，我妈妈会在
when I got up like hurry up and get to
我起床后催我快点吃
breakfast and eat something so you have
早饭，吃点东西，这样我才有
enough energy to actually go to school
足够的精力去上学
and learn something. All right? So
学习。 好的？ 所以，
that's I I developed this instinct of
我养成了
actually just getting up and eating as
起床后尽快吃点东西
quickly as I can, getting some breakfast
，吃点早餐的习惯
in. What if I told you that what I do
。如果我告诉你，我
now when I get up in the morning, I
现在早上起床后，
deliberately don't do what my mother
故意不做我妈妈
told me to do. I get up, I take my time
让我做的事，你会相信吗？ 我起床，慢慢地
getting ready, uh, I get dressed. Um, I
准备，嗯，穿好衣服。 嗯，我
don't eat anything right away. In fact,
不会马上吃东西。 事实上，
if I'm dressed and I'm ready for the
如果我穿戴整齐，准备
day, I might go check it out. I might go
出门，我可能会去看看。 我可能会
outside and take a look at the outside.
出去看看外面的景色。
I might go for a quick walk or check my
我可能会出去散散步，或者查看一下
emails or I might read a chapter of a
电子邮件，或者读一章书，
book or read a few pages of a book. I
或者读几页书。 我
wait at least an hour before I eat
至少要等一个小时才会吃
anything. Now, let's do the math. Uh,
东西。 现在，让我们来算算。 呃，
Stephen, 8:00, stop eating. 11 o'clock,
斯蒂芬，8点，别吃了。 晚上11点，
go to bed. 3 hours. 11 to 7, 8 hours. 3
睡觉。  3小时。 上午 11 点至晚上 7 点，共 8 小时。  3
plus 8 is equal to 11 hours. I got 11
加8等于11小时。 我
hours of fasting. Now, I get up and I
禁食了11个小时。 现在，我起床后，一个
don't eat for another hour. Boom. 12
小时内不吃东西。 繁荣。
hours of fasting. Just like that. Okay.
禁食12小时。 就这样。 好的。
Now, if you really want to do that
如果你真的想进行
16hour fasting, 168, just skip breakfast
16 小时的禁食（168 小时），那就跳过早餐，直接
and get to lunch. And as long as you
吃午饭。 只要你
don't overeat at lunch, which does
在午餐时不要吃得过多（这确实
require a little discipline after you go
需要在禁食期结束后保持一定的自律，
for your fasting window that you don't
不要
overeat and you're eating the right
吃得过多，并且要吃正确的
foods, that's how you actually get to do
食物），你就能以
intermittent fasting in the most natural
最自然的方式进行间歇性禁食
way possible. So, there's one part of
。 所以，
the body that we haven't talked about,
我们还没有谈到身体的一个部分，
which is and my little mannequin here
那就是我这个小人体模型，它
inside its head, the brain. And I'm
头里面的大脑。 我想知道
wondering how some of the themes we've
我们讨论过的一些主题与
common brain diseases which people talk
人们谈论最多的脑部疾病之一——
about, which is Alzheimer's and
阿尔茨海默病和
dementia. talked about I can't say that
痴呆症——之间有什么联系。 我谈到了血管生成，我不能说那个很
long word but um
长的词，但是，血管
angiogenesis is there a link between
生成，
angioenesis what we in the brain health
血管生成和大脑健康、
dementia Alzheimer's yeah absolutely so
痴呆症、阿尔茨海默病之间有联系吗？是的，绝对有。
I mentioned to you that the human body
我之前提到过，人体
has got 60,000 miles worth of blood
有6万英里的血管
vessels that are coursing through the
遍布
entire body bringing the uh oxygen and
全身，
nutrients through the highways and
通过健康的“高速公路”和“小路”输送氧气和营养物质，对吧？
those blood vessels are in your brain
其中400英里的血管在你的大脑中，
400 miles of blood vessels are actually
400英里的血管实际上在
coursing through our brain. And our
我们的大脑中流动。 而且我们的
brain is super metabolically active. You
大脑新陈代谢非常活跃。 你
know, we're we're the engine of the
知道，我们
brain is functioning all the time.
大脑的引擎一直在运转。
Regardless of your IQ, regardless of
无论你的智商如何，无论
what type of task you do, our brain is
你从事什么类型的工作，我们的大脑代谢都
very very metabolically active, highly
非常活跃，高度
dependent upon a healthy circulation.
依赖于健康的血液循环。
Now, what we do know as people get older
现在我们知道，随着年龄增长，人们的
is that problems can occur with uh brain
大脑功能可能会出现问题
function. And the reason I'm framing it
。 我之所以
this way is that it's quick to jump to a
这样表述，是因为
term that people use like dementia or
人们很容易把痴呆症或
Alzheimer's disease thinking it's one
阿尔茨海默病之类的术语当作一种疾病
thing, but in fact, dementia is just a
，但实际上，痴呆症只是一个
descriptive term for your cognition not
描述性术语，指的是随着年龄增长，认知能力逐渐衰退的现象
age. Alzheimer's, even though it is one
。 阿尔茨海默病虽然是一种
type of diagnosis, is probably several
诊断类型，但可能也包含几种
different kinds of disease as well. And
不同的疾病类型。
we do know that there are different
我们知道
types of dementia. Alzheimer's is a
痴呆症有不同的类型。 阿尔茨海默病是
subset of dement of dementia,
痴呆症的一种亚型，即
Alzheimer's dementia. There's there's a
阿尔茨海默痴呆。 还有一种
more common type of dementia called
更常见的痴呆症类型叫做
vascular dementia and that's where those
血管性痴呆症，在这种情况下，
400 miles of blood vessels in your body
你体内长达 400 英里的血管会
actually narrow, get hard, get clogged
变窄、变硬、
up, and don't have good blood flow. So,
堵塞，导致血液流动不畅。 所以
you can imagine if you were to actually
你可以想象一下，如果你真的
interrupt the sprinkler system, the
中断了喷淋系统、
tubing, the blood vessels, the
管道、血管以及
brain within those blood vessels. Okay?
通过这些血管向大脑输送氧气的支流，会发生什么。 好的？
over time your brain is not going to
随着时间的推移，你的大脑
function very well. So vascular dementia
功能会逐渐下降。 因此，血管性痴呆
is is by far the more common type of
是迄今为止最常见的
dementia. So what can we do to maintain
痴呆类型。 那么，对于任何渴望长寿的人来说，我们该如何一生保持
healthy andogenic blood vessels
健康的血管呢？
longevity. All right, you should be
好吧，你应该
thinking about how to avert that path
考虑如何避免
where your blood circula your blood
血液循环受阻，导致
vessels your circulation to your brain
大脑血液循环
gets impaired. the more uh vascular,
受损。 你越注重促进
blood vessel healthy, androgenesis
血管健康、改善血管状况、支持雄激素生成的
supporting diet and lifestyle and
饮食和生活方式，以及
medications that you take, the better
服用的药物，结果就会越好
it's actually going to be. Now, here's
。 现在，
what what's interesting. What are some
有趣的地方来了。
of those things? Turns out that dark
这些东西具体有哪些？ 原来，黑
chocolate, plant-based foods, the cacao,
巧克力、植物性食物、可可，
actually um produces helps your body
实际上可以帮助你的身体
produce something called nitric oxide.
产生一种叫做一氧化氮的物质。   一
Nitric oxide actually widens your blood
氧化氮实际上可以扩张
vessels so you get better blood flow. So
血管，从而改善血液流动。 所以，
dark chocolate is one of those foods
黑巧克力是少数几种
that actually can see seems to be able
似乎能够
to promote better vascular health
促进血管健康（
including in the brain. Now there are
包括大脑血管健康）的食物之一。 现在还有
other foods that can produce nitric
其他一些食物也能产生一氧化氮
oxide as well. Beets beetroot actually
。 甜菜根实际上
can produce nitric oxide. Spinach can do
可以产生一氧化氮。 菠菜
produce nitric oxide as well. Those are
也能产生一氧化氮。 这些都是
vascular healthy. Now here's the other
血管健康的。 还有另一
thing. When you produce nitric oxide,
件事。 当你摄入
like with these foods, you know what
这些食物时，体内会产生一氧化氮，你知道一
nitric oxide does? It recruits stem
氧化氮的作用是什么吗？ 它从你的骨髓中募集干
cells, healthy stem cells, not cancer
细胞，健康的干细胞，不是癌
stem cells, but healthy stem cells from
干细胞，而是健康的干细胞
your bone marrow. Stem cells are stem
。 干细胞是
cells are primitive cells that can turn
原始细胞，可以根据
into anything you need them to be. Turn
需要分化成任何形态。
into a brain, heart, lung, liver, skin,
变成大脑、心脏、肺、肝脏、皮肤、
hair. Um, our stem cells actually
毛发。 嗯，我们的干细胞实际上是
regenerate us from the inside out. Now,
从内而外地使我们再生。 现在，
you know that one of the things that
大家都知道，
happens as we get older is our brain
随着年龄增长，我们的大脑会
atrophies and can start to degenerate.
萎缩，甚至开始退化。
It shrinks. Literally, a scan of an
它会缩小。 从字面上看，扫描
older person, the brain, the brain
老年人的大脑，脑
matter, the mass of the brain shrinks
组织，脑容量
inside the skull. It's like a like a
在颅骨内萎缩。 就像一件
cotton shirt that shrank and you see
缩水的棉质衬衫，你可以
this actually in a scan. And so in order
在扫描图中看到这一点。 因此，
to be able to try to keep the shrinking
为了防止大脑萎缩
from happening, you want to make sure
，你需要确保
there's good blood flow going, which
良好的血液循环，这
actually helps to keep the brain growing
实际上有助于大脑以
in a healthy and maintained in a healthy
健康的方式生长和维持
sort of way. So um stem cells that are
。 所以，由一
recruited by nitric oxide actually can
氧化氮募集的干细胞实际上可以
help to also regenerate the blood
帮助再生
vessels and keep the blood vessels
血管，并保持血管
helping healthy feeding the brain.
健康，从而为大脑提供营养。
That's the connection between
这就是
Alzheimer's and and I mean dementia and
阿尔茨海默病和痴呆症之间的联系。
now for Alzheimer's
关于阿尔茨海默病，
Vagnucci some years ago and we published
几年前我和同事安东尼·瓦格努奇博士合作，我们在《
Lancet uh you know very prestigious uh
柳叶刀》（Lancet）——一份非常权威的
British medical publication and we were
英国医学期刊——上发表了一篇社论。我们探讨了雄
connecting the dots between androgenesis
激素生成
and Alzheimer's disease and here's how
与阿尔茨海默病之间的联系。
it works most people assume that if
大多数人认为，如果
you've got Alzheimer's disease or
患有阿尔茨海默病，
someone has Alzheimer's disease they
他们的
don't have very good blood flow they're
血液循环就会很差，雄
not going to have a lot of androgenesis
激素生成也会减少，他们的血液
their circulation of course and in fact
循环肯定有问题。事实上，
if If you look at um the blood flow
如果你观察阿尔茨海默病患者的脑部血流
studies, scans, brain scans looking for
研究、扫描和脑部扫描，就会发现……
blood flow in Alzheimer's brain. Indeed,
事实上，患有
actually Alzheimer's disease. But it
阿尔茨海默病的人确实会出现血液循环不良的情况。 但
turns out the brains of people with
事实证明，阿尔茨海默病患者的大脑
Alzheimer's disease have more blood
血管更多
vessels, more blood vessels that aren't
，但这些血管功能却不
working well. So their andro abnormal
正常。 所以他们的雄激素异常
androgenic blood vessels are not working
血管功能
well. So you don't get good blood flow.
不佳。 所以血液循环不好。
So the scans don't show them just don't
所以扫描结果显示它们没有
creating blood flow. Guess what those
产生血液流动。 猜猜这些
blood vessels are doing? Those abnormal
血管在做什么？ 研究发现，这些异常
blood vessels, they have been discovered
血管会
to secrete a neurotoxin that kills your
分泌一种神经毒素，这种毒素会杀死
brain cells. So abnormal androenesis in
脑细胞。 因此，阿尔茨海默病中的异常雄激素生成会
Alzheimer's disease grows blood vessels
生长出
that don't create blood flow, but they
无法产生血液流动的血管，但这些血管会
secrete a toxin that kills brain cells
分泌一种毒素来杀死脑细胞，还会
and they also secrete the precursor to
分泌
build up the plaque. So, uh, we we
形成斑块的前体物质。 所以，我们把
published this as a as a hypothesis and
这个假设和
an editorial in the Lancet and now
社论发表在了《柳叶刀》上，现在有
there's a whole field looking at
一个完整的领域正在研究
androgenesis and and Alzheimer's
雄激素生成和阿尔茨海默
disease. It's crazy how this all stems
病之间的关系。 这一切竟然都源于“
back to this idea that food is medicine.
食物即药物”这个理念，真是不可思议。   是的
Yeah. I mean, listen, before we had
。 我的意思是，听着，
pharmaceuticals in the 1930s, it's all
在 20 世纪 30 年代我们拥有真正的药物之前，在药品出现之前，这就是
we had. That's all humans had our diet
我们所拥有的一切。
and lifestyle for medicines, you know.
你知道，人类的饮食和生活方式就是为了获取药物。
And so I think that that's really I
所以我认为，这才是真正
think what's happened is that in during
发生的事情：在
with pharmaceuticals,
制药业带来的工业革命期间，
we put aside a tool in the toolbox that
我们把工具箱里一直拥有的一种工具束之高阁
we've always had. In fact, that's the
。 事实上，那是
only thing we had before. And we focused
我们之前唯一拥有的东西。 我们
myopically just on what pharmaceuticals
目光短浅地只关注药物
can do. Now, I'm telling you, as
能做什么。 现在，我作为
somebody who has developed
一个开发
biioharmaceuticals and who is still very
生物药物并且仍然
much involved in that, new medicines can
深度参与其中的人告诉你，新药可以
be life-saving. Old medicines can be
挽救生命。 老药有时能
life-saving. And so, you never want to
救命。 所以，你永远不应该把
throw out the baby with a bath water.
孩子和洗澡水一起倒掉。
What we have forgotten about is that
我们已经忘记了
tool in the toolbox. It's been with
工具箱里的那件工具。 它一直伴随着
humanity forever, which is what we do
人类，这就是我们
with our food. And and what I'm saying
对待食物的方式。 而我想说的
is that what we can do now with the work
是，我现在
that I'm doing in food is medicine. We
在食品领域所做的工作，可以转化为药物。 我们
can take the modern science that deep
可以利用现代科学的深度
probe that ex extraordinary level of
探测技术，这种技术
sophistication that we use for drug
在药物
development and we can use it apply it
研发中展现出非凡的精密程度，我们可以将其应用于
to understand why our foods help us
理解为什么我们的食物对我们有益，
which foods help us and what types of
哪些食物对我们有益，以及
outcomes we're actually looking for. And
我们实际想要获得什么样的结果。 所以说，
so food is medicine. Bringing it back
食物就是药物。 把它重新
into the fold is just replacing a tool
纳入考虑范围，就好比
in the toolbox. But now we are actually
在工具箱里更换工具一样。 但现在我们实际上是在用
knowledge provided by science of what we
科学提供的知识来强化它，这些知识告诉我们
should choose and when and why.
应该选择什么、何时选择以及为什么选择。
Supplementation. Are you a fan of
补充。 你喜欢服用
supplementation? Because I take a couple
营养补充剂吗？ 因为我
of supplements every morning. Things
每天早上都会服用几种保健品。 比如
like creatine and omega-3 and vitamin D.
肌酸、omega-3 和维生素 D 之类的东西。
Do you take supplements? Yep. Yes, I do.
你服用这些补充剂吗？ 是的。 是的，我愿意。   首先，我
And I I'll I'll first say um my my first
首先要说的是，
off approach is that uh we should get
我们应该
to be healthy from our food. Use your
从食物中获取保持健康所需的大部分微量营养素。 善用
food uh to our advantage because uh
食物，因为
single foods will have hundreds of
单一食物中含有数百种
different uh polyphenols and fiber and
不同的多酚、纤维以及
all kinds of other beneficial things. So
各种其他有益物质。 所以
and and vitamins and minerals. So, our
还有维生素和矿物质。 因此，通过
food is a much more efficient way to get
食物获取所有微量营养素是一种更有效的方式
all of our micronutrients. However,
。 然而，
supplements can be helpful in the
补充剂可以从
literal translation of the world,
字面翻译的角度来理解，即
supplement, which means topping off. So,
补充，意思是补充。 所以，
if you can't get everything that you
如果你不能
need from your food, then feel free to
从食物中获取所有必需的营养，那么可以随意
top it off. And that's what I actually
添加其他食物。 而这正是我实际
do as well. But vitamin D, vitamin D, I
所做的。 但是维生素D，维生素D，我也会服用
do it as well. Omega-3 fatty acids,
。  Omega-3脂肪酸，是
another good uh top off uh to actually
另一种很好的
use for a supplement. And by the way,
补充剂。 顺便说一句，
there are some probiotics that um I feel
我觉得摄入一些益生菌
that it's prudent to actually get have
是明智之举
in my body. So I'm not giving a general
。 所以我并不给出普遍性的
recommendation. I'm just telling you
建议。 我只是告诉你
what I do, right? That's what we're
我平时做什么，对吧？ 这就是我们
talking about. Everything's personal.
讨论的内容。 一切都与个人有关。
It's personal to them. But I, you know,
这对他们来说是私事。 但是，你知道，
we talked earlier about the acromancia,
我们之前讨论过占卜术，
right? So I do eat the foods that
对吧？ 所以我会吃一些
support acromancia, the pomegranate,
有助于增强占卜能力的食物，比如石榴、
etc., and the chili peppers. But I'm
辣椒等等。 但我
going to take the supplement because
会服用这种补充剂，因为
I've seen the data that shows how
我看到的数据表明
important it can be. Oh, an acromancia
它有多么重要。 哦，占卜术可以
improves your metabolism, lowers the
改善你的新陈代谢，降低
risk of metabolic syndrome. There might
患代谢综合征的风险。
even be some clues that acromancia um
甚至可能有一些迹象表明，占卜术
might also lower the risk of dementia
或许也能降低日后患痴呆症的风险
development later on as well. So, hey,
。 所以，嘿，
this is a pretty safe natural bacteria.
这是一种相当安全的天然细菌。
I'll take that probiotic. And another
我要服用益生菌。
probiotic I take is called Lactobacillus
我服用的另一种益生菌叫做红曲乳杆菌
rutery. Lutery. What does this do?
。 乐器。 这是做什么用的？
Lowers inflammation, builds immunity. It
降低炎症，增强免疫力。
actually text This is the bacteria that
实际上，这是通过细菌向
text messages the brain. We talked about
大脑发送短信。 我们讨论了
the brain and it causes our brain to
大脑，它会导致我们的大脑
release social hormones like oxytocin.
释放催产素等社交激素。
That's a social hormone that makes us
那是一种让人
feel good. So, you know, uh why wouldn't
感觉良好的社交激素。 所以，你知道，呃，
I actually take that? And oh, one last
我为什么不接受呢？ 哦，还有最后一
thing. Lactobacus ruti has been I the
件事。 我
kind I take is chewable. Why wouldn't
服用的乳酸杆菌是咀嚼片。 为什么不
you just take a capsule? Well, it turns
直接服用胶囊呢？ 原来，这种
out that the same bacteria, lactobacus
名为乳酸杆菌的细菌
ruterides, good for the gut, but if you
对肠道有益，但如果你
chew it up, this is the bacteria that
把它嚼碎，它就能
kills the bacteria that causes cavities
杀死导致蛀牙
and gum disease.
和牙龈疾病的细菌。
decade, you know. And so, again, this is
你知道吗，我已经十多年没蛀牙了。 所以，再说一遍，这是
one of these types of practical things
这类实际问题之一，
that um just knowing the science and
嗯，只要了解科学，
knowing what I do and where where I
知道我做什么，以及在哪些方面我
don't need enough. It's hard to get
做得不够好，就足够了。
enough vitamin D. um uh uh hard enough
维生素D很难摄取充足。嗯……
to get omega-3s, I will actually top off
其实摄取omega-3脂肪酸也很难，我会​​额外补充的
on those. I'm wondering, you know,
。 我在想，你知道，
you've I've got these two great books in
我面前有两本很棒的书，一本
is a New York Times bestseller, and Eat
是《纽约时报》畅销书《吃出健康》，另一本是《吃出健康》，这本书
to Beat Your Diet, which is really about
实际上是关于
burning fat, healing your metabolism,
燃烧脂肪、修复新陈代谢
and living longer. I know that you must
和延长寿命的。 我知道肯定
have some f people use the term
有些人
superfoods all the time, but there must
经常使用“超级食物”这个词，但肯定
be some foods where you look at them and
有一些食物，你看着它们就会
just think they are little miracles in
觉得它们本身就是小小的奇迹
their own right. So, I wanted to a
。 所以，我想给
little challenge for you is if you had
你们出一个小挑战：如果根据你们所做的研究和所看到的科学，让你们
to pick five of your favorite foods
选出五种你们最喜欢的食物，那么
those top fives be? I would bring
你们的前五名会是什么？ 我会带
coffee. Okay. Um because of all the
咖啡。 好的。 嗯，因为
polyphenols in coffee, I'd bring tea. Um
咖啡里含有大量的多酚，所以我建议带茶。 嗯，
I tend to drink coffee in the morning
我通常早上喝咖啡，
and I have tea at night. Um and I can
晚上喝茶。 嗯，而且我对
I'm not caffeine sensitive, so I can
咖啡因不敏感，所以我
have the tea at night. If if if you
晚上可以喝茶。 如果可以的话
allow me, I'll actually lump those into
，我真想把它们都加到
my beverages. Okay. Under one category.
我的饮料里。 好的。 归为一类。
Um I'll bring tree nuts. Tree nuts. Tree
嗯，我会带些坚果。 树坚果。 树
nuts. Walnuts, almonds, macadamia,
坚果。 核桃、杏仁、澳洲坚果、
pistachios. Um I love nuts. U tree nuts.
开心果。 嗯，我喜欢坚果。  U 树坚果。
And you know, not the pack prepackaged
你知道，不是那种预先包装好的
kind, but I like to, you know, kind of
，而是我喜欢
like toast them up myself and see flavor
自己烤着吃，
them myself. Um, I would bring that
自己调味。 嗯，我会带这个，
because of the dietary fiber, the
因为它富含膳食纤维，对
healthy pro, it's a good source of
健康有益，是优质蛋白质的来源
protein, some healthy fats in it as
，还含有一些健康脂肪
well, and can kill some cancer stem
，而且顺便还能杀死一些癌干
cells while we're at it. Okay, so tree
细胞。 好吧，看来树
nuts are actually good. I would bring
坚果其实是有益的。 我会带
tomatoes because I love tomatoes. Okay,
西红柿，因为我喜欢西红柿。 好的，
it's a great source for hydration, good
它是很好的补水来源，也是
source of lycopine, which we talked
番茄碱的良好来源（我们之前讨论过番茄碱，
about, good for metabolism. I would take
对新陈代谢有益）。 我会采摘
berries. Berries, blueberries,
浆果。 浆果、蓝莓、
strawberries, raspberries are are among
草莓、覆盆子都是
my favorites. Raspberries. You might be
我最喜欢的水果。 覆盆子。 你可能会感到
surprised at this, but raspberries are
惊讶，但覆盆子是
poundfor-pound or weight for weight one
单位重量
of the most fiber richch foods out
纤维含量最高的食物之一
there. They're light, they're hollow,
。 它们很轻，是空心的，里面
packed with fiber. Um, and they've got
充满了纤维。 嗯，它们还含有
polyphenols and that are useful for
多酚，多酚也有助于
lowering inflammation as well. Berries
降低炎症。 浆果
um are actually really good. And then,
其实真的很好吃。 然后，
you know, I because I follow what I call
你知道，因为我遵循我所谓的
the Mediterranean uh style of eating, I
地中海式饮食，我
love to have those vegetables that are
喜欢吃那些
actually used in both the Mediterranean
在地中海
and Asia, Mediterranean style cooking,
和亚洲烹饪中都会用到的蔬菜，比如
the bok choy, the kale, chory, escarol,
小白菜、羽衣甘蓝、白菜、菊苣，
you know, all of those types of um of of
你知道，所有这些
leafy greens. So, those would be the
绿叶蔬菜。 所以，这
five I would actually take with me. And
五样东西就是我实际会带去的。 那么，
what is the most important thing that we
我们应该谈论却没有谈论的最重要的事情是什么呢
talked about? You know, I think that uh
？ 你知道，我认为
things that that I want people to walk
我最希望人们
away with is that there's more than 200
记住的一点是，
foods that I've studied and I've written
我已经研究过200多种食物，并在
about in my books eat to be disease and
我的书《吃出疾病》和《
eat to beat your diet that you know I've
吃出健康》中写到了它们。我已经
done all the heavy lifting to help you
做了所有繁重的工作，帮助你
figure out what foods are healthy that
弄清楚哪些食物是健康的，你
you could consider adding to your diet.
可以考虑添加到你的饮食中。
But if you notice, I didn't actually
但如果你仔细观察，就会发现我并没有
give you a formula or a set menu on what
给你提供保持健康的公式或固定方案
to do for health. Because the most
。 因为
important thing I I I want people to
我最希望人们
walk away with is that my humanistic
记住的是，我的人文主义
approach to this is um you should love
方法是：你应该热爱
your food to love your health. And if
你的食物，才能热爱你的健康。 如果
you could actually do both at the same
你真的可以同时做到这两点
time, you have to find out what are the
，你就必须找出哪些
foods that resonate with you. What do
食物能引起你的共鸣。
you prefer? What do you enjoy? So, if
你更喜欢哪种？ 你喜欢做什么？ 所以，如果
you could look at 200 healthy foods,
你能看看我书里列出的 200 种健康食品，
and just take a highlighter or a pencil
然后用荧光笔或铅笔把
and circle them. Circle the ones you
它们圈出来。 圈出你
already love. Start and stick with
已经喜欢的人。 从这些方面入手并坚持下去
those, you're already way ahead of the
，你已经遥遥领先了
game. And that builds confidence that
。 这会让你更有信心，相信
you're actually doing the right things.
自己正在做正确的事情。
And that's what I love about this book
我特别喜欢这本书《
in particular, Eat to Beat Disease, is
吃出健康：战胜疾病》的一点是，
recipes um inside the book. And um I
书中还附有很多很棒的食谱。 我
think that's super helpful because
觉得这非常有帮助，因为这
there's a lot of information here, but
里面有很多信息，但
this makes it actionable. It's a it's a
这样能让信息变得可操作。 这是一本
really iconic book. It's such it's sold
非常经典的书。 它之所以如此畅销，是
so incredibly well because also it's so
因为它对
aren't scientists and that are trying to
非科学家来说也极其容易理解，这些人只是
find some things that they can add to
想找些东西添加到
their plate. Um and I think that's
他们的生活中。 嗯，我认为这
essential to the approach that you take
对你采取的方法也至关重要
as well. You're not someone that's
。 你并不是那种会
telling us we can't eat nice things and
告诉我们不能吃好吃的、不能
enjoy our life. You're talking about the
享受生活的人。 您谈到了
things that we should be adding to our
我们应该在饮食中添加哪些食物，
plate to make our lives more um healthy
以使我们的生活更健康，
and increase our longevity, which I'm
延长寿命，我对此感到
very excited about actually because
非常兴奋，因为
you're writing a book about longevity, I
我听说您正在写一本关于长寿的书
hear. And um I'm very much awaiting that
。 我非常期待那
book, which when when do you think
本书，你觉得它什么时候能
that'll be due and ready? I don't uh I'm
出版呢？ 呃，我正在
working on a manuscript, so I'm not
创作一部作品，所以现在还不能
ready to give a release date yet, but
给出发布日期，但
you'll be the first to know. Okay, good.
你会是第一个知道的人。 好的。
We have a a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结尾的传统，
podcast where the last guest leaves a
最后一位嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个
question for the next not knowing who
问题，但他并不知道这个问题是留给谁的
they're leaving it for. And the question
。
that's been left for you is, how would
留给你的问题是，
you be able to tell that your time here
你如何判断你
on Earth has been
在地球上的这段时光是否
successful, that you've achieved what
成功，你是否实现了
you set out to
你想要
achieve?
实现的目标？
Wow. I think I would
哇。 我认为
have two sides, two answers for that
对此我会有两个方面，两个答案，
that represent different sides of the
分别代表了
coin. For me, I think if I'm able to
硬币的两面。 对我来说，如果我能让
have made my immediate community, my
我的社区、我的
family better, that would uh be
家人变得更好，那将是
meaningful, a meaningful life uh having
很有意义的，我的人生才算有意义
been lived. And if you look at the whole
。 如果你回顾我整个
uh rest of my career and existence and
职业生涯和人生经历，以及
how I spend my
我如何度过我的
time, I want the work that I've done to
时间，我希望我所做的工作能够以某种
resonate with others in a way that can
方式引起他人的共鸣，从而
improve their lives. I'm, you know, what
改善他们的生活。 我，你知道，就是
I do. I kind of say I'm taking one for
我做的事。 我算是说我这是在为
the team. The team being the rest of the
团队牺牲自己。 团队指的是
world. And if I can contribute even a
世界其他地区。 如果我能够贡献哪怕一
small piece that makes other people's
小部分力量，让其他人的
lives better, then I feel like, you
生活变得更好，那么我觉得，你
know, I've done it. I've done my job.
知道，我就做到了。 我的职责已经完成了。
Well, that's what you're most certainly
没错，
doing, my friend, because you when I was
我的朋友，你的确在做这件事，因为当我
looking through what you've accomplished
回顾你
in your life, um whether it's the all of
一生所取得的成就时，无论是
you've helped to develop, um more than I
你帮助开发的、获得 FDA 批准的 70 多种疾病的治疗方法（包括癌症、糖尿病、慢性伤口和失明），多到我根本
could possibly count, or whether it's
数不过来，还是
the work that you're doing through your
你通过你的
foundation, which I think people should
基金会所做的工作（我认为人们应该去
uh check out, which is a nonprofit
了解一下），这是一个非营利
organization, which helps develop
组织，致力于开发
based on
基于
angioenesis. You've most certainly done
血管生成疗法的慢性疾病治疗方法。 你肯定已经
that and you continue to do that. But
这样做了，而且你还在继续这样做。 但或许
even maybe more importantly of all
更重要的是，
because there's so many billions of
因为世界上有数十亿
people out there that are starved of the
人缺乏
information that you have and that you
你所拥有和
find in your research laboratory is
在你的研究实验室里发现的信息，所以
you've come out into the world into the
你走到了现实世界，来到了
public forum and you're helping to
公共论坛，帮助
articulate and demystify these
阐明和揭开这些
incredibly confusing things that people
极其令人困惑的事情的神秘面纱，而像
like me who didn't go and get a PhD or
我这样没有获得博士学位或
didn't go to Harvard don't understand.
没有上过哈佛的人却无法理解这些事情。
And you're masterful at it. You really
而且你在这方面非常出色。 你真是个
are masterful. your ability to break
大师。 你崩溃的能力
down. You know, I sit here week in week
。 你知道，我每周都坐在这里和
out speaking to very very smart people
非常非常聪明的人交谈，
and not all of them have the very
但并非所有人都具备将
something very complicated into
非常复杂的事物转化为易于
something understandable. And that is a
理解的事物这种非常重要的技能。 而这正是
skill you have. It's a real real gift
你所具备的技能。 这真是一份难得的礼物，
and especially your use of like
尤其是你运用
metaphors and analogies which really
比喻和类比的方式，真正将
cement these ideas in our brain in a way
这些想法牢牢地印在我们的脑海里，让
that we can all understand. That for me
我们都能理解。 对我来说，那
is a really really important gift. So
是一份非常非常重要的礼物。
long may you continue to continue your
希望您能继续从事
work of public communication as well
公共传播工作，
because for people like me it it can
因为对于像我这样的人来说，它能
cause a penny drop moment that then
带来顿悟时刻，从而
leads us to change our lives for the
促使我们改变生活，变得
better. So thank you. Thank well well
更好。 所以，谢谢你。 非常
thank you for inviting me. But you know
感谢你的邀请。 但你知道，
I would say that you know we also live
我想说的是，我们也生活
in a time again this is about going into
在一个再次迈向
the future. I'm always about moving into
未来的时代。 我总是着眼于
the future. Well, we have the platforms.
未来。 我们有平台。
We have, you know, I I went on to I
你知道，我后来
developed a YouTube channel because I
开通了一个 YouTube 频道，因为我
realized it was a place for me to take
意识到这是一个让我能够汲取
to drink from the fire hydrant, distill
灵感、提炼精华
it, and figure out how I can deliver it
并思考如何
in swift fashion, which would have been
快速传达信息的地方，这在
impossible 10 years ago. So, for
10 年前是不可能的。
example, you know, we talked about how,
例如，我们谈到，
you know, uh, when my uncles had had
我的叔叔们得了
cancer and passed away and I felt
癌症去世，我感到很
helpless, then my mother had it some
无助，几年后我的母亲也得了癌症，
years later and we had progress. we had
但我们取得了进展。 我们有
the ability to be able to do something
能力做一些
different. Similarly for me, I look at
与众不同的事情。 对我来说也是如此，我把
my books, I look at my social channels,
我的书、我的社交渠道、
my YouTube um uh platform as ways of
我的 YouTube 平台都看作是解决
that I felt like needed to be solved,
我觉得需要解决的问题的一种途径，
but I wasn't really sure how to do it
但直到现在我才真正确定该怎么做
until now. Dr. William Lee, I highly
。 威廉·李博士，我强烈
recommend everybody goes and checks out
建议大家去看看
your YouTube channel because it is
您的 YouTube 频道，因为它
fantastic and that's a great place to
非常棒，是
get more of this information, but also
获取更多此类信息的绝佳途径。此外，
I'm going to link the YouTube channel
我也会在下面附上您的 YouTube 频道
and all of these books below for anybody
和所有这些书籍的链接，供任何
that wants to continue their journey of
想要继续
learning. Thank you. Thank you. I really
学习的人参考。 谢谢。 谢谢。 我非常
appreciate you being so generous with
感谢您慷慨地分享
your time and
您的时间和
wisdom. This has always blown my mind a
智慧。 这件事一直让我有点难以置信
little bit. 53% of you that listen to
。 经常收听该节目的听众中，有 53% 的人
the show regularly haven't yet subscribe
尚未订阅
to the show. So, could I ask you for a
该节目。 那么，我能请你
favor? If you like the show and you like
帮个忙吗？ 如果你喜欢我们的节目，喜欢
what we do here and you want to support
我们在这里所做的一切，并且想要支持
us, the free simple way that you can do
我们，最简单的免费方法
just that is by hitting the subscribe
就是点击订阅
button. And my commitment to you is if
按钮。 我向你们承诺，如果
you do that, then I'll do everything in
你们这样做，
my power, me and my team, to make sure
我和我的团队将竭尽全力，确保
that this show is better for you every
这个节目每周都能为你们带来更好的体验
single week. We'll listen to your
。 我们会认真听取您的
feedback. We'll find the guest that you
反馈意见。 我们会找到您
want me to speak to and we'll continue
想让我采访的嘉宾，然后继续
to do what we do. Thank you so much.
做我们该做的事情。 太感谢了。
[Music]
[音乐]